<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/545.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/544.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/543.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/542.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/541.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/540.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/539.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/538.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/537.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/545.html">
<title>#545 - Happy, Healthy, and Prosperous New Year!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/545.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi everyone!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let me start by welcoming you to the new year! Let me also use the opportunity thanking &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://manwar.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Mohammad S. Anwar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for his dedication in both editing every other edition of the Perl Weekly Newsletter and his very own &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Let me also thank &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://davecross.co.uk/&#x22;&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for his immense help making our grammar a bit more bearable and the various Open Source projects he creates. (e.g. the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpandashboard.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Dashboard&#x3C;/a&#x3E;). If you also like their work please thank them in an email, a blog post, or by supporting them via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar/&#x22;&#x3E;Patreon for Mohammad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; or via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/davorg/&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub for Dave&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. They won&#x27;t become wealthy from this, but receiving a paycheck every month from tens of supporters give a huge boost to the ago and makes one create even more for the public.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As for me, you might recall I&#x27;ve been learning Spanish for more than 3 years and started to learn Ladino (aka. Judeo-Spanish) a few weeks ago. Learning a foreign language is a totally different experience than learning a programming language. If for nothing else, because you don&#x27;t get immediate feedback to your mistakes from a compiler. Well. Except if you use an application that helps you. My open source mindset quickly kicked in. I found an Open Source platform called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://librelingo.app/&#x22;&#x3E;LibreLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that will help you learn languages. It is still in very early version, but started to use that platform to be able to practice Ladino and also started to contribute to the project. I&#x27;ll share more about it when enough progress was made to show something in public. Till then you are invited to check it out.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the year ahead!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-01-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/544.html">
<title>#544 - Merry Christmas</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/544.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We wish all the readers of the newsletter, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Merry Christmas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope and wish you are all enjoying quality time with your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Belated happy birthday to my favourite language, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, on completing 34 years. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mark Gardner&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; used his weekly blogging schedule to celebrate the occassion in his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://phoenixtrap.com/2021/12/21/34-at-34-for-v5-34-modern-perl-features-for-perls-birthday&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you remember which year you first picked up the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; language?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, I was introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the year 1998. So technically, I am 23 Perl years old. How about you? I am wondering if anyone other than the creator picked the language in the first year that it existed. If you know their name then please do share it with us. I am sure there must be a handful of people that I am not aware of.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about birthday celebrations, I would like to wish belated Happy Birthday to the mother of our chief editor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As per the record, my birthday was last Monday i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To date, I have never celebrated my birthday, this year also went without celebration.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I noticed that I am getting close to my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the newsletter. This is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;94th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be a big achievement for me, personally, to reach that number. I am looking forward to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;556th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter as that will be my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Stay safe and enjoy the holiday break.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-12-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/543.html">
<title>#543 - Happy Birthday!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/543.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Thomas Klausner sent me a bunch of links and suggestion, let me share them first:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abigail has a series of Advent posts starting from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://abigail.github.io/HTML/AdventOfCode/2021/day-01.html&#x22;&#x3E;day 01&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I did not find a page listing all the entries but you can get to them by changing the URL. Smylers is doing crazy stuff with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/smylers2/status/1334150980552757250&#x22;&#x3E;vim (and perl)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. One can find a lot of inspiring code (Perl, Raku and of course other languages) in the various &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/adventofcode&#x22;&#x3E;&#x27;Solution Megathreads&#x27;&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on Reddit.  Finally domm himself has a few &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://domm.plix.at/tags/AdventOfCode.html&#x22;&#x3E;Advent related posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today we are celebrating the 80th birthday of my mother. Due to the pandemic we cannot celebrate in the same space, but we have collected some videos from the family members and her friends and we are going to have a Zoom session. Much better than not being able to celebrate at all. Happy birthday mom!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In a few days a large part of the world is going to celebrate the birthday of another Jew.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Merry Christmas!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-12-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/542.html">
<title>#542 - Perl Advent Calendar</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/542.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How you all doing? Are you making the most of the festive season?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/540.html&#x22;&#x3E;540th edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter, I mentioned &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I noticed some activity in the GitHub repository for the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and was hoping to see another exciting edition full of Perl projects. A friend of mine on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; mentioned that this year the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://perladvent.org/2021/index.html&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is looking a bit sparse. At the time of writing this editorial, I have only seen &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://perladvent.org/2021/2021-12-01.html&#x22;&#x3E;one post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; i.e. Day 1 of Year 2021. Being one of many contributors in the past, I am sad to see the current state of the project. I have absolutely no idea what happened this year. I know I have too many things already on my plate but I would like to help to get the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; back to its original glory.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would like to mention &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2021&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which has mix of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; like in the past. We have been running this since the beginning i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2019&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You will find some of the fun tasks from the past year being discussed by members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have made a slight change to the look and feel this year. I hope you like it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://24pullrequests.com&#x22;&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/a&#x3E; event?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have not seen it being discussed either on any of the social platforms e.g. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LinkedIn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I haven&#x27;t had chance to take part this year. I couldn&#x27;t take part last year either; what a shame. I still have 10 days and I have booked a few days off work. So there is a possibility I might take part and even complete the challenge. Please wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, leader of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; project, announced that he had a great meeting with the Perl Steering Council and they are extremely receptive to Corinna going into the core. I can&#x27;t wait for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to be part of core Perl. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Damian&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared the details on one of issues discussed in the same meeting in a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/damian_conway/2021/12/a-not-so-simple-matter-of-privacy.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. You definitely don&#x27;t want to miss it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-12-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/541.html">
<title>#541 - Hanukkah is over - Advent started</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/541.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hanukkah, the 8-day celebration of the Jews returning to Jerusalem and the rededication of the Temple on the Temple-mount is now over. We ate way too much and the UN passed only one resolution trying to eliminate the historical ties of Jews to this hill. Very good timing.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Now onto Advent!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How often do you remember to thank Mark Gardner for his extraordinary posts about Perl? I think I have only thanked him once. Maybe I should set up a cron job to send him a thank-you note every month. Or maybe I should &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://phoenixtrap.com/tip/&#x22;&#x3E;leave him a tip&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Finally he set up a system where we can give him a one-time tip or, IMHO better yet, a recurring tip. It is so nice to see month-by-month that people still value your work even if they are too busy or too embarrassed to say it themselves.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-12-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/540.html">
<title>#540 - 24 Pull Requests</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/540.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Did you participate in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If not then you have one more chance to participate in the global event &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://24pullrequests.com&#x22;&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Participation is simple, you just have to submit one pull request each day between 1st Dec 2021 and 24th Dec 2021. It is one of my favourite events. I have participated in the event each year, without a break, since 2015. I was introduced to it by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/neilb/2015/11/24-pull-requests.html&#x22;&#x3E;Neil Bowers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Last year I was going through rough patch so, unfortunately, I had to skip it. My best performance was in the year 2018 when I contributed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;125 pull requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the first 24 days of December. If I am not mistaken then the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; event is little more relaxed as compare to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You don&#x27;t have to submit a pull request every day. Instead, you can submit in bulk one day and then take a break. However, make sure you have submitted at least 24 pull requests by the end of play on 24th December.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Hacking !!!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you follow the much-discussed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; project &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The project is run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his dedicated team of experts. I came across a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/why-is-perl-not-putting-moose-in-the-core.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; talking about &#x22;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Why is Perl not putting Moose in the core?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x22; There is a bold statement in the post in response to the question &#x22;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x2019;s an Object in Perl?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x22; and it is &#x22;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl knows nothing about OOP. It doesn&#x2019;t know what objects are.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x22;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; doesn&#x27;t say things without a reason. Please read the full blog post for more informations. I am one of the biggest followers of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and never miss his posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you remember, I mentioned &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the editorial of the weekly newsletter edition &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perlweekly.com/archive/536.html&#x22;&#x3E;#536&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Ever since then, I have noticed lots of activities in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; communities about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am confident this year we are going to have another fun filled &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (also known as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;) is going to complete &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1000 days&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;18th December 2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To celebrate the day, the team is running a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE T-shirt&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; campaign. If you are interested in knowing about it then please check out the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/1000-days&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Stay safe and avoid the new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COVID-19&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; variant &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Omicron&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/539.html">
<title>#539 - Farewell to David H. Adler</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/539.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Really sad news: that David H. Adler, known by many as DHA has passed away. I&#x27;ve included a number of links where people who can express themselves way better than I do say goodbye to him.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In other news the ephemeral miniconf took place this week. You can read about it below.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Lastly, The Weekly Challenge celebrates its first 1000 days. Congratulations to Mohammad Anwar, my co-editor of the Perl Weekly for keeping up with this project!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/538.html">
<title>#538 - Are you Perl blogger?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/538.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Going back to the editorial of last week&#x27;s &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/537.html&#x22;&#x3E;edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Perl Weekly, it is still there in my head raising many questions. It is a universal fact that Perl is no longer the favourite language among the youths in college these days. I remember when I was first introduced to Perl in 1999, it was the most popular language. Being a Perl fan, I feel it is my responsibility to bring Perl back to the discussion table. One way to do that is to talk about Perl-based projects and share them with the users of other languages. I have noticed that not as many people blog about Perl as they used to in the past. Talking about blogs, I would like to thank &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; team for spreading the power of Perl. For the record, in the last 138 weeks, the team have created and shared over 2000 blog posts. I used to blog regularly in the past but nowadays I hardly find time. Having said that, I still wrte a monthly report blog post where I talk about Perl and my other projects. I find making a live video is less time consuming than writing a blog post. I made some and then I stopped that as well, sorry. You can take a look my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/mohammadsajidanwar&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube Channel&#x3C;/a&#x3E; if you fancy. I came across series of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/beginner-perl-maven-video-course&#x22;&#x3E;videos&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Gabor Szabo teaching Perl. It is great source for someone new to Perl and explore with live action.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember, Dave Cross, wrote a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/davorg/don-t-be-a-perl-programmer-4h2d&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about something that not many people would speak about. I personally agree with him fully and believe knowing more than one programming languages helps you as a programmer. I can tell from my own experience, I picked up Raku last year while participating the weekly challenge. Whatever little I know about Raku to date, I can tell it has helped me a lot. I use that knowledge to write better Perl programs. Recently, I started writing Python as well - just the basics for now. So the question is, does knowing Raku or Python make me any less of a Perl programmer? I am still a Perl programmer and all of my thought processes still follow Perl&#x27;s rules. Perl is my first love and will remain so for the rest of my life. Even today, after more than 22 years, I find features that I never knew existed before, especially in the field of regex. I would like to give credit to Abigail for sharing the magic of regex in Perl as part of his weekly contributions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;While talking about blogs, how can I miss those who are doing great service on a regular basis? I would like to thank &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.polettix.it/ETOOBUSY&#x22;&#x3E;Flavio Poletti&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for blogging every day for months now. Also there is another name, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://phoenixtrap.com&#x22;&#x3E;Mark Gardner&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, who writes a weekly blog post. Similarly we have weekly stats by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://niceperl.blogspot.com&#x22;&#x3E;Miguel Prz&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/537.html">
<title>#537 - How do you spend your free time?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/537.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl Weekly newsletter is more than 10 years old and over those years we have witnessed a huge decline in the number and diversity of posts. There are still a few people who write about Perl regularly, The Weekly Challenge of Mohammad generates many posts, but in general we see fewer and fewer posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wonder, do those people who used to write about Perl write about other technologies or have they just stopped? How come that so few people write about Perl? Are there no new things in Perl? Are there no new problems that one solves in Perl?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know that writing about stuff is not the same thing as writing the stuff, but as many other people who write or teach will attest, the best way to improve your knowledge is to explain it. to explain it to live audience (at a Meetup) or to write about it in a blog post.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So how do you spend your free time? Do you write more code? Do you try to explain what you wrote, how you wrote and why? Or do you spend your time on some other activities? I, for examples started to read a lot more than I did in the recent years. And sure, I&#x27;ll even share my recommendations with you. (See below.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In any case enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html">
<title>#536 - Auf Wiedersehen Hacktoberfest</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The headline of this week&#x27;s newsletter is dedicated to all my German friends. However, the message is global &#x22;Good bye Hacktoberfest&#x22;. I don&#x27;t know the language, so I asked Google to help me. I am sure you all celebrated the month-long festival with loads of contributions to many opensource codebases. I can completely understand the feeling at the end of the month. Those who have participated and completed the challenge successfully i.e. submitted at least 4 eligible Pull Requests, should just relax and wait for their FREE gift. Please take November as a break as December will bring in another fun challenge i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://24pullrequests.com&#x22;&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anything else to look forward to?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, there is another fun bit is the &#x22;Advent Calendar&#x22;. There will be plenty of Advent Calendars available during the month. It is really hard to follow all of them. I came across something called, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.lenjaffe.com/AdventPlanet&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Planet&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, which collects almost all popular Advent Calendars for us. Please do check it out, if you want a early peek. I really miss those days when I used to have time for such things. I have contributed to the Perl/Raku advent calendars in the past. If you have spare time and interest then please do get in touch with the person behind the project now and book your slot. There is one &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2020&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; dedicated to the members of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; only. I make sure the tradition continues every year. I hope everything goes as per the plan and we have another fun Advent Calendar by the dedicated members this year.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Start your week with yet another informative newsletter. You take care of yourself and your family. Keep a safe distance and stay safe,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>