<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/552.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/551.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/550.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/549.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/548.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/547.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/546.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html">
<title>#555 - Holidays</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am in Hungary now where where there is a 4-days Holiday around the 15th March - the Hungarian version of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolutions_of_1848&#x22;&#x3E;Springtime of Nations revolutions&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Then I&#x27;ll have another 2 days off as my client  in Israel celebrates &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purim&#x22;&#x3E;Purim&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I use these free days to work on an open source platform for word-games. It is not ready yet to show the world, but it is already in a condition where people can contribute to it. The first game needs lots of words in various languages. I already started to do versions in English, Hungarian, Hebrew, and Ladino and I already had a contributor with French and German, but I am looking for more people who might be interested in contributing in other languages. Let me know and I can show you the game. I hope that two weeks from now, when I am editing the next issue of the  Perl Weekly I&#x27;ll be able to already link to the game. (the game is only front-end code now so there is no Perl in it. Sorry.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html">
<title>#554 - Exceptions in Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I borrowed the title from Curtis&#x27; recently shared &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/Ovid/5205534f7dcc52e4d931aaff301b39aa&#x22;&#x3E;gist&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure every one of us have dealt with exceptions in Perl. Being a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; fan, I found plenty of choices readily available. I am a big fan of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/Try-Tiny&#x22;&#x3E;Try::Tiny&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and it has always been my first choice to deal with exceptions in Perl. I suggest you must check out the gist for more insights and suggestions shared by Curtis.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would also like to share another gem by Curtis, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki/Porting-from-Moose-or-Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Porting from Moose or Moo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is a big help for anyone to move to Corinna from Moose or Moo. Most of my personal work shared on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/MANWAR&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; used Moo. The document by Curtis would be handy when porting to Corinna once it is part of core Perl. I am eagerly waiting for it to happen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;99th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. In two weeks time, I would be presenting the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I joined the team of editors in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;May 2018&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, thanks to the chief editor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, for all the support and guidance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and pray for the world peace.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html">
<title>#553 - Looking for a copy-editor for the Perl Weekly</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago some people asked me not to include politics in the Perl weekly so I won&#x27;t add my opinion on the murderous Russian dictator, but I would like to wish the best to all the people and their families I met while I was at the Perl conference in Kyiv, Ukraine 10 years ago.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Since Dave Cross got fed up with our broken English and started to copy-edit the Perl Weekly we became a bit spoiled by having him. Unfortunately (to us) he got himself busy with some real work and won&#x27;t be able to allocate the time for copy-editing the Perl Weekly. So now we are looking for a volunteer to do it. Basically every Monday, sometimes during the European morning hours (we don&#x27;t have a fixed timing), we push out a version to our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;web-site&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Then I&#x27;d send an email to the copy-editor who checks the most recent version and sends a Pull-Request on GitHub with the fixes. Once I get the PR, I merge it, regenerate the HTML and send out the newsletter. If you would be interested to volunteer, please get in touch with me so I know whom to notify.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-02-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/552.html">
<title>#552 - Outreachy and TPF</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/552.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Welcome to my personal 98th and overall 552nd edition of the Perl Weekly newsletter. I can&#x27;t wait for the day when I reach the 3-digits number.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today, I would like to talk about the Outreachy program and its association with TPF. Few days ago, I came across a Facebook post by a friend of mine sharing the news TPF (The Perl Foundation) is looking mentor and project for the year 2022. Please check out the official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/outreachy-2022&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have been following the work done as part of the Outreachy program. In the past, it has supported &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://world.openfoodfacts.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Food Facts&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, a very popular Perl based project. To be honest, I find the application process to submit project idea is not smooth. It would be a big help if &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge (Perl &#x26; Raku)&#x3C;/a&#x3E; get the support too. As some of you associated with the project knows it is currently built using Hugo and hosted on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/theweeklychallenge&#x22;&#x3E;Github&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have been planning to get it over to pure Perl template web based solution e.g. Dancer2 and hosted by real hosting service e.g Digital Ocean. As we grow bigger with times, I find it hard to manage the contributions on GitHub. It takes longer now to process comparatively. If it ever get approved, I can offer to be a mentor to the selected candidate.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was a good news shared last week about Perl warning i.e. &#x22;signatures are experimental&#x22; is going to disappear for ever with the next major release. I always wanted to have this feature in my Perl. I can&#x27;t wait for the next release to use it. Do you want to know more about it? Please &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/pull/19424&#x22;&#x3E;checkout here&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for more information.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you need help with Perl related queries?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I highly recommend, the two Facebook groups (members only), &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (run and managed by Curtis Poe) and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Programmers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (run and managed by Will Braswell).&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For parents of school going kids in England, welcome to the daily routine after a week long break. I know it is tough, specially if you have to cover two different schools in the morning rush. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-02-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/551.html">
<title>#551 - Nothing to do with Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/551.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I wrote about Wordle and that it has &#x27;Nothing to do with Perl&#x27;. Within a few hours Saif Ahmed proved me wrong and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/siuqy9/nothing_to_do_with_perl/&#x22;&#x3E;posted&#x3C;/a&#x3E; an implementation of Wordle in Perl. That&#x27;s the spirit!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On a totally different topic, but still nothing to do with Perl: I just saw someone I know from the Perl community posting yet another disgusting accusation against Israel. As people more clever than me said: &#x27;In the Middle Ages, Jews were accused of killing Christ. In the nineteenth and early twentieth century they were accused of ruining the nations where they lived. Today they are accused of apartheid, genocide, and having concentration camps&#x27;. Some people always find ways to blame the Jews for the crimes that are considered the worst by the contemporary civilization. Why am I writing about this, you ask? Because it hurts me a lot. You can&#x27;t do much about it, but I hope that whenever you hear or see something horrific thing that Israel is accused of, you will double and triple-check it before you accept it as truth, &#x27;like&#x27; it, or &#x27;share&#x27; it. I hope you&#x27;ll remember that an awful lot of misinformation is spread by people. Both by people who have an agenda against Jews and people who fall for true-looking lies.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-02-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/550.html">
<title>#550 - Perl &#x26; Unicode</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/550.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Are you a Unicode fan?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally, I am not. The reason is that I still struggle to get my head around it. During my early days of learning, I never got the opportunity to work with Unicode. So far, I have never had to deal extensively with Unicode characters. There is so much information available on the internet. I remember, a long time ago, I was dealing with the well-known warning &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Wide character in print&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. After a quick search, I came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/15210532/use-of-use-utf8-gives-me-wide-character-in-print&#x22;&#x3E;explanation&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have kept it bookmark for future reference. I know am repeating myself here as I remember talking about in an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/498.html&#x22;&#x3E;earlier weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is worth sharing with readers again and again.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, there is another reason why I am talking about it today. Let me share gem of an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/drhyde/a-brief-guide-to-perl-character-encoding-if7&#x22;&#x3E;article&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;David Cantrell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The article gives us very deeps knowledge about Unicode, specially for a Perl developer. It has cleared most of my doubts, so a big thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;David&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for such a great article. It also introduced me to a new word, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mojibake&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. A friend of mine on Facebook, suggested a CPAN module, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Test::Mojibake&#x22;&#x3E;Test::Mojibake&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which is very handy. I wish there was dedicated book on Perl and Unicode. Having said that, I found this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Perl_Programming/Unicode_UTF-8&#x22;&#x3E;Wikibook&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on the subject, you may want to explore it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I came across a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MijmeoH9LT4&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube video&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that explains Unicode in terms that any lay-person can easily understand. I loved it the way it is explained in a casual way. The guy in the video makes it so simple.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let&#x27;s talk about regexes in Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure you have used regexes in Perl at some point in your career. A few days ago, I found out a clever use of regexes shared by Abigail. The use of //g in list context. It completely blew me away. Later someone pointed me to the official Perl &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/perlre#Repeated-Patterns-Matching-a-Zero-length-Substring&#x22;&#x3E;documentation&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about it. If you are curious to know more about it then I would suggest you take a look at his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://abigail.github.io/HTML/Perl-Weekly-Challenge/week-150-1.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-02-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/549.html">
<title>#549 - Wordle</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/549.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Probably many of you have seen people posting their Wordle results. It is a nice little game that originally was written fo English speakers. Then several open source versions popped up that were then forked to create versions in many languages.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://wordle.szabgab.com/&#x22;&#x3E;partial list of Wordle clones&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I was hoping the author of one of these open source versions would make it easy to add other languages and then people would not need to host their own translated versions. So far I have not seen that happen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anyway, this has nothing to do with Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-01-31T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/548.html">
<title>#548 - Perl Books Collection</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/548.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you have a Perl books collection?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure most of us own the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Camel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; book. As you know, there have been hardly any new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books published in recent years. I recently bought two very popular &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Extending and Embedding Perl&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Network Programming with Perl&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have realised there are two distinct views about good old &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books. One view is that the recommendations in these books are no longer in use, since we have better choices available on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; now. I fully agree with this view but I also agree to the other view that it is still relevant in terms of base knowledge of the subject. Above all, there is a sentimental values attached to each &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; book that I own.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How about you?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, spoke about learning languages in his editorial. Being an &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Indian&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by birth, I know more than just the national language of India, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hindi&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I can understand, to be precise, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;six human languages&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Nowadays, I am learning &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Spanish&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; from my daughter as she is learning as part of her school curriculum. But here I would like to know how many programming languages one can fluently code in. Recently in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; contest, we have received loads of solutions in different languages. In &#x3C;strong&#x3E;week 147&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we received &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100+&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; solutions. One member who stands out front the crowd is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Abigail&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, who has contributed in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;30 different programming languages&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To me it seems impossible, but he did it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How many programming languages do I know? Well thanks to the weekly challenge, I have had the opportunity to code in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Python&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Java&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Swift&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as well as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, of course. Do you want to try some new languages? Please give it a try.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the week and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-01-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/547.html">
<title>#547 - Learning a human language vs. a programming language</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/547.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Learning a programming language is not easy, but have you tried learning a human language? You don&#x27;t have a compiler to tell you when you make a syntax error. You have a lot more words and rules and a lot more exceptions than in a programming language. Mostly however, the lack of quick feedback is what makes it hard. However, after a few months work you start to be able to speak to people in their native language.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As you might have read I&#x27;ve started to learn Ladino - the language spoken by the Jews who were expelled from the Iberian peninsula more than 500 years ago. It is a mix of medieval Spanish, Portuguese, Italian, French, Turkish, Serb, Arabic, and Hebrew. It is a fantastic exercise and it involves programming as well. Join me!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Something else: In Israel every Saturday evening, once the Shabbat ends, and throughout Sunday people say &#x27;have a good week&#x27;. Referring to the week that starts on Sunday, the first day of our work-week. I don&#x27;t recall ever hearing that or anything similar in Hungary. Not even on Sunday or Monday. I wonder, do you use any similar expression in whatever country and language environment you live in? Let me know and...&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a good week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-01-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/546.html">
<title>#546 - Perl Books</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/546.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Welcome to my first edition of 2022 and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;95th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; overall.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember there was a time when the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;O&#x27;Reilly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group published many Perl books. Then came a few other publishing houses like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Manning&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; publications. I am sure you must have owned a handful of Perl books from these publishers. In recent times not many Perl books have been written, except one or two by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. A friend of mine donated all his Perl books to a local library as he is moving to Python. It is a sad state to be honest. Recently, I came across a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; post by a friend of mine about a Perl book called &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extending and Embedding Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I knew about it but I had never had the chance to read it. So I decided to buy a used copy from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Amazon&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I must confess I was missing a great deal. If you haven&#x27;t read it then you must check it out. By the way, I have kept all my Perl books safe. I like to read physical books and not online versions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;With a new year, there is a tradition of new year resolutions. As far as I am concerned, I stopped making any resolutions two years ago. But this year, I decided to make one and stick to it. And the resolution is to get the draft of my first Perl book out as soon as possible. It has been going on for months now. It is embarassing now to even talk about it. There are so many things going on at the same time, I hardly find time for the book. Please wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A long time ago, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started a campaign to make live videos about Perl. He even did few pair-programming sessions and they were very popular. But then there has been no noise on that front in recent times. I used to make &#x3C;strong&#x3E;YouTube&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; videos for the Weekly Challenge during the middle of last year and then I also stopped because of lack of time. Last month, I started making videos again for the Weekly Challenge. It gives me immense pleasure when I see comments on my videos. Someone recently commented on one video and requested I should make videos of past challenges as well. I have to manage my time carefully otherwise my first book would be neglected again. Having said that, I am not giving up on making videos for the Weekly Challenge. If you are interested then please do check out my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/mohammadsajidanwar&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube Channel&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is one piece of good news shared by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; - that the MMVP (minimally minimal viable product) RFC for Corinna has been sent to P5P. I am keeping my fingers crossed.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, please look after yourself and your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-01-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>