<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2025, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/716.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/715.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/714.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/713.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/712.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/711.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/710.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/709.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/708.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/707.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/716.html">
<title>#716 - CVE in Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/716.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A few days ago, I wrote a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/cve-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CVEs&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was my first time looking at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CVEs&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; closely. Then I came across a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/1jy9pbe/perl_5402_and_5384_released_with_cve_fix&#x22;&#x3E;reddit post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; discussing &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CVE-2024-56406&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am a bit confused, was this fixed in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/5.38.4/perldelta&#x22;&#x3E;Perl v5.38.4&#x3C;/a&#x3E; or &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/perl5402delta&#x22;&#x3E;Perl v5.40.2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;That said, it gave me something fun to dig into. I already know what I&#x27;ll be doing next. During my search, I discovered the, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://security.metacpan.org&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Security Group&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, a community effort dedicated to handling security incidents on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Pretty cool!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Also the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit 2025&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; needs our support as mentioned in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-toolchain-summit-2025-needs-you&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I&#x27;m happy to see my current employer, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Oleeo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, listed as one of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;In-Kind Sponsors&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Now, I&#x27;m curious to find out who the lucky team member is that gets to attend!. It&#x27;s happening this year from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thursday May 1st&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Sunday May 4th 2025&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember back in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2019&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the summit was held so close to me, in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Marlow&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, if I recall correctly. I&#x27;ve said it before and I&#x27;ll say it again, I have to get involved in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; project. The main blocker last time was setting up the local development environment. I spoke to someone about it, can&#x27;t remember who, and he mentioned the team was working on simplifying the setup process to make it easier for contributors. I haven&#x27;t had a chance to check the current status, but I&#x27;m adding it to my ever-growing &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TODO&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; list.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Monday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and enjoy the rest of the newsletter!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-04-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/715.html">
<title>#715 - Why do companies move away from Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/715.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I asked &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/713.html&#x22;&#x3E;Why do companies migrate away from Perl?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and got a lot of responses. Most of them described the reasons their employers decided on this change but a few also wrote why they stay using Perl. Some of the answers were only a few lines, some were longer, going into a lot more details. I think I managed to reply to every one, though to some people I replied only today as I went over the messages again. I think it would be interesting o publish the full responses, but that&#x27;s up to the respective people. Let me know if you do so I can mention your post in the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I collected the most common responses and put them on my web site: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/why-move-away-from-perl-by-readers-of-the-perl-weekly&#x22;&#x3E;Why move away from Perl? From the readers of the Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The most frequently mentioned reason was the lack of available Perl developers (both senior and junior) and the lack of willingness to learn Perl. (coolness, few opportunities to reuse the knowladge)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The second reason was the lack of 3rd party libraries and the quality of the existing ones. Long-standing bugs, lots of open issues without a new release, etc.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;None of these complaints are new. They just got worse in the last decade or so as the number of people using Perl was shrinking.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The question is, what do we do about this? Some people keep working towards improving &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/psc/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the whole &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;ecosystem&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I still run this newsletter, despite the fact that I have no income from Perl and maybe I should invest my time in other hobbies.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What I see is that I can help Perl developers and companies using Perl to evaluate what would be the cost/benefit ratio staying with Perl or switching to some other language. I personally use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Rust and Python&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, though from the responses I saw that others switch to NodeJS and/or to Go.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So that&#x27;s where we are at. If you would like to extend the useful life of Perl there are plenty of things you can do and I&#x27;d be happy to read about them and share them in the newsletter. If you are interested in moving to some other language, you can talk to me. I might be able to help with that.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-04-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/714.html">
<title>#714 - Munging Data?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/714.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Idd&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to all the weekly newsletter readers who celebrate the festival. We celebrated Idd yesterday in England and I assume it is being celebrated today in my native country, India.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me personally, the highlight of last week was the event organised by the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It focussed on the new edition of the book, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/datamungingwithperl&#x22;&#x3E;Data Munging With Perl (2nd edition)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Unfortunately I missed the event despite registering for it. However, I&#x27;m told the recording will be available soon. If you missed it too, don&#x27;t worry, you will be able to catch up soon.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Speaking of the book, it is one of those must read classics for every &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; programmers. I read it, when it was first released, and I highly recommend you getting a copy to benefit from it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; mentioned &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; seemed to have had positive impact on me as I started writing more frequently these days. He was absolutely right!. But now that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is over, I&#x27;m not sure if I&#x27;ll continue at the same pace. That said, I truly enjoyed this little burst of writing. It felt like therapy to me. It allowed me to share whatever was on my mind at the time. And when I receive encouraging responses, it gives me even more motivation to keep going.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wrote few pieces last week, all of which are listed below. Please do check them out and share your thoughts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;d also like to take this opportunity to thank, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for his incredible book: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/perl_new_features&#x22;&#x3E;Perl New Features&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have shared my take on some of the topics discussed in the book, and I highly recommend getting a copy. The latest edition has been updated to cover &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This edition of the newsletter is packed with positive &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; news, so take your time and enjoy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Monday!!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-03-31T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/713.html">
<title>#713 - Why do companies migrate away from Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/713.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ramadan seems to have a very positive impact on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://manwar.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Mohammad Sajid Anwar (manwar)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, author of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and co-editor of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. He learns all kinds of new things and writes long blog posts about them. Some of them are Perl related, some are not. Anyway, see the links in this newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I, on the other hand, was recently contacted by a number of people wanting to migrate from Perl to Rust or Python. My first question is &#x3C;b&#x3E;why&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. After all even if I end up helping them with the move, I need to understand why do they want to move. Because of this I started to have some picture of why people feel the urge to move away from Perl. However, my sample is too small and probably rather biased.  None of the people who contacted me wanted to move to Java or C, or NodeJS. That&#x27;s can be for many reasons, one of them the fact that I don&#x27;t mention those languages on my LinkedIn profile.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So I&#x27;d like to get your help in understanding the central motivations for wanting to move away from Perl. If your company has moved away or is discussing the idea, I&#x27;d love to hear from you (a private email would be excellent) to understand the real pain points.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the other hand, if your company has recently moved to Perl or is planning to do so, I&#x27;d love to hear about that too. If they need help I&#x27;d be glad to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/moving-between-perl-python-rust&#x22;&#x3E;help them too&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and I am sure people in the Perl community would be thrilled to hear such stories. Even if we can&#x27;t publish the names of the companies.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-03-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/712.html">
<title>#712 - RIP Zefram</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/712.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We lost, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Zefram&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, a very respectable and prolific contributor to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core. The sad news was shared on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2025/03/msg269672.html&#x22;&#x3E;P5P&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. He was a regular attendee of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although I never interacted with him personally,  I always followed his contributions on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/ZEFRAM&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I also found his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.fysh.org/~zefram&#x22;&#x3E;web space&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where his works are nicely logged. Additionally, there is a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fZZBYRT5Ghc&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube video&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of him presenting at the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop 2015&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit 2025&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is happening from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;May 1 to May 4, 2025&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Hosting such event is only possible because of the generous sponsors, as &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2025/sponsors.html&#x22;&#x3E;listed here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Speaking of sponsors, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Deriv&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is one name you&#x27;ll find at most &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; gatherings. There is a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/why-deriv-supports-the-perl-ecosystem&#x22;&#x3E;dedicated post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that details why? I remember when &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Booking.com&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; used to be everywhere and was often the first to sponsor. Finding a sponsor in current environment is really tough, all credit goes to the team working tirelessly behind the scenes.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have a firsthand experience in seeking sponsors for my pet project: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I was lucky enough to find our first sponsor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Careers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; (by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Pete Sergeant&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;) without much effort. After a long term sponsorship, he stopped it about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; ago. Fortunately, we immediately found another generous sponsor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lance Wicks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, who has been our solo sponsor ever since. In both cases, I didn&#x27;t actively seek out sponsors, they found us. The main obstacle we face is that we are not a registered organisation. It remains a one-man organisation, and I lack the experience to run a registered organisation entity.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; continues, today marks &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 17 of Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and I find my routine slightly disrupted. Not that I am complaining, it is just that my sleep pattern has changed. I don&#x27;t need to emphasize, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;How important is sleep.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; I have learned that the hard way. However, there is a positive side to this change in routine. It has given me time to re-visit my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TODO&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; list. There was a time when I used to blog regularly but then I stopped completely. I don&#x27;t know if you&#x27;ve noticed but I&#x27;ve started writing again. Below are some of my recent posts, in case you missed any.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;ul&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/mce-how-to&#x22;&#x3E;MCE - How to?&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/slurp-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Slurp in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/future-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Future in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/promise-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Promise in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/scientist-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Scientist in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/extraction-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Text Extraction in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/ul&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is still a lot in the pipeline. I hope to share it soon. So far, I have received positive feedbacks which has given me the energy to continue. I would like to take this opportunity to thank each and every one of you for your kind words.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I should pause here and give you time to go through rest of the newsletter. Enjoy and please take a good care of your physical and mental health.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-03-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/711.html">
<title>#711 - Obfuscating Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/711.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As you might know I used to teach Perl and helped companies using Perl. Unfortunately, in the last couple of years only a few companies asked for my help with Perl and in most cases in areas I am not that familiar with. So I referred them to other, well known consultants.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Instead of Perl most of my clients are asking for help with Python and Rust. Especially because of the latter I felt the need to know more about C and C++. At least to the level where I understand the questions C/C++ programmers might have about Rust. So I dusted off my copy of &#x22;The C programming language&#x22; and started to learn again.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This time it will be especially fun as my son - who has been a professional programmer for more than 6 years now - decided to get a degree in Computer Sciences so he is also taking classes about C.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The way I learn is by trying to implement things and trying to explain them. So I am going to post about my new journey with C on the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://c.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;C Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; web site. You have been warned.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In other news we are celebrating Purim this week, when everyone dresses up as someone else. I wonder if I should dress up as a C programmer?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-03-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/710.html">
<title>#710 - PPC - Perl Proposed Changes</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/710.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you remember, the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/706.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where I mentioned about the work carried out for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;PPC web portal&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, it is now fully functional and operative: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.github.io/PPCs&#x22;&#x3E;PPC&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has everything that you need to know about the future plan of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Not only that, you can also involve in the new feature request. It made the process smooth and easy to understand. You can also take part in the discussion as well. This is your opportunity to share your view on the work being carried out. Or if you have any suggestion, you can use the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.github.io/PPCs/template&#x22;&#x3E;template&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to submit your ideas. Isn&#x27;t it simple? The best part for me is the ability to join the discussion in the work being done before it becomes the part of future release.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/709.html&#x22;&#x3E;last edition of newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, there was an announcement about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German Perl/Raku Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I encourage every community members to come forward and help the organisers to make it reach wider audiences. There is another announcement about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/from-code-to-community-sponsoring-tprc-2025&#x22;&#x3E;The North American Perl and Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Please do share the details with your colleagues and friends.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Are you new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and want to learn in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2025&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then checkout this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/zaphoddont/learning-perl-in-2025-3od3&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Here is another: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://medium.com/@chandantechie/step-by-step-guide-to-learning-perl-programming-from-novice-to-expert-56eaa0fce54b&#x22;&#x3E;Step-by-Step Guide to Learning PERL Programming: From Novice to Expert&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 3 of Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in England. May &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ALLAH s.w.t&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; bless you with peace, happiness and prosperity.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-03-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/709.html">
<title>#709 - GPRW and Perl Toolchain Summit</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/709.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;A reminder: The 27th &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl-workshop.de/&#x22;&#x3E;German Perl/Raku Workshop&#x3C;/a&#x3E; will take place between May 12-14, 2025, in Munich, Germany with &#x22;ticketing systems&#x22; as the main theme. The focus will be on building ticketing software, addressing real-world challenges, and exploring practical solutions. In addition to this deep dive, attendees can look forward to a variety of cutting-edge and exciting topics presented by renowned speakers. Whether you&#x27;re a seasoned developer or just curious about the latest in Perl and Raku, this event promises insights and inspiration for everyone!. See official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/gpw2025/i&#x22;&#x3E;website for more info&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Philippe Bruhat sent me a message: The Perl Toolchain Summit is happening again in 2025. This year, we&#x27;re going to be in Leipzig, hosted by Daniel B&#xF6;hmer and Tina M&#xFC;ller, from May 1st to May 4th, 2025. This year again, we&#x27;re going to need the support of sponsors to be able to bring our 30+ attendees in the same place at the same time to work on the Perl and CPAN toolchain. Download our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2025/PTS2025-Sponsor-Prospectus.pdf&#x22;&#x3E;sponsor prospectus&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. See the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/book/2025/02/announcing-the-perl-toolchain-summit-2025.html&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After several weeks in Hungary I am now back to Israel. We are having in-person events in the other language communities. Unfortunately not Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, I still offer help to companies that would like to reduce their bugs in their programming environment in Perl, Python, or Rust or that would like help introducing either of those languages.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-02-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/708.html">
<title>#708 - Perl is growing...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/708.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There&#x2002;are many interpretations of what it means to grow? I am using the term for&#x2002;new features. We get lots of&#x2002;improvements and new features with every release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the&#x2002;experimental &#x3C;strong&#x3E;class feature&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was rolled out in core. In the next maintenance release of Perl&#x2002;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, new field attribute &#x3C;strong&#x3E;:reader&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was added and&#x2002;many other improvements. The next thing, we all waited was for field attribute &#x3C;strong&#x3E;:writer&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Luckily it is already part of development release &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.41.7&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I made this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/b7579bf6ba2b8aa05434972d2beb03a3&#x22;&#x3E;gist&#x3C;/a&#x3E; demonstrating the core&#x2002;changes.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x2002;Release Policy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then there are two types of release i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Maintenance&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Development&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The even numbers&#x2002;are reserved for the maintenance release e.g. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.38, v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; whereas odd numbers are for the development release e.g. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.39, v5.41&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The maintenance release are mostly production ready.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are interested in release history then please checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perl_5_version_history&#x22;&#x3E;version history&#x3C;/a&#x3E; page. I found an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl/PPCs/pull/58&#x22;&#x3E;interesting proposal&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with regard to the version number.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently, I got to try the different facets of parallel and concurrent programming. Please find below the list covered so far.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;ol&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/0c37843a295f8b0d03542c26a3998c63&#x22;&#x3E;Thread Lifecycle&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/20ed64db9a881269deee98c7987aa59a&#x22;&#x3E;Multi-threading&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/9ed16ea3df2391e123446ef04f0b28a7&#x22;&#x3E;Multi-processing&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/f1bc103b8213998ddbfbb64796ff80eb&#x22;&#x3E;Thread Synchronization&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/8ce2a5878f190cbfa39a3a177d40929f&#x22;&#x3E;Process Synchronization&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/e2915771fb709cc4379abd1d8aba7ea3&#x22;&#x3E;Read/Write Lock&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/d2a18b1609250cef29bf54b998623f54&#x22;&#x3E;Re-entrant Lock&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/82fce643703d449cf395dd34fedbff67&#x22;&#x3E;Livelock&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/7dce3cbc96f4b98229e471bc7e48a0ca&#x22;&#x3E;CPU bound Thread Performance&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/691de0aa1e1992f9becbb6960c1f9e10&#x22;&#x3E;IO bound Thread Performance&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/ol&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-02-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/707.html">
<title>#707 - Is it ethical?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/707.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A week or so ago I &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/szabgab_perl-python-rust-activity-7289991817306034177-Xra2&#x22;&#x3E;posted on LinkedIn&#x3C;/a&#x3E; asking the rather rhetorical question, if I should offer a service helping companies move from Perl to Python or Rust. The comment I got is that I should not as it hurts the Perl community and that it would be &#x3C;b&#x3E;unethical&#x3C;/b&#x3E; to rewrite something in an inferior language. I admit, this comment really annoyed me.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Instead of arguing I published &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/szabgab_perl-python-perl-activity-7290365095337979905-Mbnh&#x22;&#x3E;another post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; asking if it would be ethical to wtite anything in Perl which is, I guess the flip side of the above comment. Now that post got a lot of comments. Some really valuable, some really strange ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It think the question of ethics depends a lot on the parties involved. Do I write the program for myself? Am I offering the resulting application as a service? Am I writing it for a client who will have to maintain it? Are the other involved parties informed about the costs and risk of the choices we make?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2025-02-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>