<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/593.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/592.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/591.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html">
<title>#599 - Open Source Development Course for Perl developers</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently I started to offer a course called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The idea is to let participants learn and practice(!) git/github/pull-request/testing/code-coverage/linters/ci/etc. That way they improve their development practices and can also contribute to Open Source projects.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is a course designed to run for 12-13 weeks with about 5 hours per week workload. It can be either part of a university program or people can take it while they have a full-time job. Every week there is a 1-2 hours long presentation and the rest is hands-on work with my async help.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;d like to offer a version of this course especially for people who are interested in contributing to Perl-based Open Source projects. The participants will learn Perl-specific tools and processes. All proceedings will go to sponsor the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/book/2023/01/the-perl-toolchain-summit-is-back-in-2023.html&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Check out &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-public-2023-01-perl&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for further details and let me know ASAP if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-16T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html">
<title>#598 - TIOBE and Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy New Year everyone !!!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Year 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; saw the biggest release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was released with big bang. There were lots of positive vibes around it. I had never seen such noise before. If you missed the fun then you can checkout my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not a big fan of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TIOBE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but came across &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.tiobe.com/tiobe-index&#x22;&#x3E;TIOBE Index for January 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; going up slightly in the index recently. It is refreshing to see the progress. Who knows one day, it would reach the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TOP 5&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; brackets.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking back the participation in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, it looks promising. Nearly &#x3C;strong&#x3E;10K&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contributions in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by the members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the last &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What is new happening in Perl?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, personally, I am looking forward to the modern OO &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in core &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; wrote an interesting &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/converting-object-oriented-code-to-corinna.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; recently where he shared his real life experience with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-09T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html">
<title>#597 - Happy New Year!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I hope you had a successful 2022 and you are ready for the next year. I certainly have lots of plans. As always. They are also changing a lot all the time. One of them is a new course I am working on called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;OSDC - Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is a hands-on course that covers git/GitHub/GitLab/Testing/CI using real-world open source projects. It is also not only a plan, I am starting the first session next Sunday. It will be given in Hebrew.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For the course I started to collect &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/open-source-by-corporations&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source projects developed by corporations&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There are a few where the product is open source such as &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://redis.io/&#x22;&#x3E;Redis&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.elastic.co/&#x22;&#x3E;Elastic&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There are others where the company shares some of its code as open source such as Netflix, Facebook, or Booking.com.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;d like to ask for your help. Look around at your company and maybe other companies and let me know which one shares projects using an Open Source license. It would help me and the participants of this courses a lot. For the purpose of the course and for my collection the programming languages don&#x27;t matter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, if you can also point out Perl-based projects, that would be even better. Then I could feature these projects in the newsletter. Let&#x27;s start now with one I already found:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/bookingcom/pakket&#x22;&#x3E;pakket&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.booking.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Booking.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is an Unopinionated Meta-Packaging System that allows you to manage dependencies. It works by trying to avoid work.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your year!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-02T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html">
<title>#596 - New Year Resolution</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;With the end of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; celebration, another celebration kicks in i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Christmas/Boxing Day&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although I don&#x27;t celebrate, being a Muslim, but I do enjoy the break from the routine work.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This edition of the weekly newsletter is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;120th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope you enjoy reading the newsletter as much as I do getting ready for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you have any new year resolutions?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I used to but then last year I stopped it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Why?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well couple of projects closed to my heart didn&#x27;t get started and that made me very pessimistic. I feel so bad that I don&#x27;t even talk about it. I hope new year will bring positive change.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Still, I don&#x27;t feel like setting new year resolutions. Could it be, I am getting old to keep up with fast pace dev life? Having said, the dev inside me still alive but just needs some push. Fortunately I have so many people around me that always gives me much needed positive energy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let&#x27;s talk about some positivity now. Well for me, it was the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and team. I wanted to be part of it but then missed the train unfortunately. Never mind, there is always next time. Having said, I did manage to get &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/app-timer&#x22;&#x3E;the post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; up but was too late to make it. Fortunately my contribution to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; did work out nicely like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://raku-advent.blog/2022/12/21/day-21-raku-and-i-journey-begin&#x22;&#x3E;Raku and I&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the holidays and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html">
<title>#595 - Happy Hanukkah - Merry Christmas</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Yesterday was the 35th birthday of Perl. Congratulation to Larry Wall!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the 1st day of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanukkah&#x22;&#x3E;Hanukkah&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, commemorating the Maccabean revolt agains the Seleucid (Greek) Empire when the Jews recovered Jerusalem roughly 2200 years ago. When I go for my daily stroll, I often pass by some archeological digging from that era. We lit the first candle yesterday night.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In a few days the Christian world will celebrate Christmas, the birth of Yeshua (commonly known as Jesus) roughtly 164 years later. Both events are celebrated by lights and way too much food.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I wrote extensively about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/&#x22;&#x3E;DEV&#x3C;/a&#x3E; inviting you to post there and even if you don&#x27;t feel like writing, at least to support the few of us who post about Perl. A few people followed my call. It is still mostly only Yuki Kimoto posting there, but there were a few posts by others, there were some comments and a few &#x22;likes&#x22;. As for me, I publish about a lot of things, not only Perl and I put most of them in series. I have a steady number or readers and the number of followers is also growing nicely. There are more than 400 already. If you too are interested about the subjects I write about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/&#x22;&#x3E;follow me on DEV&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html">
<title>#594 - Advent Calendar</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; celebration begins with the start of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. For all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans, we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to the hard work of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his team. I am sure you have checked out the amazing daily source of fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As of today, we have got through &#x3C;strong&#x3E;12 days&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you have any favourite so far?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well I do have mine. To me the best part is the festive flavour in every article. I find it amusing and fun to read the story. I have contributed in the past but never got around to add the spice. I would blame the lack of background knowledge. This year&#x27;s calendar started with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toby Inkster&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; creation &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-01.html&#x22;&#x3E;Silent Mite&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. What a cool way to start the calendar. If you look at closely all the contributions so far, you would notice a fresh air with lots of positive energy. One name stands out very prominently this year is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault DUPONCHELLE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. His first contribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-03.html&#x22;&#x3E;Santa is on GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was a nice way to begin the journey. Then found a gem from a very dear friend of mine, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; talking about good old friend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CGI&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In fact, I have seen him presenting the subject &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-04.html&#x22;&#x3E;northpole.cgi&#x3C;/a&#x3E; at the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Conference&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found another piece of work by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault DUPONCHELLE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MongoDB&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 5&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contribution &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-05.html&#x22;&#x3E;Catching dreams&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is worth checking, if you want to explore &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MongoDB&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If I am not mistaken then few years ago, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared his creation &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/SVG::ChristmasTree&#x22;&#x3E;SVG::ChristmasTree&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I was happy to see it part of this year calendar too, not directly though. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 8&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-08.html&#x22;&#x3E;A Perlmas Tree&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Maximilian Lika&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 11&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contribution very technical dealing with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;signal ALRM&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Not an easy subject to discuss in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in my humble opinion. Thanks &#x3C;strong&#x3E;OODLER&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the fine contribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-11.html&#x22;&#x3E;Wake up! Time to open presents!&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are still looking for more &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; theme fun then I would highly recommend, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2022&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Like in the past, this year also, it has contributions from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; hand picked by me. I am sure you would find it interesting.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am working on something that I would love to be part of this year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Hopefully it would be ready soon. Well I am also working on something similar for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be an achievement if I can get both done on time. Please wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/593.html">
<title>#593 - Perl on DEV.to</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/593.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I registered to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/&#x22;&#x3E;DEV.to&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in 2017, more than 5 years ago. Posted a few articles with rather limited success: less than 10 people looked at the articles. Then in 2020 I posted a few more articles. On one of them &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/tests-are-awesome-3i63&#x22;&#x3E;Tests are awesome!&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I got as many as 300 readers, but the others have not received much love so I did not continue publishing. In 2021 I had another experiment when I published &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/perl-modules-with-their-own-web-site-2gmo&#x22;&#x3E;Perl modules with their own web site&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on which there were some 600 visitors. Primarily the readers of the Perl Weekly newsletter. I published a few more articles with readers in the low 10s. A few weeks ago I started to publish again. This time several of my articles got above 100 viewers and one, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/open-source-development-courses-5d4b&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Courses&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is already above 1100 viewers. I started to get around 600 readers a day. That&#x27;s already really valuable!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So what happened? There were a couple of changes: 1. There are more people on DEV. 2. I publish a lot more articles that appeal to a wider range of people. 3. There is a sort-of network effect. The more people up-vote and bookmark (the two kinds of reactions on DEV) my articles the more people will see it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The nice thing about DEV is that I can republish the articles I published elsewhere (e.g. on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;PerlMaven&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Code-Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, or &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/&#x22;&#x3E;blogs.perl.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;), and also I can set the canonical URL of each article on DEV to the original one on my blog. That way I get the visitors on DEV as well, but the &#x27;Google juice&#x27; the articles receive will flow over to my sites. It seems like a win-win for DEV and authors who have blogs elsewhere. You can even configure DEV to pull your RSS feed and create drafts from your articles published elsewhere. I even started to republish the content of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/perl-weekly-591-less-than-50-use-ci-4966&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So here is what I suggest. If you already write about Perl elsewhere, republish those articles on DEV and tag them with &#x3C;b&#x3E;perl&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. If you are primarily a reader of articles, then register on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/&#x22;&#x3E;DEV&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and start up-voting the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/t/perl&#x22;&#x3E;Perl-related posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E; you like. You can even follow a few authors there, get notified when they have new posts, and up-vote those to encourage them to write even more.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Alternatively, you can watch the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.theplanetarium.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Planetarium&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It already follows the &#x3C;b&#x3E;perl&#x3C;/b&#x3E; tag on DEV.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/592.html">
<title>#592 - Perl Blogging?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/592.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We all know not many people blog about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; anymore. Are we doing anything to get it back on track? Well, unfortunately again, nothing is happening on that front either.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;But, hey, there is still hope and handful of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans doing their best. One of them is our chief editor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. He has been running &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for years now and many of us benefitted from his work. He recently started blogging on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab&#x22;&#x3E;Dev.To&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I request all the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans to follow him and like blog post. I didn&#x27;t have the account there before so I decided to create &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;personal account&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Although I no longer blog at all but this is going to change soon. Earlier I used to blog on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar&#x22;&#x3E;blogs.perl.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E; but then I moved to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; recently.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about blogging, how can I miss one name, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Flavio Poletti&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? He has been blogging daily for years now. Feel free to check out his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.polettix.it/ETOOBUSY&#x22;&#x3E;work here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Kudos to him for his effort.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would like to mention another name, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, for his hard work in reviving the good old friend, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has been helping him in the project too. I remember there was a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2022/07/21/the-perl-advent-calendar-2022-call-for-papers-is-now-open&#x22;&#x3E;call for papers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by him. If you have time and something to share about your favourite &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; module then please do contribute. I have booked one slot for myself for this year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Hopefully, I will submit my article on time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, I would like to thank all the members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for creating friendly and positive vibes for years now. As of today, they have published &#x3C;strong&#x3E;3000+ blog posts&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; sharing creative ideas and solutions. If you are interested then please do checkout &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/recaps&#x22;&#x3E;blog posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-11-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/591.html">
<title>#591 - Less than 50% use CI</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/591.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One of the best things about programming is that you can get almost immediate feedback from your work. The compiler tells you immediately if your code has syntax errors. Your tests can tell you within minutes if your code does what you expected on your computer. Your CI system can tell you within another few minutes if your code works on various other environments.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the Perl community writing test became the norm. You rarely find any Open Source Perl code without tests. People write test even for code that only they use. Even for code they consider &#x27;toys&#x27;. Yet with CI we are still far from it. On our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/metacpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;stats page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; you can see that 12% are missing their link to VCS (some of those do have VCS they are just missing the link), but 45-60% (depending on the week) of CPAN releases have no CI configured.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;From experience I know that corporations are way behind the curve in terms of test writing. So I can only imagine how few use Continuous Integration. There is a lot of work to be done.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-11-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html">
<title>#590 - Perl &#x26; Corinna</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Congratulation to all England cricket team fans for the T20I world cup trophy. You played like a champion in the final. Although you beat us (India) in the semi final, still I am very happy for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Did you hear any update about Corinna recently?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We used to get regular update earlier and I really enjoyed the discussion about the Corinna. Last week &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/OvidPerl/status/1590247361384792065&#x22;&#x3E;tweet&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he mentioned that code example has been added to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/blob/master/README.md&#x22;&#x3E;README.md&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure you are going to love it. Thank you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and the entire team of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for all the hard work. We are waiting for it patiently.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was one more &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/OvidPerl/status/1591119906510077963&#x22;&#x3E;tweet&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; that made my day about the proposed feature of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where you no longer need to end module with true value. In my career of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;23 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I have come across many creative ways to return true values in the module. I welcome this change and thanks the entire team.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am keeping the editorial short this week as I am running short of time. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-11-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>