<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2024, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/659.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/658.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/657.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/656.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/655.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html">
<title>#661 - Perl Toolchain Summit 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/release/PEVANS/perl-5.39.9/view/pod/perldelta.pod&#x22;&#x3E;Perl 5.39.9 was released&#x3C;/a&#x3E; including the new ^^ operator. It is only a development release, but I&#x27;d like to encourage you to give it a try and give feedback to the developers.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was some nefarious activity on CPAN. Someone &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/1biniqg/perl5382_suspiciously_reposted_to_cpan/&#x22;&#x3E;re-uploaded perl-5-38.2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It was reported and the security team quickly eliminated the threat.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was wondering if I should write about the hate mails I received: one for myself as Jew (my ethnicity) triggered by what I wrote &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/659.html&#x22;&#x3E;two weeks ago&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and one on behalf of Mohammed as a Muslim (his religion) triggered by what he wrote &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html&#x22;&#x3E;last week&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I&#x27;ve removed these people from the distribution, but I think they need more accountability. I am still contemplating publishing the names of these people along with their messages so the Perl community and their employers will be aware of that. After all most of us don&#x27;t want to work with abusive people, do we?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl Toolchain Summit is coming again and they need your help sponsoring the even. Here is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2024/PTS2024-Sponsor-Prospectus.pdf&#x22;&#x3E;Sponsor prospectus for Perl Toolchain Summit 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Last year I ran an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-2023-01-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;online course about Open Source development&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the proceedings went to the summit (though I transferred them late, so probably they could not use that in time). This year I don&#x27;t have the time for that, but I hope you will see the value in the summit and will sponsor it directly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html">
<title>#660 - What&#x27;s new ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to all the readers who fast during this holy month. May &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ALLAH s.w.t&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; accept your fasting, Ameen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently became active on official Slack for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; after a long gap. I noticed it is very much active and live. Lots of positive noise and useful information shared with each other. I am not a big fan of Slack but after spending just few days, I find it easy to move around. I would like to keep an eye for important news and announcement. Earlier my only source of information was the good old &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org&#x22;&#x3E;https://blogs.perl.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We used to have regular post by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; enthusiasts but that has stopped unfortunately. And I don&#x27;t blame them as I also stopped blogging completely. As and when I do blog, I use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; platform. Having said, the platform is still used by some, for example &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Steering Council&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for weekly updates. Every now and then, you do get some magical post by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans. One such post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/e_choroba/2024/03/changes-in-mooxroleparameterized.html&#x22;&#x3E;Changes in MooX::Role::Parameterized&#x3C;/a&#x3E; appeared last week by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;E. Choroba&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have been a big fan of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Moo - Minimalist Object Orientation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, so this post became even more important for me. Although, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has made it to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core, it is still a long way before it becomes a complete solution to all OO needs. I am looking forward to the next big release which would bring in some more features, hopefully.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was introduced to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by the post series &#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;David Farrell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It used to be regular every month with full of fun facts about new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; modules released. During those days, I used to be active on CPAN and released few &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I had the honour to find place in the post often. Recently &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; took the initiative to revive the activities on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Because of his hard work and with the help of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mathew Korica&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; we now have the post series back. You must check latest in the series, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-february-2024&#x22;&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN - February 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just realised that this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;150th&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; edition and in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 months&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; I will complete &#x3C;strong&#x3E;6 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as co-editor of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; newsletter. It has been a very fruitful learning experience for me and I enjoyed it thoroughly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Keep the spirit high and don&#x27;t let the bad influence pull you down. Please do take care your health and loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/659.html">
<title>#659 - The big chess game</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/659.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3_Szab%C3%B3_(chess_player)&#x22;&#x3E;My father was a chess player&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. In his best time he was sometimes called &#x22;the best non-Russian chess player&#x22;. He survived WWII and the Holocaust in a Hungarian forced labor camp and in Russian POV camp. When he got back to Hungary all he wanted to do is get back to chess. He did not want to care about &#x27;politics&#x27;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the 90s he often lamented that he did not pay enough attention to what went on in Hungary in the 50&#x27;s. That he was not aware of the communist atrocities in Hungary and neighboring countries.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been publishing the Perl Weekly for more than 12 years. In the first 9-10 year I think I have never mentioned anything besides Perl or related technologies. I wish I could keep focusing on technology only. Unfortunately I don&#x27;t have that luxury any more.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Frankly, if we paid more attention to what&#x27;s going on outside of Perl and outside of technology in general, maybe we would not be in such a bad situation.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On a related subject, I hear &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garry_Kasparov&#x22;&#x3E;Garry Kasparov&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was added to the list of &#x27;terrorists and extremists&#x27; by Russia.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We can&#x27;t change the past - well, some do it anyway by lying about history - but we also cannot claim we &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://saturday-october-seven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;did not know&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We want to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stories.bringthemhomenow.net/&#x22;&#x3E;bring them home&#x3C;/a&#x3E;!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a better week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/658.html">
<title>#658 - Perl // Outreachy</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/658.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has been associated with the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.outreachy.org&#x22;&#x3E;Outreachy program&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for sometime. I have followed the annual program very closely in recent times. I noticed it is helping young fresh bloods getting into open source from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Indian subcontinent&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I know for sure, there are plenty of scope to bring in young students into Perl fold. Unfortunately it is not tapped with focussed program yet. I really want to do something to bring &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; back to dicussion table among freshers. I know I have slowdown a bit in recent time because of health issues but I still have the same energy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For the first time, I have submitted my pet project &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for the next &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Outreachy program&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping to see some fresh talents coming forward and work with us. Looking forward to mentor and share my experience. I just wish the process was a bit simpler. May be, it is my first time, I find it harder to follow through. My advice to all newcomers stay focussed and work towards your goal taking one step at a time. Don&#x27;t forget to enjoy the journey while learning. It would make a big difference, trust me.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Look after your health and stay happy, specially your mental health.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/657.html">
<title>#657 - Perl Toolchain Summit in 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/657.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi There!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As the newsletter goes out to more than 4,000 people I often get back vacation notifications. Most of them are in English, but there are a few that are in some other language. I assume the local language of where that person works. A few of them are both in English and in the local language.  Usually a language  that I don&#x27;t fully understand. I can guess and I can use an automated translator, but it seems it would make sense for these messages to include an English version as well.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Apparently we missed the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/book/2024/02/announcing-the-perl-toolchain-summit-in-2024.html&#x22;&#x3E;announcement of the Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. In 2024 it will be in Lisbon, Portugal, from Wednesday April 25 to Sunday April 28. They are looking for sponsors.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-02-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/656.html">
<title>#656 - Perl Conference</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/656.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Did you get the opportunity to attend YAPC::Hiroshima?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking at whatever news is out in public about the conference, it appears to be a big success. A big round of applause to everyone involved. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Makoto Nozaki&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared his experience in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/makoto_nozaki/2024/02/yapchiroshima-i-attended-yapchiroshima-in-japan.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There were regular updates shared on Twitter profiles e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/kfly8&#x22;&#x3E;kobaken&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/yapcjapan&#x22;&#x3E;yapcjapan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Japan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is one of few places that I always wanted to visit. I still remember when I was in college my mom asked me she wanted to see &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Tokyo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; city. I casually promised her that time. But when I moved to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;England&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; she kept reminding me about my promise but for health reason she couldn&#x27;t travel. I was first introduced to the city when I watched the movie &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_in_Tokyo&#x22;&#x3E;Love in Tokyo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I think &#x3C;strong&#x3E;YAPC Japan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; would be the perfect excuse to fulfill my mom&#x27;s wish. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Israel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is also one place that I would like to visit once in my life time and meet &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in person.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How about upcoming TPRC 2024 in Las Vegas?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember when it was annonced at the end of conferece in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; last year, there was big cheers all around. I could feel the positive energy. There was a call for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las/index.php/volunteer&#x22;&#x3E;volunteer&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.papercall.io/tprclas24&#x22;&#x3E;presentation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If I managed to find time and health permit then I would definite go to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure it is going to beat the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; experience. I would submit the talk only when I am 100% sure to travel. I really miss the similar gatherings in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Europe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Talking about conference, what&#x27;s happening to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? Don&#x27;t you miss &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? I honestly hope it happens this year and we get to meet local champions. It is the only time, I get to meet my idols like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Neil Bowers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There is also a friend of mine, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Theo van Hoesel&#x3C;/strong, regulars to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; meetup, I miss him. I remember during one such meetup he gave short presentation on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=09iUEbgmmxg&#x22;&#x3E;Iphone iOS scripting&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I simply loved it. His ability to present difficult topic looks easy, is commendable. Let&#x27;s bring back the golden moments.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Back to reality, the schools are open today after a week long holiday here in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Too much trouble, I wonder how parents cope up with this routine. I just go with the flow, no choice. You look after yourself and loved ones. Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-02-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/655.html">
<title>#655 - What&#x27;s new in Perl and on CPAN? What&#x27;s new in Italy?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/655.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a hiatus of 4 years, it seems the &#x22;What&#x27;s new on CPAN&#x22; series is back on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Apparently there was already one published December 20 &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-november-2023/&#x22;&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN - November 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and then one on January 9, 2023 &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-december-2023&#x22;&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN - December 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Thanks to Mathew Korica.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you&#x27;d like to know what&#x27;s going on with Perl, I&#x27;d suggest you watch the presentation of Paul Evans from the recent FOSDEM: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ATbmoP34zRs&#x22;&#x3E;Updates from the PSC&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;And a last minute notification I received from Michele Beltrame that made me quite happy: After some years of stagnant activity, we opened a &#x3C;b&#x3E;Telegram&#x3C;/b&#x3E; group for the Italian Perl community. Link from the web site of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.it/&#x22;&#x3E;Italian Perl Mongers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-02-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html">
<title>#654 - Perl and FOSDEM</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Did you know FOSDEM happened last week?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;FOSDEM&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, Free and Open source Software Developers&#x27; European Meeting, is still a mystery for me. Few years ago a fellow member of LPW organising team introduced me to FOSDEM for the first time. Ever since, I always wanted to attend at least once just to experience the gatherings. I found out familiar faces attending this year FOSDEM like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Evans&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Salve J. Nilsen&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although the location wasn&#x27;t far from my place but timing wasn&#x27;t ideal. I wish I was mentally prepared to attend this year FOSDEM. I even saw a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/vanhoesel/2024/02/fosdem-2024-tprf-community-dinner.html&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Theo van Hoesel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with regard to TPRF sponsored Dinner at FOSDEM. It would have been a great opportunity to meet good old friends. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared the live video link from the event. I was able to watch the fun luckily thanks to the organiser. I am hoping the video recordings of the event would be made public soon. Here is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://archive.fosdem.org/2021/schedule/track/perl_and_raku_programming&#x22;&#x3E;schedule&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Perl and Raku Programming devroom.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you tried ChatGPT?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have and I find it fun playing with it. Recently I asked &#x22;How do I check if memcached server is running locally and listening to default port?&#x22;. Like always, I got instant response with few lines of Perl to get the desired result. Guess what, it didn&#x27;t do what I asked it to do. I went back and asked again. This time, I got another variation. I tried that too but no luck. By now, I was too tired to repeat the question. I then used CPAN module &#x3C;strong&#x3E;IO::Socket::INET&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to see if I can create socket. I know it is not ideal but does the job. Time to move on to next thing in the long &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TODO&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; list.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Does a programmer need to know system admin task also?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been a programmer and only programmer all my life. I remember in the past, I was sent to a week long training to learn sysadmin tasks. It was fresh for a week after the training then I was back to my programmer life. I did enjoy the training and learnt few tricks. As some of you know about my CPAN module, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Map::Tube&#x22;&#x3E;Map::Tube&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I published in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2010&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I decided to create &#x3C;strong&#x3E;REST API&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; interface to play with it. Luckily I had another CPAN module, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Map::Tube::Server&#x22;&#x3E;Map::Tube::Server&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. With this, I was able to setup the server in no time on my local box. Now comes the difficult task, create service to manage the server. Being a programmer doesn&#x27;t help the cause, also when your box is running &#x3C;strong&#x3E;WSL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and not real linux. With the limitation of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;WSL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I had only one option to create service based on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;init.d&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It wasn&#x27;t hard to create service file for the map server. I could even use the service to start the server but termination didn&#x27;t work for some strange reason. I didn&#x27;t have the energy to ask &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ChatGPT&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for help. It has to wait for now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am thinking of writing a blog post about the whole process, if I can find spare moment.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter and do share your Perl story with us.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-02-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html">
<title>#653 - Perl &#x26; Raku Conference 2024 to Host a Science Track!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are monitoring the number of subscribers of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that we have on the front page, you can see that it dropped by more than 70 today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;That&#x27;s because after a long period of time I went through the bounce-reports of Sendgrid, the provider I use to send the messages. There were many  reporting &#x3C;b&#x3E;No such user&#x3C;/b&#x3E; or that &#x3C;b&#x3E;the email account that you tried to reach is over quota and inactive.&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. I know I missed some and more will appear in the list next week, but it was enough for today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;BTW, we store the historical data in the src/count.txt file in our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly&#x22;&#x3E;repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If I am not mistaken it peaked on week 370-371 with 6,449 subscribers. Now we are down to 4,523 that we had between the weeks 113-114.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html">
<title>#652 - Perl and TPF</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;string&#x3E;Is it TPF or TPRF?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking at the official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org&#x22;&#x3E;news page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, it still says &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation News&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have no issue how you call it whether &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The most important bit is the work they do to promote &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; programming languages. There was a big news recently as we had the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/presidentslettert2024&#x22;&#x3E;Letter from the President&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We don&#x27;t very often hear from the President. I was curious to find out what is special this time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would like to talk about two things, one the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2024 Prospectus&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and second about new board members. Honestly, I never knew about the prospectus. I will be watching when it gets published more likely ahead of the annual conference in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the month of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;June 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. With regard to the new members, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bruce Gray&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ruth Holloway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would like to congratulate both of them. I am confident they are going to be a big help to present the wider audience point of views. It is a proud moment for me as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bruce Gray&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is one of the most active and regular members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;OK, tell me how many of you watched the live release of Perl v5.39.7?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To be honest with you, I wasn&#x27;t aware of such live streaming of Perl release. Thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for this information in the last edition of the newsletter. For me, it was perfect timing, first thing on Saturday morning. I was a mute spectator, just watching the release flow. Some of the things just went above my head but few things I could follow. It was fun though. I would definitely watch the live streaming if it happens again. Just out of curiosity, I asked one question in the end about release ETA of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I got the response that in the next &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2-3 months&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. That made me really happy as I am eagerly waiting for the next big release. Looking forward to more features to the newly added OO ecosystem.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you use GitHub Actions?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was fortunate to attend the talk on the subject by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; at the Perl Conference in Toronto last summer. It is really cool thing to have if you have codebase in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I would highly recommend you checkout his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2024/01/github-actions-for-perl-development&#x22;&#x3E;latest post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he shared the details.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Are you enjoying the cold days and nights of January?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally, I just hate it as my body doesn&#x27;t like extreme condition either cold or hot. I know I came from a place in India where &#x3C;strong&#x3E;50 degree celcius&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was normal during summer. Not anymore unfortunately, may be I am getting old now. I just want &#x3C;strong&#x3E;January&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to get over asap as in this month we hardly get any sun where I live.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a safe and fun week ahead.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>