<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/607.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/606.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/605.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/604.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html">
<title>#611 - Test coverage on CPAN Digger</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Easter and Happy Passover!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In Hungary Easter Monday is the time to go out and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://medium.com/globetrotters/the-curious-tradition-of-sprinkling-women-so-they-can-grow-5b3e69e0d30d&#x22;&#x3E;sprinkle women with water&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Back when I grew up I was not aware that it is in order so they can grow, but whatever. Nor did I know that it was a pre-Christian (aka. Pagan) tradition.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Celebrating Passover, among other things, requires cleaning your house, your car, your office that turned into the big spring cleaning tradition in many parts of the world. I cleaned my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/notifications&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub notifications&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had some 600 entries there. Luckily most of them were just updates and did not require any action from me.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;During the last week I spent way too much time on sending pull-requests to CPAN modules, but I also got around to improve the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN::Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It does not store the generated html files in the git repository any more and it now includes the test coverage numbers from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cpancover.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPANCover&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It makes it easy to find a CPAN package that needs contributors to increase the test coverage. I also believe that in most cases the author of a package that was recently released (and thus appear on the CPAN Digger) will more likely be active on the package and thus more likely to accept your contribution.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently saw a post asking &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/bekahhw/why-arent-you-contributing-to-open-source-3nk8&#x22;&#x3E;Why aren&#x2019;t you contributing to open source?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; There were a number of interesting answers, but the top most one was focusing way more on &#x27;releasing your own open source&#x27;, while I think there us a huge open field &#x3C;b&#x3E;contributing to an existing open source project&#x3C;/b&#x3E; without the burden of maintaining it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Another comment talked about the difficulty with the agreements one needs to sign on the big, corporation-created projects, such as React. Actually only a very small fraction of open source projects are from corporations and only a very small fraction requires any signed agreements. Avoid those. Pick one that does not require any such agreement. Pick one that is not a huge, well known project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html">
<title>#610 - Perl and TPF</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Belated &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to those who celebrate the holy month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To me and most of us, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is the parent body who supports the language. With the emergence of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, it is now referred as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRF (The Perl and Raku Foundation)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There have been many positive changes brought by the parent body. One of them is the creation of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Steering Council&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and we even get the weekly update too. You can checkout the latest update from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/psc/2023/03/this-week-in-psc-102.html&#x22;&#x3E;PSC&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The change in name reminds me when I had to change the name &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to accommodate &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and many other languages. Even today, I use the term &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as I find it hard to move on. The best part is the team shares ideas from other languages. A fellow &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; member, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Cheok-Yin Fung&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started series where she talks about popular and usefull &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; module. Latest in the series is about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/c_y_fung/2023/03/graph---weekly-travelling-in-cpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;Graph&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you like the idea then do share your comments and encourge her. I am so proud of her. I would also like to mention about the work recently done by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2023/03/improvements-to-planet-perl-and-perlanet&#x22;&#x3E;Improvements to Planet Perl and Perlanet&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am looking forward to the next big stable release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; which would bring the new shiny OO concept, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; among many other features. Ideally I would want to have &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v7&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as it was suggested many years ago. I have no clue if anything is happening on that front.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you look at the positive noises on so many social platforms, I am confident we are going to bounce back soon. We have best of the best talent, we just need guidance. I am sure, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; can help us on that front too. So all you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Hackers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, please don&#x27;t loose hope. We would bring back the glory we once had. For now enjoy all the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; goodies in the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html">
<title>#609 - Open Source and your workplace</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You probably already heard about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I started to teach. The core assumption there is that helping more people contribute to Open Source will make the world a better place.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been teach two versions of this course as open registration where anyone could register and I already started to teach one at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.jce.ac.il/en/&#x22;&#x3E;Azrieli College of Engineering&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in Jerusalem, Israel. I hope soon I&#x27;ll be able to teach this (via Zoom) at other institutions as well around the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As part of that course I started to collect information on Open Source projects by governments, corporations, higher education institutions, and non profits. The results so far can be seen &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/open-source-by-organizations/&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However I have another direction with this I&#x27;d like to understand how your workplaces relate to open source. Do they have any formal guidelines on how you can contribute to open source? Informal ones? What happens if you encounter a bug in an open source project you use? Are you allowed to contribute the fix back? On company time? Do they have a budget to support open source contributors who are not employees of the company? e.g. random Jane who works on some open source project? Please get in touch with me if you can share anything.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html">
<title>#608 - Love You Perl!!!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My 6 years old twins reminded me on Sunday morning about Mother&#x27;s Day. Although I didn&#x27;t even know such day existed when I was in India but this country exposed me to all kind of celebrations. I miss my mom a lot. Let me share with you one of my childhood memory. During my school days, everytime somebody complain to my mom about my fight she wouldn&#x27;t listen to my side of story. In fact she would start beating me up infront of the complainant. All my so-called friends knew this and they would blackmail me all the time. My mom would never defend me and believe what others have to say about me. I hated it to the bottom of my heart. This affected my personality and made me an introvert. I have been fighting with my nature all my life, even today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I see the similar treatment to my beloved programming language &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It pains me when I see some &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Gurus&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; never defend the language same like my mom. I expect them to show the bright side of the language to the rest of the world instead, being the language guru. Even a single negative statement about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; would take us one step back and create a bad image. I am fully aware of all the shortcomings but I am not going to go out and tell everyone about it. I would rather find the solutions, if I can. There is nothing wrong to try other programming languages from the job prospective. In fact, I have recently played with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Python&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, thanks to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; but &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; remains my first choice of programming language.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know I don&#x27;t blog regularly any more but I have done it in the past every time I have done something nice using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You can find some of them &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar&#x22;&#x3E;bpo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I know there are many &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans out there doing their bits to dust off the negative image. Honestly speaking, we need more people to come forward. For example, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has been running dedicated website, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he showcase the cool features of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have seen some of the brightest brain creating magic using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; every week when it comes to solving the weekly challenge. The best part is that they even share the code with others on various platforms like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Mother&#x27;s Day&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to all the moms out there, including mine who is in India right now. I love you mom. I would like to apologise to all the readers of the newsletter about the last week incident when I couldn&#x27;t get my contributions to the newsletter available on time. I will try to be more organised in future, promise.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/607.html">
<title>#607 - The Perl Planetarium</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/607.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the previous newsletter Mohammad included a blog post of Dave Cross about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.theplanetarium.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Planetarium&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but I think it is worth another highlighting. It is an excellent way to follow what&#x27;s going on in and around Perl on a daily basis. Now also including commits to the source code of Perl and questions on Stack overflow. I&#x27;ve also opened two issues asking Dave to allow the user to filter the messages based on source and to color-code the sources. Something one of you could implement in the front-end.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A couple of days ago I saw &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/curtis.poe/posts/pfbid02TKsTS9KQi9TbW7hH2gmUNwm1dDJ387TquNkiUR5CCj3kfdmQM9C7RkHXusmUHN2Jl&#x22;&#x3E;a post on Facebook&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Curtis Ovid Poe and then &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers/posts/6296612980371437/&#x22;&#x3E;Will Braswell reposted it&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The rant was on why Perl is dying. Basically Ovid says that Perl lags behind the more popular languages adopting new features. Including features that were available to some other languages 10-20-40 years ago. Predictably some people jumped on blaming the Perl 6 effort. Others pointed out the lack of volunteers. The lack of outreach. The missing modules from the standard libraries.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some very interesting comment, but you might need to be Facebook account to be able to read them. Sorry for that.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;While preparing a blog post I searched GitHub for repositories written in Perl and then it gave me the idea to check out the other languages and got this table on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/the-most-popular-programming-languages-on-github-2i6b&#x22;&#x3E;The most popular programming languages on GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I posted the link to the Perl programmers group on Facebook. They did not like the numbers.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Here is an idea to make GitHub better for Perl projects: The dependabot helps developers keep their dependencies up-to-date. As far as I can tell it does &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://docs.github.com/en/code-security/dependabot/dependabot-version-updates/configuration-options-for-the-dependabot.yml-file#package-ecosystem&#x22;&#x3E;not support Perl.&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. However, it&#x27;s &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/dependabot/&#x22;&#x3E;source code is on GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E; so interested parties could probaly add this support. Let me know when it becomes available so I can try it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/606.html">
<title>#606 - First Love Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/606.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you remember the first programming language you picked up?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure in the life span of a programmer, one picks more than one programming language but still have special place for one. I remember during my first encounter in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1993&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I was introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COBOL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as part of the course I joined immediately after getting through &#x3C;strong&#x3E;12th or (+2 as some remember)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I had only access to PC at the institute and that too 2 times a week for one hour each. Imagine relying on books and nothing else, I was attracted towards many other programming languages. During that period, I picked up &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Fortran&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as well and I loved it more than &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COBOL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. When I got bored of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Fortran&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I went to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Pascal&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. That too didn&#x27;t last long before I moved to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;C&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I stayed with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;C&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; longer than any of the programming languages I picked before. I remember when I moved to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mumbai&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for a better opportunity in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1997&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I hardly got any offer so I took a part-time job to build a desktop application for a small factory using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FoxPRO&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was during this period, I got the offer to join a startup looking for fresher willing to learn &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was my first proper job as a programmer. Infact, I was given two choices, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Java&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I choose &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as it was easier to move from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;C&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. And here I am today, in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, working as a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Developer&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Reason I am sharing my story is last week I came across some post on social media talking about (again) &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is dead or not moving fast enough to keep up with the younger generations. I don&#x27;t want to repeat what is said in favour or against &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but it pains to see not many coming forward to stop the lies. I remember when &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was released, it made a big impact and everyone started talking about it. I even did daily series on the new features of latest release. I have kept it recorded in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for anyone to have a look. In few months time, there is going to be another big release that every &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans are looking forward to it. So to all ignorants and haters, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is not going anywhere and will remain stronger as ever.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Just for fun, I asked &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ChatGPT&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; his views on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I must say it didn&#x27;t dissappoint me. It tried to be polite and diplomatic in his response. I liked it. Please don&#x27;t get me wrong, I don&#x27;t live in the fantasy world. I know the fact, we don&#x27;t have many new projects being developed in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. So what? That doesn&#x27;t make it any lesser than others. You can try other while still in love with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am not suggesting you do but if you do then there is nothing wrong in it. I know many experts in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; equally good in many other languages. You can find them doing &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;weekly challenges&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in so many different languages.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The moral of the story, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; will remain my first love no matter what. How about you, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Enlightened Perl Organisation (EPO)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is closing down, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mark Keating&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; made it public the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ww2.enlightenedperl.org/2023/02/27/closing-down&#x22;&#x3E;sad news&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I would like to take this opportunity to thank &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mark Keating&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his entire team for all the hard work and support, specially to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Please enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/605.html">
<title>#605 - Trying to save a disappearing language</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/605.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In 1492 the Jews were &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/the-spanish-expulsion-1492&#x22;&#x3E;expelled from Spain&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and 4 years later also from Portugal. Many of those Jews settled in the Ottoman Empire and kept talking and changing their language. This is what created the language we call &#x27;Judeo-Espanyol&#x27; or in its modern name &#x27;Ladino&#x27;. For 500 years these people kept speaking and improving their language which is now a mix of medieval Spanish, Portuguese, Catalan, Turkish, Greek, Italian, Hebrew, Arabic, and probably a few other languages. These Jews are usually referred to as the &#x27;Sephardic&#x27; Jews because &#x27;Sepharad&#x27; means Spain in Hebrew. It was originally written using old Hebrew letters called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rashi_script&#x22;&#x3E;Rashi&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solitreo&#x22;&#x3E;Solitreo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but in the last 100 years or so it was switched to Latin letters.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Unfortunately due to various reasons (The modernization of Turkey by Atat&#xFC;rk, the Holocaust, emigration to USA, Israel and elsewhere) the majority of remaining Ladino speakers switched to the local language and today there are only a few ten thousands of native Ladino speakers, most of them above 60.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There are various grass-root projects to revitalize the language. One of them is called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://kantoniko.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Kantoniko&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is a multi-lingual dictionary with sample sentences, audio, poster etc. There are also experiments to use the material for educational purposes for people who would like to learn Ladino. The project has some Open Source code written in Python and JavaScript. There is also a lot of data under various Creative-Commons licenses.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know Python is not your cup of tea, but the whole project might be interesting to some of you and might take a look at it. I recorded a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLw7UYp3N0eUYt8ARGB4DbNffB4MPROFDY&#x22;&#x3E;series of videos in English&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about the site and how to contribute to it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/604.html">
<title>#604 - P in LAMP?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/604.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Depending who you ask the question, you might get different answer. As I am native &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; speaker, I would say it stands for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I first came to know about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LAMP&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1999&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; when I was first introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although the term was first coined by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Michael Kunze&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1998&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. During that time, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;PHP&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; were the only two contenders. Many years later, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Python&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; joined the gang. That makes it good fun discussion on what &#x3C;strong&#x3E;P&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; stands for in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LAMP&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Those days, Web Development was mostly around &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and good old friend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CGI&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Things have changed for good in all these years. We now have plenty of choices to pick from, like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Catalyst&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mojolicious&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dancer2&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; etc etc. Most of my time with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; spent on Web Development. At one place, we had inhouse Web Framework, which worked like a charm but recently when I moved to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oleeo.com&#x22;&#x3E;Oleeo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I got the opportunity to work with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Catalyst&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am a big fan of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dancer2&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, so getting on with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Catalyst&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was a little difficult. Having said, I did find some similarities between the two.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Going back to the topic, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LAMP&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I remember a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dzone.com/articles/lamp-is-dead-long-live-perl-web-frameworks&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on the same subject going into fine details and variations. It was fun read.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also came across this question, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://askubuntu.com/questions/736203/why-perl-is-included-into-lamp-server&#x22;&#x3E;Why Perl is included into lamp-server?&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I loved the reply to the question. I never thought about it before. Last but not the least, I let you explore this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/6446385/what-is-the-significance-of-the-p-in-lamp-why-is-it-php-perl-or-python&#x22;&#x3E;Stackoverflow Q&#x26;A&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on the similar topic.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My twins always say &#x22;My dad is the best&#x22;, so I borrow their pet statement and say &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Perl is the best language ever&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. So go on and play with it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and please keep supporting us as always.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html">
<title>#603 - Generating prejudice</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure most of you reading this newsletter have heard that &#x22;perl is unreadable&#x22; or &#x22;perl is a write only language&#x22;, or maybe that &#x22;perl is dead&#x22;. In many cases this comes from people who have never actually saw perl. You might have not named this phenomenon, but this is called prejudice.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prejudice&#x22;&#x3E;Prejudice&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is having (usually negative) opinion about an individual, a group of people, or a thing, with partial or no real knowledge about the subject. It&#x27;s name is quite clear. It is having a judgement before (pre) having knowledge.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One can see prejudice as a phenomenon that happens naturally, but it can also be manufactured and used for personal, economic, or political gains. We saw that happening in the last 25 years with Perl. I saw a number of very interesting, though painful cases.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Prejudice against Perl clearly has way less personal consequences than other forms of prejudice, but maybe because of that it is easier to discuss it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In one case, a few years ago, someone explained to me that he writes both in Perl and in Python. When he writes in Perl he does not care about indentation or good programming practices as Perl works that way as well. Then he continued explaining that Perl is unreadable. He did not seem to realize the absurdity that the cause and effect relationship might not be of language-&#x26;gt;readability, but rather effort-to-write-clean-code-&#x26;gt;readability.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I often hear people writing in Perl talking about the code being unmaintainable. It is a type of internalized prejudice when you could know otherwise, but because of the social pressure of viewing the negative aspects one will adopts, repeats, and thus strengthens the prejudice. &#x22;If even Perl developers say so then it must be true.&#x22;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Once, more than 10 years ago, when &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/fosdem-2011-and-perl.html&#x22;&#x3E;I was at FOSDEM&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I talked to someone at the pre-conference beer drinking party. She explained that at their company they would not consider hiring anyone who had ever written in Perl. - Clearly a very stupid idea as there are some brilliant Perl programmers. However, this is where prejudice leads to. It does not only hurt the Perl developers, it also hurts the people having the prejudice.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;How is prejudice manufactured?&#x3C;/b&#x3E; One key aspect of creating and then increasing this prejudice against Perl and even against people who wrote in Perl was the repetition of lies that are now accepted as &#x22;facts&#x22;. Another aspect was that saying bad things about Perl seemed like a requirement to be accepted in the Python community. It certainly helped some people who moved from Perl to Python to &#x22;be forgiven&#x22;. I remember when I first started to write in Python and go to Python events, there was a some pressure to distance myself from my &#x22;sinful past&#x22; writing Perl. So far I managed no to cave in and so I still receive such demands once in a while.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;How to fight prejudice?&#x3C;/b&#x3E; There are many articles about this topic, I am sure it will be interesting to read some of them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;hr&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;That&#x27;s it for this weeks rant.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the meantime I continue running two instances of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. One in Hebrew for a mix of biologists and programmers. Some of whom are students and some with work experience. The other one is in English with extra focus on Perl. I hope that the participants in this course will soon start opening issues and sending Pull-Requests to various CPAN modules.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html">
<title>#602 - RIP Ben Davies</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I got the sad news about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ben Davies&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; through the git notifications, being member Raku github repositories. Although I didn&#x27;t know him personally but I felt a personal loss. He was so young and actively involved in development of Raku language. I found &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.tributearchive.com/obituaries/27062822/benjamin-nelson-davies&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; sharing the details, if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It reminded of loss another very dear friend of mine, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rakudoweekly.blog/2020/03/16/2020-11-farewell-good-friend&#x22;&#x3E;Jeff Goff (aka DrForr)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had the honour to meet him at various Perl/Raku conferences. Life is so unpredictable, it is unbelievable. I have reached a point in my life where every little things create havoc as far as health is concerned.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about heartbroken news, I would like to bring the subject raised by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the last edition of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/601.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. At times, I wonder how can one be so disrespectful to others. I was really sad to hear what &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; had to go through. Honestly speaking, I only came to know about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.holocaustremembrance.com/resources/working-definitions-charters/working-definition-antisemitism&#x22;&#x3E;Antisemitism&#x3C;/a&#x3E; when I moved to England in 2000. During my college days, I never had interest in subject outside of domain of India. Although I was aware of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;love/hate&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; relationship between Muslims and Jews, I never bothered looking into the history behind it. Muslim community in general in India is more sympathetic towards fellow muslims. Some may find, my relationship with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; strange. Again, I must confess that I wasn&#x27;t aware about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; background when I first met him when he took my interview in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2016&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I only found out later about him being a Jewish when I had further interactions with him with regard to CPAN works. He has been my mentor ever since I first met him and has helped me every time I was in trouble. For me, religion is very personal thing and I like to keep it private. Having said, I don&#x27;t hide the fact that I am a practicing Muslim.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I urge everyone, please be kind to each other and spread love. Life is too short, so enjoy every moment of it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>