<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html">
<title>#562 - Perl Conference</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish all the readers of the weekly newsletter, a very &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Idd&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. We are celebrating Idd today in England and luckily it is a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bank Holiday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as well.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have seen Facebook post about the upcoming &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlconference.us/tprc-2022-hou&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2022, Houston, TX&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. With this, I kept wonderung why not have &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; too? Being member of the LPW organising team, I discussed it with fellow member, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Good news is he seems positive about it as well. I don&#x27;t know whether we have enough time to kickstart the process. Just hoping we get the opportunity to organise the conference. It has been a long time since we last had the gatherings in London. We had German Perl Workshop organised successfully only recently. Although I didn&#x27;t see a single event report published by attending members unfortunately. I remember last time when I attended the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, there were plenty of post event reports published as per the tradition.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-05-02T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html">
<title>#561 - Switching to Sendgrid</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have just switched from using Mailman to Sendgrid to distribute the Perl Weekly. I hope this will improve the delivery rate. I was wondering what system should I use to maintain the list of registered people and got to the conclusion that, at least for the time being, I&#x27;ll use a flat file and I&#x27;ll manually maintain it. We&#x27;ll see how that works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In other news, my son started his own start-up company. He and his partner are building a tool for private investors so instead of chasing data sources they can spend more of their time on the decision making process. It would be nice of you if you checked out their site called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://torto.ai/welcome?utm_source=perlweekly&#x26;utm_medium=email&#x26;utm_campaign=perlweeklyintro&#x22;&#x3E;torto.ai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If would give a huge boost to them and would help them find investors if you also subscribed to their system. You could also use the code &#x3C;b&#x3E;perlweeklyApr20&#x3C;/b&#x3E; until 1st of May which gives 20% off.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html">
<title>#560 - Perl Rocks</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Here in England, two long weeks of school holidays are ending for us today. It is Monday bank holiday in England today. From tomorrow, we are back to the school run in the morning and afternoon, whilst fasting during the day as Ramadan is going on.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let&#x27;s enjoy the last day of the break and not worry about anything else.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the last one week or so, I have been sharing Perl sample code in posts on various social media platforms, like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Programmers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadanwar/&#x22;&#x3E;LinkedIn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has generated lots of buzz on the subject. Lots of new ideas, at least to me, came to the fore.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For those who missed it, let me share some of them here:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;ul&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1196449164496041&#x22;&#x3E;Stacked file test operators&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1197846361022988&#x22;&#x3E;Compare numbers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1195694301238194&#x22;&#x3E;Power of printf()&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1195152567959034&#x22;&#x3E;Size of hash&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1194997197974571&#x22;&#x3E;Handling of conflict markers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1193298991477725&#x22;&#x3E;Substitution operator&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/ul&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have fun with Perl and share your experience with us. Take care of yourself and your loved ones!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html">
<title>#559 - Endangered and dying languages</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;While the population of the world is growing the language-diversity is shrinking. There are many languages that are used less and less. (Wikipedia has &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_endangered_languages&#x22;&#x3E;a list by location&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure as programmers there are plenty of thing we can also do to help. That&#x27;s why I have been investing time in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://librelingo.app/&#x22;&#x3E;LibreLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; project and specifically in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judaeo-Spanish&#x22;&#x3E;Judaeo-Spanish (aka. Ladino, or Judezmo)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Now I can also show you the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://diksionaryo.szabgab.com/&#x22;&#x3E;dictionary&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I have been working on. You can type in words in any of the languages listed there and it will try to find the Ladino word for it. The dictionary is still small. It contains only 3,500 words, but I hope I&#x27;ll be able to enlarge it to help people who would like to learn Ladino.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It was a very slow week and I hardly found any articles to include (besides the Weekly Challenge that Mohammad collects), but there were also new authors. Let me congratulate to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/simbabque/&#x22;&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/scotticles&#x22;&#x3E;Scotticles&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for their first posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html">
<title>#558 - Perl Magic</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish you all a very &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. May &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ALLAH s.w.t.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; bless us all in the holy month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have you seen any Perl code that surprised you recently?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have, only recently, found out that braces become optional when calling a subroutine, depending on when you call the subroutine. If a subroutine is defined before you call it in a script, braces are optional. If you call the subroutine in a script &#x3C;strong&#x3E;before&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; it is defined (which is perfectly acceptable too), then braces are a must.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How about this calling sub add() passing two scalar parameters? &#x3C;strong&#x3E;add my ($x, $y) = (2, 3);&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2022/03/30/making-dynamically-required-package-names-more-discoverable-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where he shares a very interesting use of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x27;::&#x27;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in package names.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html">
<title>#557 - Human languages</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;First of all, let me congratulate &#x3C;b&#x3E;Mohammad S. Anwar&#x3C;/b&#x3E; for editing 100 issues of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you visit the main page of the website you will see a list of all editors, past and present, in the order they joined and with the number of issues they edited. Let me thank all of you!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Learning programming languages is not easy, but if you compare that to learning human languages you&#x27;ll notice that it has a lot more difficulties. Human languages have much bigger vocabulary and much bigger grammar with lots of exceptions. This already makes it much harder to learn on, but in addition it is hard to get fast and cheap feedback. Something you are given by the compiler/interpreter of your language. You can even add more by writing your own tests and setting up a CI system. That&#x27;s part of the value &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.duolingo.com/&#x22;&#x3E;DuoLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; provides. Fast and cheap feedback. However it is proprietary.  &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://librelingo.app/&#x22;&#x3E;LibreLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is an open source alternative to which I started to contribute. The most fun part for me is actually trying to write a course: building a dictionary and writing sample sentences.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html">
<title>#556 - Cucumber &#x26; Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How do you test a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Web API&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using Perl?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure you have most likely used TDD to test your Web API. How about trying something new for a change?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Something like BDD, Behaviour Driven Development. I came across BDD many years ago when my manager introduced the term to the team and gave us a short tutorial using Java. I was completely blown away by the idea itself. I never actually got the opportunity to use BDD in any of the Perl projects I worked in afterwards, unfortunately. Then few years later in 2018, I got the opportunity to attend the talk &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2018/talk/7547&#x22;&#x3E;Behaviour Driven Development and Cucumber&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Martin Berends&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; at the London Perl Workshop. After a quick search, I found a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6IsKr50wAE&#x22;&#x3E;video&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the same talk. If you missed the talk then it is your chance now to watch the talk. If the video is not enough and you are looking for more. I would highly recommend the book &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B084Z6GTKK&#x22;&#x3E;Cucumber &#x26; Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;John Davies&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was published by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlschool.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl School&#x3C;/a&#x3E; publishing house run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are interested in complete tutorial then you should check out this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.cognizantsoftvision.com/blog/how-to-test-web-apis-with-perl-and-cucumber&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Speaking of BDD, I came across the term &#x22;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming (XP)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x22;. TDD has been part of my day job most of the time without realising it being part of XP. I found this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.extremeperl.org/bk/home&#x22;&#x3E;website&#x3C;/a&#x3E; showing &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming using Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You can download the entire book in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.extremeperl.org/f/extremeperl.pdf&#x22;&#x3E;pdf format&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for FREE. If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then take a look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.extremeprogramming.org&#x22;&#x3E;gentle introduction&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;THe last couple of years have been very tough for most of us in the IT sector. Although we all have been adjusted to the new normal of work-from-home culture, it has still left some scars behind. Mental health is one such issue being discussed more frequently during this period. I have found a way to keep my mind busy when needed; reading books (mostly non-technical). Recently I found the quote &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Lately my peace has been more important than proving my point.&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on web that express my current mental state. How do you deal with your WFH blues?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, I have finally reached the 3 digits figure i.e. my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. It took me nearly &#x3C;strong&#x3E;3 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to get this far. I would like to take this opportunity to thank each and every readers of the weekly newsletter for the kind words and appreciations. I would also like to thank, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for being my guide and mentor, all these years.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter, stay safe and pray for world peace.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html">
<title>#555 - Holidays</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/555.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am in Hungary now where where there is a 4-days Holiday around the 15th March - the Hungarian version of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolutions_of_1848&#x22;&#x3E;Springtime of Nations revolutions&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Then I&#x27;ll have another 2 days off as my client in Israel celebrates &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purim&#x22;&#x3E;Purim&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I use these free days to work on an open source platform for word-games. It is not ready yet to show the world, but it is already in a condition where people can contribute to it. The first game needs lots of words in various languages. I already started to do versions in English, Hungarian, Hebrew, and Ladino and I already had a contributor with French and German, but I am looking for more people who might be interested in contributing in other languages. Let me know and I can show you the game. I hope that two weeks from now, when I am editing the next issue of the Perl Weekly I&#x27;ll be able to link to the game. (the game is only front-end code now so there is no Perl in it. Sorry.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html">
<title>#554 - Exceptions in Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/554.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I borrowed the title from Curtis&#x27; recently shared &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/Ovid/5205534f7dcc52e4d931aaff301b39aa&#x22;&#x3E;gist&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure every one of us have dealt with exceptions in Perl. Being a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; fan, I found plenty of choices readily available. I am a big fan of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/Try-Tiny&#x22;&#x3E;Try::Tiny&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and it has always been my first choice to deal with exceptions in Perl. I suggest you must check out the gist for more insights and suggestions shared by Curtis.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would also like to share another gem by Curtis, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki/Porting-from-Moose-or-Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Porting from Moose or Moo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is a big help for anyone to move to Corinna from Moose or Moo. Most of my personal work shared on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/MANWAR&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; used Moo. The document by Curtis would be handy when porting to Corinna once it is part of core Perl. I am eagerly waiting for it to happen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;99th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. In two weeks time, I would be presenting the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I joined the team of editors in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;May 2018&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, thanks to the chief editor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, for all the support and guidance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and pray for the world peace.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html">
<title>#553 - Looking for a copy-editor for the Perl Weekly</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/553.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago some people asked me not to include politics in the Perl weekly so I won&#x27;t add my opinion on the murderous Russian dictator, but I would like to wish the best to all the people and their families I met while I was at the Perl conference in Kyiv, Ukraine 10 years ago.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Since Dave Cross got fed up with our broken English and started to copy-edit the Perl Weekly we became a bit spoiled by having him. Unfortunately (to us) he got himself busy with some real work and won&#x27;t be able to allocate the time for copy-editing the Perl Weekly. So now we are looking for a volunteer to do it. Basically every Monday, sometimes during the European morning hours (we don&#x27;t have a fixed timing), we push out a version to our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;web-site&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Then I&#x27;d send an email to the copy-editor who checks the most recent version and sends a Pull-Request on GitHub with the fixes. Once I get the PR, I merge it, regenerate the HTML and send out the newsletter. If you would be interested to volunteer, please get in touch with me so I know whom to notify.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-02-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>