<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2024, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/651.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/650.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/649.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/648.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/647.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/646.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/645.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html">
<title>#654 - Perl and FOSDEM</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/654.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Did you know FOSDEM happened last week?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;FOSDEM&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, Free and Open source Software Developers&#x27; European Meeting, is still a mystery for me. Few years ago a fellow member of LPW organising team introduced me to FOSDEM for the first time. Ever since, I always wanted to attend at least once just to experience the gatherings. I found out familiar faces attending this year FOSDEM like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Evans&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Salve J. Nilsen&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although the location wasn&#x27;t far from my place but timing wasn&#x27;t ideal. I wish I was mentally prepared to attend this year FOSDEM. I even saw a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/vanhoesel/2024/02/fosdem-2024-tprf-community-dinner.html&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Theo van Hoesel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with regard to TPRF sponsored Dinner at FOSDEM. It would have been a great opportunity to meet good old friends. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared the live video link from the event. I was able to watch the fun luckily thanks to the organiser. I am hoping the video recordings of the event would be made public soon. Here is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://archive.fosdem.org/2021/schedule/track/perl_and_raku_programming&#x22;&#x3E;schedule&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Perl and Raku Programming devroom.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you tried ChatGPT?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have and I find it fun playing with it. Recently I asked &#x22;How do I check if memcached server is running locally and listening to default port?&#x22;. Like always, I got instant response with few lines of Perl to get the desired result. Guess what, it didn&#x27;t do what I asked it to do. I went back and asked again. This time, I got another variation. I tried that too but no luck. By now, I was too tired to repeat the question. I then used CPAN module &#x3C;strong&#x3E;IO::Socket::INET&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to see if I can create socket. I know it is not ideal but does the job. Time to move on to next thing in the long &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TODO&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; list.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Does a programmer need to know system admin task also?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been a programmer and only programmer all my life. I remember in the past, I was sent to a week long training to learn sysadmin tasks. It was fresh for a week after the training then I was back to my programmer life. I did enjoy the training and learnt few tricks. As some of you know about my CPAN module, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Map::Tube&#x22;&#x3E;Map::Tube&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I published in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2010&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I decided to create &#x3C;strong&#x3E;REST API&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; interface to play with it. Luckily I had another CPAN module, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Map::Tube::Server&#x22;&#x3E;Map::Tube::Server&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. With this, I was able to setup the server in no time on my local box. Now comes the difficult task, create service to manage the server. Being a programmer doesn&#x27;t help the cause, also when your box is running &#x3C;strong&#x3E;WSL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and not real linux. With the limitation of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;WSL&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I had only one option to create service based on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;init.d&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It wasn&#x27;t hard to create service file for the map server. I could even use the service to start the server but termination didn&#x27;t work for some strange reason. I didn&#x27;t have the energy to ask &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ChatGPT&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for help. It has to wait for now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am thinking of writing a blog post about the whole process, if I can find spare moment.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter and do share your Perl story with us.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-02-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html">
<title>#653 - Perl &#x26; Raku Conference 2024 to Host a Science Track!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/653.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are monitoring the number of subscribers of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that we have on the front page, you can see that it dropped by more than 70 today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;That&#x27;s because after a long period of time I went through the bounce-reports of Sendgrid, the provider I use to send the messages. There were many  reporting &#x3C;b&#x3E;No such user&#x3C;/b&#x3E; or that &#x3C;b&#x3E;the email account that you tried to reach is over quota and inactive.&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. I know I missed some and more will appear in the list next week, but it was enough for today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;BTW, we store the historical data in the src/count.txt file in our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly&#x22;&#x3E;repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If I am not mistaken it peaked on week 370-371 with 6,449 subscribers. Now we are down to 4,523 that we had between the weeks 113-114.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html">
<title>#652 - Perl and TPF</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/652.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;string&#x3E;Is it TPF or TPRF?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking at the official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org&#x22;&#x3E;news page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, it still says &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation News&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have no issue how you call it whether &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The most important bit is the work they do to promote &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; programming languages. There was a big news recently as we had the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/presidentslettert2024&#x22;&#x3E;Letter from the President&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We don&#x27;t very often hear from the President. I was curious to find out what is special this time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would like to talk about two things, one the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2024 Prospectus&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and second about new board members. Honestly, I never knew about the prospectus. I will be watching when it gets published more likely ahead of the annual conference in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the month of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;June 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. With regard to the new members, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bruce Gray&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ruth Holloway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would like to congratulate both of them. I am confident they are going to be a big help to present the wider audience point of views. It is a proud moment for me as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bruce Gray&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is one of the most active and regular members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;OK, tell me how many of you watched the live release of Perl v5.39.7?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To be honest with you, I wasn&#x27;t aware of such live streaming of Perl release. Thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for this information in the last edition of the newsletter. For me, it was perfect timing, first thing on Saturday morning. I was a mute spectator, just watching the release flow. Some of the things just went above my head but few things I could follow. It was fun though. I would definitely watch the live streaming if it happens again. Just out of curiosity, I asked one question in the end about release ETA of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I got the response that in the next &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2-3 months&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. That made me really happy as I am eagerly waiting for the next big release. Looking forward to more features to the newly added OO ecosystem.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you use GitHub Actions?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was fortunate to attend the talk on the subject by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; at the Perl Conference in Toronto last summer. It is really cool thing to have if you have codebase in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I would highly recommend you checkout his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2024/01/github-actions-for-perl-development&#x22;&#x3E;latest post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he shared the details.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Are you enjoying the cold days and nights of January?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally, I just hate it as my body doesn&#x27;t like extreme condition either cold or hot. I know I came from a place in India where &#x3C;strong&#x3E;50 degree celcius&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was normal during summer. Not anymore unfortunately, may be I am getting old now. I just want &#x3C;strong&#x3E;January&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to get over asap as in this month we hardly get any sun where I live.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a safe and fun week ahead.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/651.html">
<title>#651 - Watch the release of Perl live!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/651.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a long period of time, finally I see a live online event about Perl that&#x27;s worth following. Max Maischein will &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/max_maischein/2024/01/live-streaming-the-release-of-perl-5397.html&#x22;&#x3E;Live stream the release of Perl 5.39.7&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Even if you are not a core Perl developer and are not interesting in becoming one, I think it is an event worthy to follow. It is in the morning hours of Europe so it seems to be more relevant to people in Europe, Africa and the East, including New Zealand.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Am I the only one bothered by The Perl Foundation publishing a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/congo_hackathon&#x22;&#x3E;grant request&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that looks suspicious, to say it mildly? Are they legally required to publish anything that has the word &#x27;Perl&#x27; in it even if the person submitting it has no track record with Perl and the Perl community? Do they really believe that a person who has never contributed to Perl from a place that has not seen any Perl contribution will out of the blue run a Perl Hackathon? Or is this a political agenda?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Speaking of sponsorship. In the last few years the Perl Weekly had some income from job ads. Unfortunately that ended in December. I used to use some of the money to sponsor Mohammad, but unfortunately I had to stop that. So I&#x27;d like to ask you to step up, open your purse, and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar/&#x22;&#x3E;support Mohammad&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. He is running &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and about 3/4 of the Perl Weekly. I think it would be important to make him feel appreciated and valued in this way as well.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;And as for me, I keep &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rust.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;writing about Rust&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I just bought a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://microbit.org/&#x22;&#x3E;micro:bit&#x3C;/a&#x3E; thingy to experiment a bit with light-weight embedded programming.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/650.html">
<title>#650 - Perl in 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/650.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What is in for Perl in 2024?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We had a big release &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; last year, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;July 3, 2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was the first release introducing &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; into core. Although it was good enough for starter but I am looking for another push in the next release in the year 2024. I am sure you must have tried the new OO in core. One thing that I really wanted was the ability to create a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;role&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using new shiny OO. I have no idea what is in the plan for the next release. I am looking forward to another update to the new OO ecosystem.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally, I am also looking forward to the next &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl and Raku Conference in Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I had a wonderful experience last year in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Canada&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope things get back to normal before the event. I don&#x27;t know about the conference in Europe. I missed it last year as it clashed with my India visit. It used to be my only opportunity to meet fellow &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; friends. I miss the local event, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope it gets fresh boost this year.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My pet project, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; recently completed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;250 weeks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It has been a great learning experience for me personally. I was introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Python&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Thanks to the team members we get regular blog posts talking about magical &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; code. Talking about blog post, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, invites us to join the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://wundersolutions-com.eo.page/k22w4&#x22;&#x3E;newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have accepted his invitation. How about you?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Stay safe and enjoy rest of the week.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/649.html">
<title>#649 - Happier New Year!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/649.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not big on New Year celebrations so I went to sleep at 11 pm to be ready today as the first action of the new year to prepare and send out the Perl Weekly Newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We were woken up at midnight by the air-raid sirens (now apparently called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civil_defense_siren&#x22;&#x3E;civil defense sirens&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, not to be confused with the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siren_(mythology)&#x22;&#x3E;mythological sirens&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.) The Palestinians were shooting rockets at us reminding us that it is still more important for them to try to kill us than to protect and feed their own children. What they certainly don&#x27;t need to remind us is that there are still &#x3C;b&#x3E;more than 100 Israelis kidnapped in Gaza&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. Among them children, young women, and elderly people.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know some people on this list don&#x27;t like when I write about &#x27;politics&#x27; and even write me emails complaining. Our soldiers, some of whom are fellow hi-tech employees, are literally sacrificing their life in order to protect me, protect us. I think I have the moral duty to use every platform I have to remind people we have this war to bring the kidnapped home and to end the constant rocket fire on our borders. I also feel strongly that I need to thank the people who put themselves in grave danger to allow us to live a normal life. Frankly, I don&#x27;t know how can I ever repay them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some other readers complain about Mohammad using religious references. Well, each one and his &#x27;flaws&#x27;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To everyone else, let me use a Perlish expression, (finally some Perl content in this editorial!) &#x3C;b&#x3E;bless $you;&#x3C;/b&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish by the end of 2024 we will be able to say that it was a much better year than 2023!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your year!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-01-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/648.html">
<title>#648 - Merry Christmas</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/648.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Merry Christmas everyone !!!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This is my last edition of the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Normally it is the time when I look back and recap of my achievements. During my peak, I used to share monthly update and in the end annual report. My last monthly report was &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar/2021/12/monthly-report---november-3.html&#x22;&#x3E;Nov 2021&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and last annual report was &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar/2022/01/annual-report---2021.html&#x22;&#x3E;Year 2021&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Reading back, it seems I had so much time and energy. One thing, however, did stay with me is my pet project, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Is there anything to remember year 2023?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was one high and one low moment for me. Both happened within weeks of each other. It happened when I was at my lowest for a long time. The low moment was when I lost my dad and couldn&#x27;t attend the last moments. It wasn&#x27;t the only low moment in the year 2023. I lost my Mom too yesterday after a long illness. I just want &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to get over ASAP. The high moment was when I received &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://whitecamel.org/p/mohammad_sajid_anwar.html&#x22;&#x3E;2022 White Camel Award&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Also for the first time, I got the opportunity to attend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. By the way, we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/whitecamel2023&#x22;&#x3E;2023 White Camel Award&#x3C;/a&#x3E; declared now. Heartiest congratulations to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;R Geoffrey Avery&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, a well deserved member of the community.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do I have plans for year 2024?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I stopped plannings for future as when it doesn&#x27;t happen then I feel low and it takes time to recover from it. I rather deal each day as it comes. I hope and wish it would bring in fresh energy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Talking about events in 2023 that has bothered me?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, I am not a person who shares his view on social platforms for a reason. I must admit I am not strong enough to deal with responses, positive or negative. This is the reason, I don&#x27;t share my views with regard to the recent global conflict. Although, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; never hides his view as it is very evident from his post on various social platforms. I must give credit to him. I remember a sweet moment from the past when I released &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/Calendar-Hebrew&#x22;&#x3E;Calendar::Hebrew&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;23rd July 2017&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I wrote a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar/2017/07/1000th-consecutive-days-releasing-to-cpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;1000th consecutive days releasing to CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I received few comments to my post too. However, there was one from none other than the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Larry Wall&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; himself as below.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Allow me to also say- and this probably reflects my own limited world experience as much as anything else- how gratifying I find it to see someone named Muhammad release Calendar::Hebrew. Truly you help make this world a better place!&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have known &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; from his contributions to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. He has been supporting me on personal and professional front for a long time. He makes me feel so comfortable to talk about anything under the sky. I always go for his guidance every time I am stuck. I didn&#x27;t know about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; link to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Israel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; initially. For some it may sound strange relationship between two person with opposing religious background. I don&#x27;t talk about 2 things in public, one is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Politics&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and other is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Religion&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. That doesn&#x27;t mean, I don&#x27;t have a view. I do but I don&#x27;t share on public platform. Having said, I do talk about them in private though.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the break and have fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-12-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/647.html">
<title>#647 - Happy birthday Perl! &#x1F382;</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/647.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the birthday of Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you don&#x27;t have an advent calendar just go around the kitchen randomly opening doors and see if there is anything edible... Luckily you can pick from several calendars&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2023/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; continues and now there are the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://advent.perldancer.org/2023&#x22;&#x3E;The Twelve Days of Dancer&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as well&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-12-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/646.html">
<title>#646 - Festive Season</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/646.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is normally the busiest month of the year as we get to participate in two events i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://24pullrequests.com&#x22;&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for many programming languages e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2023&#x22;&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://raku-advent.blog&#x22;&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2023&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. As mentioned in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/641.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, there is an aggregation of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://lenjaffe.com/AdventPlanet&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Calendars&#x3C;/a&#x3E; managed by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Len Jaffe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/644.html&#x22;&#x3E;last edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of newsletter, I requested for sponsor. To my surprise, I have had few offers came through. It is still early stage of discussion. I am hopefull something positive will come out of it. I am keeping fingers crossed.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you contributed to Perl Advent Calendar 2023?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If not then you should and share your real life experience with Perl. You can find the details on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/perladvent/Perl-Advent&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I missed the deadline last year but this year I really didn&#x27;t want to miss the train. Luckily, thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and team, my contribution got accepted and merged. It is now allocated &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2023/2023-12-10.html&#x22;&#x3E;Day 10&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in the calendar.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the fesive season and look after yourself.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-12-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/645.html">
<title>#645 - Advent Calendars</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/645.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Welcome to the new subscribers!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;December has arrived and with it the season of the Advent Calendars. You might recall that Len Jaffe has an Advent Calendar aggregator called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://lenjaffe.com/AdventPlanet/&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Planet&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you know a running calendar that is not listed there, please contact Len!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It lists the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2023/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://raku-advent.blog/2023/&#x22;&#x3E;Raku advent calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, and a few more. Ingy dot Net pointed to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://yamlscript.org/posts/advent-2023/index/&#x22;&#x3E;YAML Script Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the previous edition Mohammad sent a call to get sponsor for his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Weekly programming challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Several people replied to me. Those messages were forwarded to Mohammad as that is his gig. However, I noticed that the link we used to have at the top of the Perl Weekly was only showing up on the web site. I added it back. In a nutshell, if you&#x27;d like to spoonsor/financially help the work of Mohammad S Anwar then either contact him or just support him via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;Patreon&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you&#x27;d like to support my work then you can do so either via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/szabgab&#x22;&#x3E;Patreon&#x3C;/a&#x3E; or via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/sponsors/szabgab&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-12-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>