<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2021, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/516.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/515.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/514.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/513.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/512.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/511.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://perlweekly.com/archive/510.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html">
<title>#519 - Crystal conference and course</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am going to give a presentation at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://crystal-lang.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Crystal&#x3C;/a&#x3E; 1.0 &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://crystal-lang.org/conference/&#x22;&#x3E;conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; alongside Yukihiro &#x27;Matz&#x27; Matsumoto and Bruce Perens (just to throw in two names you might be familiar with and to have some honor by association). It is taking place this Thursday. It is my first presentation at an international conference for a long time. Wish me luck!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you cannot make it to the conference, but you are interested in learning Crystal, I am going to start an experimental programming Crystal course via Zoom. You can &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/crystal-course&#x22;&#x3E;get more information and register here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As for Perl, it was a rather quiet week without a lot of posts, but still there is some nice stuff in here&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-07-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html">
<title>#518 - Becoming book author?</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently came across a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://davecross.substack.com/p/the-story-of-ebooks-and-me&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Dave Cross where he shared the story of how he got into publishing ebooks. I highly recommend you read his blog post, I find it inspirational, personally. I always wanted to write a technical book on a subject related to Perl. I have high regard for those who are professional authors e.g. Curtis Poe, brian d foy, Gabor Szabo, Dave Cross and many more. Ever since I started the weekly challenge, I became more involved in writing technical blogs. Soon I realised it is not the same as writing a technical book. But the urge inside me to become an author didn&#x27;t die forever. With Dave&#x27;s recent blog post fanning the idea once again, I became charged one more time but this time I am seriously thinking about it. I have a topic that I wanted to explore for some time. I discussed it with Gabor and Dave and got very positive responses. So it is official I am now working on my first book, soon to be published by Dave Cross. Fingers crossed. Life is so beautiful when you have friends like Gabor and Dave who always encourage and guide you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is another story that I would like to share. Andrew Shitov reached out to me few days ago to ask if I was interested in sharing my Raku story at the upcoming &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://conf.raku.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have accepted his offer and am working on my presentation. I haven&#x27;t submitted my talk yet but will do so soon. Do you have a Raku story to share? If yes, then please do submit your talk before the deadline.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One last story for the week and then I will go away. Many of you know that I have been running the Perl Weekly Challenge for more than 2 years now. It started as a weekly challenge aimed for Perl and Raku community but soon it spread out to other languages. As of today, we now have received contributions in over 50 different languages. Latest addition is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/crystal-binary-palindrom&#x22;&#x3E;Crystal programming language&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by none other than Gabor Szabo himself. A long time ago, someone (I don&#x27;t remember who), suggested that I should register a generic domain instead of perlweeklychallenge.org. I didn&#x27;t waste any time and registered the new domain theweeklychallenge.org. Having registered the new domain, I didn&#x27;t have the courage and expertise to switch over the actively used live site to another domain. I asked about this on Facebook and guess what? Dave Cross came up with step-by-step guide explaining how to do the domain switch. I was still very nervous to take the risk. Then came the final blow with Gabor asking the same question: why don&#x27;t I move domain to a generic domain. To cut a long story short, Gabor and I spent an hour or so yesterday (Sunday afternoon) and got the domain switched over. So we now have new domain the weekly challenge: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;theweeklychallenge.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Thank you Gabor and Dave for all the support and guidance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html">
<title>#517 - Commitment and habit</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Flavio Poletti has just completed one year of blogging. Mohammad S. Anwar has been editing the Perl Weekly for more than three years and running the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for more than two years.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not sure what the secret is, but something about creating a commitment, even if it is an artificial commitment that then you need to stick to. I am sure both of them had times when they thought of sleeping in and not doing the work that day or that week. After all, this is not their paid job, but the commitment kept them going. With time it became easier to do the task and the whole thing became a habit. I wish more people found the strength to do something like this.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/516.html">
<title>#516 - Conference in the Cloud</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/516.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The highlight of last week was the Conference in the Cloud. It gave us the opportunity to meet and greet Perl and Raku fans from across the globe. On top of that, we got loads of quality talks by experts. Before I talk about anything else, let me thank and congratulate all the organisers and volunteers for such a successful event. I am personally impressed with the video quality of the live and recorded talks.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, I find the timing little bit odd as I am in the UK. The day started at 6:30pm British Summer Time, which is not ideal. At the end of a full day at $work, there is hardly any energy left to attend the talks live. But the best part wasthat the recorded talks were available on YouTube immediately. I find it convenient, as I can watch at my own time. Also I can fast-forward if I want to.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Please find below my personal favourites in no particular order.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;1. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fKqxdTbGxYY&#x22;&#x3E;perlimports or &#x22;Where did that symbol come from?&#x22; by Olaf Alders&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;2. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aDUxaBsDcDg&#x22;&#x3E;Local dev setup for a complex app using docker-compose by Thomas Klausner&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;3. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=go7Ru3QQYYs&#x22;&#x3E;Introduction to Perl Data Types by William N. Braswell, Jr.&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;4. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FO5ift28RyE&#x22;&#x3E;Rummaging in the clOOset by Curtis Poe&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;5. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kxMfnk3fQlY&#x22;&#x3E;Life after Perl (and Raku) by Peter Sergeant&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;6. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FlGpiS39NMY&#x22;&#x3E;What&#x27;s new in Perl? by Ricardo Signes&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;7. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kc_bP73xNyM&#x22;&#x3E;Perl&#x27;s Amazing Time Machine by Paul Evans&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;8. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZY8HrAL755M&#x22;&#x3E;Valiant - Heroic validations for Moo and DBIC classes by John Napiorkowski&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;9. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y2_bqfLUHDM&#x22;&#x3E;Our shared vision of Perl by Andrew Solomon&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;10. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=En49kYRDbsg&#x22;&#x3E;Cross-platform native GUIs: {trade,pay}offs, {integra,distribu}tion by Zaki Mughal&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There are plenty more to watch later. You can find the complete list &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/YAPCNA/videos&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and please stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/515.html">
<title>#515 - Events and blog posts</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/515.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;As I can see &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlconference.us/tprc-2021-cloud/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in the cloud&#x3C;/a&#x3E; starts tomorrow. I am a bit confused as don&#x27;t remember a lot of promotion of the event.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some people complain that the content created by the Perl Weekly Challenge has flooded the Perl Weekly Newsletter. I&#x27;d say if there was more Perl content outside of the PWC that we can share then we could consider reducing the amount of space the PWC takes up.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;BTW that reminds me, I think the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/events.html&#x22;&#x3E;events&#x3C;/a&#x3E; page and the events section at the bottom of the newsletter is shrinkig as the event organizers rarely send updates. I guess having these links did not bring them visitors.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/514.html">
<title>#514 - Is OOP bad?</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/514.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;First things first, I am a big fan of OOP in general. However I do agree OOP is not always the best choice. Since Perl promotes the idea of TIMTOWTDI (There&#x27;s more than one way to do it), we have plenty of options to pick from. I have come across many Perl haters in the past complaining about lack of proper OOP support in Perl. With the introduction of postmodern object system for Perl, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Moose&#x22;&#x3E;Moose&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, we finally had structured OOP support. I must confess I prefer &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Moo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which is known as minimalist object orientation.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Fast forward to now, Curtis Poe joined hands with other Perl masters and came up with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki/Corinna-Overview&#x22;&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is proposed to be part of core Perl soon. I can&#x27;t wait for that to happen. I sincerely applaud the efforts of each and every contributor of Corinna. I beleive it will be the best addition to the Perl core in recent times. I am confident it will be the highlight of the future Perl7.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the last week &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/513.html&#x22;&#x3E;edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter, Gabor reminded me that I forgot to celebrate the special &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/512.html&#x22;&#x3E;512th edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. What a shame, I missed the opportunity. I blame my busy routine for the missed opportunity. I am looking forward to my personal 100th edition of the weekly newsletter. This is the 79th edition for the record, not far off from the target.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy to see, the COVID-19 situation in India is getting better. I pray to ALLAH s.w.t for the complete protection from COVID-19. Please look after yourself and your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To all our readers in the UK, enjoy your bank holiday with the weekly newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-05-31T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/513.html">
<title>#513 - Perl 5.34.0 is now available!</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/513.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am disappointed. Mohammad does not like round numbers. He was editing both the 500th edition and the 512th edition and nothing. He did not even blink an eye. I hope he will not forget to celebrate the 1024 edition.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On another note, perl 5.34.0 was released.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not saying it is easy, but I really enjoy the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/live&#x22;&#x3E;live pair programming sessions&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with Mark Gardner, Upasana Shukla, Juan J. Merelo, Erik Hulsmann, Ferenc Erki, Thomas Klausner, Ynon Perek people whom I know from the Perl community and also Shai Berger, Ivett &#xD6;rd&#xF6;g, Rachel Normand, Tally Barak, and Laia Asensio L&#xF3;pez, people I know from other places. One day you might also want to find a partner and try it. It is nice to work with other people who think differently from you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-05-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/512.html">
<title>#512 - Celebration Time</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/512.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Idd to all the readers of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We should try to avoid all the negativity around us and focus on every little success story. I know it is not easy but we shouldn&#x27;t give up without a fight. Nowadays, social media platforms play a vital role in spreading news. So if you do come across any success story please share it with the community. It helps as morale booster.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would like to specially mention two stories this week, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/newcomer-survey-results-actions&#x22;&#x3E;Andrew Solomon&#x27;s survey results and actions taken&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/dean/2021/05/a-perl-community-dashboard.html&#x22;&#x3E;Dean&#x27;s proposed community dashboard&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Kudos to Andrew and Dean for taking the initiative. Keep it up.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-05-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/511.html">
<title>#511 - I am exhausted</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/511.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There have now been more words spent on the improper way TPF in general and CAT in particular handled the abusive behavior than the decade-long harassment and abuse by - let&#x27;s keep to the tradition - Individual 1. Some of the lieutenants of the abuser demand evidence, but this is just a well known tactic for silencing them. As we all know abused and harassed people rarely speak up. Partially because they know the lieutenants will then try to discredit them and they will receive further harassment and abuse. I am not suprised that many people leave their active role in Perl or withdraw from certain parts of the Perl community and I am not surprised that most of them do it silently. After publishing this I fully expect the team will now restart harassing me as well or will just keep spreading lies about me.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This whole &#x27;discussion&#x27; is really exhausting and I can understand that most of the reasonable people will want to keep a distance from it. So let&#x27;s see what positive went on the last week and let me point out two:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The question &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/n5ceq1/anybody_hacking_on_anything_cool_this_week/&#x22;&#x3E;Anybody hacking on anything cool this week?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the answers to it were excellent. This is what we need.  So do this: Write a 5-line entry on that Reddit-post or on &#x3C;a href&#x22;https://dev.to/t/perl&#x22;&#x3E;dev.to&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (or any other visible place) about a cool project you worked on in the last week. Then send the link to me!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/davorg/easier-web-sites-for-cpan-modules-1nn4&#x22;&#x3E;Easier web sites for CPAN modules&#x3C;/a&#x3E; project is another example of Dave Cross moving things forward. If you are a CPAN author, pick one of your modules and set up a website for it using this module. Then send me the link!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-05-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://perlweekly.com/archive/510.html">
<title>#510 - The Perl Community?</title>
<link>http://perlweekly.com/archive/510.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not sure if you have read the recent &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://neilb.org/2021/04/27/perl-communities.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Neil Bowers. I have read it multiple times to understand the subject of the post. I must admit, I had never read such an in depth analysis of the term &#x22;Community&#x22;. As my vocabulary is rather limited, I found it very interesting to read such a long blog post. To me, community is group of like-minded people. When I attended my first London Perl Workshop, I immediately felt part of the community. The organiser and everybody was so accommodating and friendly. It made me come again the following year and I became addicted to it afterwards. I always looked up to the big names of the community everytime I needed some inspiration. Take a look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.org/advocacy/white_camel/&#x22;&#x3E;past recipients&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the White Camel Award, you can get some idea of who&#x27;s who in the community. Unfortunately it hasn&#x27;t been awarded since 2018 for some reason that I am not aware of. I miss the community spirit of attending Perl Conferences. You can never experience that feeling unless you attend one. I hope and wish we get back to attending conferences. Although there has been virtual events in recent times, it can&#x27;t replace real events in my humble opinion. I must give credit to everyone who is keeping the community spirit alive.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is a bank holiday in the UK, so all the British readers of the newsletter, enjoy your break with the newsletter. Rest of the world, start your week with weekly doses of Perl news. Stay safe and healthy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-05-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>