<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/623.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/622.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/621.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/620.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/619.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/618.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html">
<title>#624 - TPRC 2023</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;By the time you read this newsletter, I would be on the flight to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to attend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I hope and wish to meet many experts and learn from their experience.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/622.html&#x22;&#x3E;issue 622&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I mentioned that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is coming soon. Then a week later, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; announced the arrival of latest release in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/623.html&#x22;&#x3E;issue 623&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I was pleasantly surprised by the early release. I would like to take this opportunity and thank all involved in the release. Special mention to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his team for the work on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To me it is one of the most anticipated feature. To me, it is not just another release but a very special one. Therefore I was expecting it to be the talk of the town. Unfortunately I didn&#x27;t come across any such noise. In fact, the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was more discussed on various social platform. I even collected my experiment with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As of today, the latest release is one week old and I finally managed to install it on my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Windows WSL (Ubuntu 20.04)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Plan is to extend the above mentioned repository and record my experiment with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have recorded the installation steps in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/868aeb07ef4b445b55f726b02a79544d&#x22;&#x3E;gist&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For all the German speaking readers, we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blog.perl-academy.de&#x22;&#x3E;blog posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with the regard to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Renee Baecker&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Talking about blog post, we have another &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/corinna-in-the-perl-core.html&#x22;&#x3E;detailed post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by the lead designer of Corinna, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I would also like to mention another name here, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Andrew Shitov&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, mostly known for his work on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, sharing his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://andrewshitov.com/2023/07/06/built-in-classes-in-perl-5-38&#x22;&#x3E;solution&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to the task &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/perl-weekly-challenge-224/#TASK1&#x22;&#x3E;Special Notes&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Week #224&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using the new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;class feature&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Who owns the Camel logo?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well it is long outstanding issue, so much talked about it but unfortunately nothing happened so far. I just hope and wish it gets resolved soon. I came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/thibaultduponchelle/open-letter-to-tim-oreilly-to-free-the-perl-camel-k3i&#x22;&#x3E;Open Letter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault Duponchelle&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/623.html">
<title>#623 - perl v5.38.0 was released</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/623.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Good news. The new version of perl is out, just in time to be included in this edition. See the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2023/07/msg266602.html&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/release/RJBS/perl-5.38.0/view/pod/perldelta.pod&#x22;&#x3E;perldelta&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for changes. If I understand correctly the bigges change by far is the addition of the &#x3C;b&#x3E;class&#x3C;/b&#x3E; keyword. There are also a number of deprecations you will want to pay attention to. If you&#x27;d like to take it for a ride you can find the instruction &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.cpan.org/src/README.html&#x22;&#x3E;how to install perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. You can also use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlbrew.pl/&#x22;&#x3E;perlbrew&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to install it. I hope we&#x27;ll soon have a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://strawberryperl.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Strawberry Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; release as well.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week I asked two questions on various forums:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If someone asks you why contribute to open source? What do you say?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you don&#x27;t contribute to any open source project, what stops you from contributing?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;ve collected some of the responses at the bottom of the page: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/why-contribute-to-open-source&#x22;&#x3E;Why contribute to open source&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As Mohammad already mentioned last week, I&#x27;ve set up a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://zulip.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Zulip&#x3C;/a&#x3E;-based chat server for people who would like to get help on their path to contributing to open source. In this community I we&#x27;ll be able to support contributors in several programming languages. We started with Perl, Python, and Rust. You are &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.zulipchat.com/&#x22;&#x3E;invited&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/622.html">
<title>#622 - Perl v5.38 coming soon ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/622.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally I am back to editing the weekly newsletter. Thank you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for all the supports and kind words. I would also like to thank all the weekly newsletter readers for sending the sweet message. Never thought it would affect me so much, honestly speaking.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Although I am staying away from screen most of the time, I did see lots of activities by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I wish I could help him in his work. If you are interested then you can read about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/community&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and help him on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.zulipchat.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Zulip&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been waiting for the final release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. However I am very happy to see at least we got the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/release/RJBS/perl-5.38.0-RC2&#x22;&#x3E;RC2&#x3C;/a&#x3E; out in public.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you know what is in Perl v5.38?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You can find the details in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/blead/perldelta&#x22;&#x3E;perldelta&#x3C;/a&#x3E; page. For me, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is going to be the highlight of the new release. However I am told not to have high expectations about it in this release. Still, I am excited to at least play with it and have fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I had almost forgot about participating &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.to/tprc-2023-tor/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; because of what I have gone through in the last few weeks and still going on. But the best part is, I have booked everything from air ticket to hotel reservations. Having said, I still have to get the slides ready for the my talk about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you are planning to attend the conference then please do come and see me. I would love to meet as many Perl enthusiasts as I can. I am mostly looking forward to meet the weekly challenge members. I got exactly &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 weeks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; time to get everything sorted before it is too late.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, please do checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2023/06/05/docker-fix-perl-test-failure&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where he shared his encounter with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Docker&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to fix a Perl v5.37 error.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-06-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/621.html">
<title>#621 - OSDC - Open Source Development Club</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/621.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Mohammad even though he kept handling &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, skipped the previous edition of the Perl Weekly because he was attending his father who was in a very bad health condition. A couple of days ago he posted on Facebook that his father passed away. Mohammad, let me send you my condolences and my hugs here, through the Perl Weekly as well!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;OSDC: As you might know I have been using this acronym for a while to stand for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but I have already seen it used where the C stood for Conference (I even organized one of those), and where the C stood for Club. The goal in all of these cases is to Contribute to open source. (another potential for the letter C).&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently joined a club, well, it is basically a Discord server, where Israeli developers help each other get involved in open source. The basic idea is very similar to what I have been talking about for years now: One of the ways for newbies (or juniors) to gain experience and increase their chances to find a job is to work on open source projects. I am really glad that someone created it. There are already more than 600 members. In this group the main conversation language is Hebrew so if you can read and write in Hebrew and if you are interested to join let me know and I&#x27;ll send you the invite link.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would be also very interested to know if there are other, similar local groups using their own local language elsewhere and if you are familiar with other such clubs that are maybe focused on a specific programming language or maybe a specific project? Links are welcome to my email address!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-06-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/620.html">
<title>#620 - Abandoned modules?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/620.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Mohammad asked me to the edition this week as well, so now you are stuck with me. Again :)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week I wrote about my offer to companies to help with the maintenance of open source Perl (and Python) libraries they rely on. One of the responses I got was from someone who wanted to help with abandoned modules in his free time. He asked me which modules are abandoned?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pause.perl.org/pause/query?ACTION=pause_operating_model&#x22;&#x3E;PAUSE operating model&#x3C;/a&#x3E; mentions 3 special owners that can help identify modules that are up for adoption or otherwise need help. You can see the lists here: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rt.cpan.org/Dist/ByMaintainer.html?Name=ADOPTME&#x22;&#x3E;ADOPTME&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rt.cpan.org/Dist/ByMaintainer.html?Name=HANDOFF&#x22;&#x3E;HANDOFF&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rt.cpan.org/Dist/ByMaintainer.html?Name=NEEDHELP&#x22;&#x3E;NEEDHELP&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;More details can be seen on the CPANMeta site: for example for the modules owned by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpanmeta.grinnz.com/perms?author=ADOPTME&#x26;module=&#x26;match_mode=exact&#x22;&#x3E;ADOPTME&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Another type of listing can be found on Meta::CPAN. e.g. the permissions of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/HANDOFF/permissions&#x22;&#x3E;HANDOFF&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, I&#x27;ve also started to create similar listings with a different view on modules that are up for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/adoption&#x22;&#x3E;adoption&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So if you have free time and would be interested to contribute to the Perl community, one way would be to pick up a module and start maintaining it. If you need help with that, let me know and I&#x27;ll try to point you to the channels where you can get &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/help&#x22;&#x3E;help&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;-&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On a more personal note, I just finished watching the mini-series &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Small_Light&#x22;&#x3E;A Small Light&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It made me really sad and at the same time furious with all the self-declared &#x27;humanitarians&#x27; who try to paint Israel as being similar to Nazi Germany. It is especially disgusting, and even frightening, when celebrities do it and tens of thousands of people celebrate them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;-&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anyway, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-06-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/619.html">
<title>#619 - Maintenance of CPAN modules</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/619.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There are way too many CPAN modules that are abandoned or at least not maintained. Even many central ones rarely see activity. It is not very surprising though. Many people who used to develop and maintain these modules have moved to some job where the particular module is not needed or even where they use other languages. Actually I see similar things in Python as well, but let&#x27;s focus on Perl now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Encountering an issue in such a module that is hardly maintained is a frustrating experience as you could also read in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2023/05/mission-almost-accomplished/&#x22;&#x3E;recent article&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Dave Cross. However, it is not only frustrating. It hinders the efforts to get the job done. If it is an individual who wants to write some personal code that&#x27;s &#x27;just&#x27; frustrating. If it is a corporation then this actually cost a lot of money in wasted time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So what can be done about this?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For individuals such as Dave and plenty of people on this list, I think really the only solution is to take over the maintenance of the modules.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A corporation has various strategies. They can allocate time to their employees to fix the issues in the open source libraries. They can hire someone to work on these open source libraries. They could try to contract the developers and maintainers of these modules. Or they can just disregard the problem and basically make their own employees (that&#x27;s probably you) frustrated and waste a lot of time overcoming the issues.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After I read &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://words.filippo.io/full-time-maintainer/&#x22;&#x3E;this article&#x3C;/a&#x3E; a few weeks ago I wanted to see if I could offer a similar serveice. An alternative to the solutions mentioned before. &#x3C;b&#x3E;In a nutshell&#x3C;/b&#x3E;: companies could contract me specifically to work on the open source libraries they care about. (primarily Perl and Python libraries). I contacted a few companies and started to work with some of them on the idea.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My original thought was that we&#x27;ll agree upon a certain list of modules and I&#x27;ll work on that. Instead of that my first task is a more generic one. To make a tool that can help us evaluate the problems for a particular set of modules and decide what is more urgent. Basically triage the issues across a few 10s or more likely a few 100s of CPAN modules.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So in the last week or so I changed the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; a lot. Besides listing the most recently uploaded modules it now has a list of the most heavily dependent on modules based on the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://neilb.org/2015/04/20/river-of-cpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;river analogy&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Neil Bowers. It has a page for every distribution and every author. There is plenty of more to improve on it, but I am glad there are at least a few people who see this type of work valuable.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not good at marketing and sales so I figured the only way this model could work if some of you working at corporations who understand the need will become the local champions of the idea. Then we could work together to formulate the service to your management in a way that will be valuable to them. If you think this could help you, talk to me so we can figure this out together.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-06-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/618.html">
<title>#618 - Conference Season?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/618.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It seems we have been spoiled with the in-person conference. For all the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans, we got two choices, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.to/tprc-2023-tor&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Toronto&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Koha Conference in Helsinki&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I would highly recommend the one convenient to you. We all need to come together and share the knowledge.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am all set for the one in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Thanks to the organisers, I got the time slot to give a talk on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Looking at the list of attendees and speakers, it is going to be fun 3 days event. Looking forward to meet fellow &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; members at the event.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few weeks ago, I spoke about the ambitious project, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Conference in India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Soon I realised, it isn&#x27;t the right time to talk about. Although not my idea originally, I am taking a back seat for now. I hope to see it happening in my life time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html">
<title>#617 - The business risks of using CPAN</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You might know that I talk and write a lot about Open Source and I have a number of open source projects. Mostly web applications. One of them is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where I try to analyze CPAN packages and point to directions for relatively easy improvement. The most basic one would be a link to the public VCS (Version Control System) of the project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We have some historical data points with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/metacpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly reports&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Around 80% of the recently uploaded distributions have a link to their VCS. It is not bad, but is still 20% less than would be ideal. I am less happy about the fact that only 50% use any CI to check their code before it is released to CPAN.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;All this boils down to trying figure out the business risks of using Open Source 3rd party libraries in general and Perl modules in particular along with ways to alleviate them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;When you or your boss think about your Perl-based application, what are the things that make you worry? Do you bump into issues with modules that are not fixed? If you try to fix the issues, do you feel that it is hard to understand the code of the module?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What would make your life as a programmer using Perl easier? What would make your manager happier? Write a blog post. Comment on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly/issues/506&#x22;&#x3E;this issue&#x3C;/a&#x3E; or reply to me in private!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html">
<title>#616 - Camel in India</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;When I say &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I mean &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Indian Subcontinent&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; i.e. Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan and Srilanka. Having said, my prime concern is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; right now. You must have realised the context of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Camel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by now. Today I would like to talk about the popularity of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I remember when I left &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2000&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, it was on the rise and that is how I got into &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Programming&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. After moving to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;England&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I noticed how frequent the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans meetup and share ideas. I got the opportunity to attend some and realised how it can boost the popularity of the language and spread the positive word among newbies. Regular &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; meet also keep the subject live and active.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ever since the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COVID&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; happened, all these in-person events stopped initially. But the good news is that we are getting back on track with the events like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.to/tprc-2023-tor&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha Conference in Helsinki&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have decided to attend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Canada&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have submitted talk proposal too, little late though. I am still waiting for the acceptance. The other conference is clashing with my planned visit to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; unfortunately.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Going back to the main topic, I am wondering if we ever had any &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Conference in India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am aware of active &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but never heard of their activities. In the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Will Braswell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; reached out to me with a proposal to do &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Conference in India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Because of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COVID&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we put it on hold then. At the time, we decided to do month long tour to cover major cities spending 2-3 days in each city. I suggested the best time would be &#x3C;strong&#x3E;August&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as I will have long summer break. We would definitely need sponsors, ideally if we do under the banner of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then the reach would be even greater, in my humble opinion. The local &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group can be handy in organising the event. I would be eager to know if any &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group interested in these events. I would expect the groups down south would be more active as they are highly aware of technologies in general.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just realised this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;130th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. I also completed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as co-editor of the weekly newsletter in this month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter. Please do share your ideas and suggestions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html">
<title>#615 - PTS - Perl Toolchain Summit</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2023/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was held last week in Lyon, France. The website itself does not have a lot of information on it, but luckily the participants have blogged about it. There is plenty for you to read now if you&#x27;d like to keep up with the development in Perl, how to package Perl modules; how to install them, how CPAN and MetaCPAN work etc.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The PTS is a small even for people who are very deeply involved in the Perl ecosystem. It is a brain-storming session and a Hackathon. I wish there were similar session held more frequently around the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are looking for some Perl related event to participate in, there are two that I know of listed at the bottom of the newsletter and on our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/events.html&#x22;&#x3E;events page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. One is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in July in Toronto, Canada&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the other one is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in August in Helsinki, Finland.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you have the time and the budget make sure you attend at least one of them!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the meantime, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>