<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html">
<title>#585 - Handle your Pull-Requests!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know you are busy with tons of stuff and I know that as an Open Source developer you are most likely just a volunteer, but so are the people who send you Pull-Requests. It is very unpleasant to do the work, even if it small, send the pull-request and then never hear from the author any more.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking at my GitHub profile, apparently I created 600 Pull-requests, 530 of them are closed but 70 are still open. Some of them are open since 2011, that is 11 years ago. Some are as small as changing http to https in a URL, accepting (or rejecting) them should not take more than a few second. Finding them might be harder as GitHub does not seem to have a button for that, but you can easily search for them as you can see in my post &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/github-pull-requests-waiting-for-me&#x22;&#x3E;Listing Pull-request waiting for a user&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So I&#x27;d like to ask you to check if there are any &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/github-pull-requests-waiting-for-me&#x22;&#x3E;Pull-Requests waiting for you&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and try to clean up the queue.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hacktoberfest: If you receive a Pull-request during October, if you like it, accept it and consider marking it according to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.com/participation/#maintainers&#x22;&#x3E;instructions for maintainers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; so the PR will be accepted. (Hacktoberfest recognized 11 PRs I sent since registering, none of the repos are marked as participating. I am not sending the PRs for Hacktoberfest, but it would be encouraging to get the recognition.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html">
<title>#584 - Hacktoberfest &#x26; Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Hacktoberfest 2022 everyone !!!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure, most of you, already started hacking open source code. If not then you haven&#x27;t missed the train yet. You still have plenty of time to submit at least &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to qualified repositories in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitLab&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then I suggest you please take a look at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.com/participation&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The rule of the game has changed since I first participated in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2015&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have received the specially designed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;T-shirt&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; every year after completing the challenge ever since. As far as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is concerned, there are plenty of choices we have. However you have to make sure the open source project is taking part in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; event. As mentioned in the official note, you have to be quick as only the first &#x3C;strong&#x3E;40,000&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; participants who complete the challenge are eligible to receive the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE T-shirt&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Almost all my opensource contributions are hosted on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, you are FREE to pick any from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitLab&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; too. If you are like me, then you can pick and choose the participating repository from the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/topics/hacktoberfest?l=perl&#x22;&#x3E;list here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Having said, if you are still not sure then I would recommend two fun open source projects, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pullrequest.club/hello&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Kivanc Yizan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you miss &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There has been discussion started few days ago among the team members behind the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. We have an official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2022/09/london-perl-workshop-status-update-2023.html&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; requesting your opinions about the proposed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW 2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I sincerely request you all who participated in the past and would like to attend the event next year. Please do share with your friends too. I have already seen emails with suggestions, being one of the organiser. Thank you for your inputs, much appreciated.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html">
<title>#583 - Sponsoring Perl and other Open Source work</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy New Year - Shana Tova - to all the Jews around the world!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A couple of days ago Ed Freyfogle wrote us pointig to their post on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blog.opencagedata.com/post/sponsoring-metacpan&#x22;&#x3E;sponsoring MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I love this on so many levels. First of all, of course the fact that they sponsor some Perl-related activity. They also blog about it. They also send us a heads up to be included here in the Perl Weekly. I hope many more small and large companies, and also individuals will follow them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Dean Hamstead also sent us an email linking to the new &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://the-perl-store.creator-spring.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Store&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, that was also announced on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/tpf-merch-store&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Foundation blog&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Buying a T-shirt or some other swag will both help you with clothing and help TPF financially. Nice initiative!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, I managed to set up my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/sponsors/szabgab/&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub sponsors profile&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. So now, if you&#x27;d like to support my Perl and in more general Open Source work (articles, code, and videos) you can do so via GitHub as well. It would be awesome to get a few of you start supporting me via GitHub in the next couple of days. That will help things get rolling there and I would be able to see how the system really works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html">
<title>#582 - Grandfather&#x2019;s Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few months ago, there was a blog post &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.blog/2022/07/06/why-perl-is-still-relevant-in-2022&#x22;&#x3E;Why Perl is still relevant in 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E; created a lot of noise among the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; community. The author clearly missed the point. If you check the comments section, you can see how, White Camel Awardee, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and few others responed to the post.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was pleasantly surprised when I found out that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; came up with perfect response to the other blog post with this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.blog/2022/09/08/this-is-not-your-grandfathers-perl&#x22;&#x3E;This is not your grandfather&#x2019;s Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has already created positive noise. If you want to take a closer look at the recent changes to the latest release of &#x3C;/strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then please do checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E; sharing the changes with example. By the way, it is not just limited to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You will find plenty more to keep you busy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we got another gem from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; sharing the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/current-corinna-status.html&#x22;&#x3E;Current Corinna Status&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you can&#x27;t wait for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would suggest you take a look at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; module &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Object::Pad&#x22;&#x3E;Object::Pad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Evans&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, today, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Monday 19 September&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the date of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II&#x27;s State Funeral&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; declared as National Bank Holiday. Please checkout the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html">
<title>#581 - What to write about?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;People often tell me that they don&#x27;t know what to write about or that they are too new to Perl to blog about anything. Let&#x27;s see.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week I posted this article about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/ansi-command-line-colors-with-perl&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI command line colors with Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It hardly has anything to do with Perl, but I needed it and it can be a useful to others as well. Actually it originated from a discussion I had with my son who is using Python. So first I wrote the article &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/ansi-command-line-colors-with-python&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI colors using Python&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and only after that I converted it to Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It did not require any deep knowledge, definitely not that of Python or Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So if you would like to try writing articles, there are plenty of such small subjects one can cover.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After including the link in the previous edition of the Perl Weekly, Thomas K&#xF6;hler contacted me saying that he would do it differently and then he posted a short article showing how would he use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://gott-gehabt.de/800_wer_wir_sind/thomas/Homepage/Computer/perl/ansi-colors.html&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI colors in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; including a link back to the original article.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This is excellent.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So here is a suggestion: If you don&#x27;t have an idea for an article, pick one of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; posts and write a different solution or extend the subject and send a link to us, the editors of the Perl Weekly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html">
<title>#580 - Perl Mentor</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Good luck to all parents with school going kids in England, as today is the day one after a long summer vacation. I am one of them, fortunately or unfortunately. Be strong and you will get through this phase of life too.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Parents are the best mentor for their kids, in my humble opinion. During my early days, I didn&#x27;t know the importance of mentor. Having met some great mentor in real life in the recent times, I can say it is great service. In 2018, I gave a short talk on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2018/talk/7543&#x22;&#x3E;The power of mentoring&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, at London Perl Workshop. A work colleague who does &#x3C;strong&#x3E;mentoring&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as part of his role, is by far the best mentor, I have met so far. I learn something new every day from him by just joining him on daily standup. Although my contribution to the standup is nothing but it feels nice to see young blood with so much energy. I wish I had mentor like him when I started.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember there was an initiative started on private &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook group&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to encourage and help newbie. Unfortunately nothing happened although we had loads of mentor in the group.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Is it easy to be a mentor?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You would think so but I can tell you it is not. You have to have patience first thing first. I have seen how difficult it is to be a mentor. I would like to share a sweet moment with you. A month ago, a young blood interested to learn &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; reached out to me on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. At times, I wonder how did he find out about me. His question was, how do I execute &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hello World&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; script, he has already created. He was using VSCode editor. I am not a big fan of VSCode editor but in the current role, I got the opportunity to use it. Having said, I still use &#x3C;strong&#x3E;vim&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for everything else. Back to the story, we started talking on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; messenger. I find it hard to convey message on messenger. So I requested him to join on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team video call&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It took &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 minutes&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; call to resolve the issue. While there, I showed him few other things beyond, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;hello world&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, he would carry on exploring the language further.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Is it mostly about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In my personal experience, no. I was once contacted by a member of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with regard to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;git related issues&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as he couldn&#x27;t submit his contribution to the weekly challenge. So there again, we jumped on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team video call&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and in no time, he was good to go. Just to be explicit here, he was not a newbie but an experienced techie with way more than experience than me. It feels great to help. It is not one-way traffic as when I get stuck, I know who to contact. Luckily I get instant help too, so far. Few months ago, when I used to do &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/mohammadsajidanwar&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube video&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I had trouble with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;OBS Studio&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I asked for help on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You wouldn&#x27;t believe, I had more help than I expected from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lance Wicks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I now have working environment back, although I am not doing live video any more because of lack of time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For those, need help can reach out to me on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/mohammad.s.anwar&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I must make this clear, I will not do your course work. I am available for anyone anytime as I literally spend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;12-14 hours&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in front of machine every day.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a great week and enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html">
<title>#579 - Looking for that motivation</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html&#x22;&#x3E;Last time&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I mentioned the numbers I collect with the number of visitors to CPAN and I was wondering about the increased activity starting in August 2011. I got a few comments in email and some on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/wosxyi/perl_weekly_issue_577_optimism_and_numbers/&#x22;&#x3E;Reddit&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Probably the best explanation is what I received from Neil Bowers:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://neilb.org/2022/02/07/cpan-report-2022.html&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN report I did in February&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you look at the new user signups, you&#x27;ll see a jump in 2012, and also looking at that chart you&#x27;ll see that 2012, 2013, and 2014 seem to buck a trend.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In 2012 Intermediate Perl was released, which told the reader to sign up for a PAUSE account and release a test module. If I remember right, brian d foy ran a tutorial at YAPC::NA the previous year, where he also got people to sign up (not sure if the tutorial was 2011 or 2012). We had the first CPAN Day in 2014, which also resulted in a big bump in CPAN releases. That may have helped 2014 stay up above the trend.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The question now, what could be a new motivation to increase activity and if there could be one that is sustainable?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html">
<title>#578 - Corinna MVP</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Belated Happy Independence Day to all fellow Indians. We celebrated 75th Anniversary of Independence on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;15th August&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, a proud moment for all of us.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ever since the release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, everyone is looking forward to the next big thing in the pipeline, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, you don&#x27;t need an introduction but if you do then you can take a look at this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor&#x22;&#x3E;official documentation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; recently shared the latest update about the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna (MVP)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as accepted by The Perl Steering Committee as detailed in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/blob/master/rfc/mvp.md&#x22;&#x3E;document&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you follow the latest release to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I noticed one particular distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/WWW-Mechanize&#x22;&#x3E;WWW::Mechanize&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, currently maintained by a friend of mine and colleague at work, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. He is on the mission to clear pending issues. He shared the news recently that pull request queue is empty in this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/simbabque/status/1559267485764816896&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter thread&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I noticed the distribution has &#x3C;strong&#x3E;92.50% coverage&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you have spare time and would like to contribute then please do help get &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100% coverage&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Perl jobs in London seems getting back on track. Couple of days ago, I received an email about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.careers/jobs/perl_programmer_business_owner_uk_eu_remote&#x22;&#x3E;Perl role in London&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Perl Careers. The title of the post caught my eye, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Developer and Business Owner?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, I would like to recommend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/learning_perl_exercises&#x22;&#x3E;Learning Perl Exercises&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, you will find it handy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html">
<title>#577 - Optimism and numbers</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;last week Mohammad expressed his optimism about Perl rising again. It&#x27;s nice to have a gut feeling about that, but I would also like to see the numbers. So I looked at the stats I&#x27;ve been collecting for a while: The number of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/cpan-number-of-visits.html&#x22;&#x3E;visits to CPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. More specifically these are the number of &#x22;entrances&#x22; to MetaCPAN (and in earlier times to SCO as well.) as measured by Google Analytics.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My assumption is that we can measure well the level of Perl usage by the number of visits to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The number for July 2022 does not indicate any (positive) changes, but it is probably too early to see any effects anyway.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, looking at the numbers I noticed that there was a nice increase in the activity in 2012. Actually starting in August 2011. This increased activity lasted about a year then the decline continued and by 2014 the activity was below that of the 2011 level.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I could find 2 Perl-related events preceding the increased activity. In May 2011 the release of perl 5.14 and in July the opening of MetaCPAN. Neither seem to explain the change. So I am turning to you:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What other things happened in or out of the Perl community that might explain that sudden increase of visitors to CPAN?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html">
<title>#576 - Perl is on the Rise?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally I have noticed the fresh energy among all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans ever since the release of latest &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am telling this based on the amount of positive noise I heard on various public platform. There are still few in the pipeline that would give further push e.g. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are interested to know more then please do checkout this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki&#x22;&#x3E;page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; maintained by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is another place where you can see all the latest cool &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; projects. I know plenty of volunteers helping to improve the code base. If you use a distribution and you like it then why not share your experience with the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and submit your proposal to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cfp.perladvent.org&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;? Or if you have created one then why not share with rest of the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and needs help then please do give us a shout. There are plenty of help available on various public platforms.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>