<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2024, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/665.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/664.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/663.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/662.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html">
<title>#669 - How Time Machine works</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week Mohammed wrote that he can&#x27;t wait to test out perl 5.40. In response Michiel Beijen wrote a blog post explaining how you can already try 5.39.10, using plenv. I love this!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As you might know a while ago I stopped using mailman for the Perl Weekly and now both the subscription and unsubscription process is done by sending me an email that I read and process manually. This gives an excellent opportunity to the new subscribers to introduce themselves and even to mention the subjects that are interested in.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As the Perl Weekly is a news aggregator I am going to share some of the items in his mail hoping that some of you will write blog posts covering some of the issues.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a long break from Perl, I&#x27;m looking for best current practice on building a website for a cycling club.  So I&#x27;m curious about the full stack (for collaborative dev, integration, and public deployment) the architecture (MVC (Dancer2 or Mojolicious) &#x26; DB), and frameworks for Plack/PSGI, JavaScript, unit and acceptance testing, and OO, for example.&#x3C;br&#x3E;Also, what collaborative tools to use for Scrum/Kanban collaboration, and source control, CI and CD.&#x3C;br&#x3E; To start with, I am hunting around for best practice on a dev Webserver and client, and, later, a public web hosting server.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This was my response: To respond to your questions: I personally was using Dancer a lot, but  Mojolicious seems to have slightly more development activity.&#x3C;br&#x3E;For CI I use either GitHub Actions or GitLab pipelines depending on which git hosting service the project uses.&#x3C;br&#x3E;I rent a server at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linode.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Linode&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but I have converted many of my sites to be static using some Static Site Generator and then I host them on GitHub pages.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I hope you&#x27;ll have more detailed answer.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Actually, in this edition we have a post by Dave Cross on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2024/05/deploying-dancer-apps/&#x22;&#x3E;Deploying Dancer Apps&#x3C;/a&#x3E; already responding to part of the questions. This is how time-machine works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html">
<title>#668 - Perl v5.40</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The latest Perl Steering Council weekly updates about the good progress in preparation of release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I can&#x27;t wait to get my hand dirty with the new features.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;London Perl Workshop is making good progress thanks to the hard work of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lee Johnson&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As per the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024&#x22;&#x3E;official website&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, we now have a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Diamond Sponsor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping venue would be finalised soon. I would urge all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans to register your interest in the event so that the organiser can plan the event better.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The upconing event, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is in demand. I get to hear a lot of preparation is underway to make it memorable experience for all attendees. I am going to miss the fun, unfortunately. I hope to join you all online if it is available.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, you take extra care of yourself and your loved ones. Enjoy and celebrate Perl as always.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html">
<title>#667 - Call for papers and sponsors for LPW 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week Mohammed already mentioned the LPW, now they have a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2024/05/lpw-2024---call-for-papers-and-sponsors.html&#x22;&#x3E;Call For Papers and Sponsors&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am glad they write on bpo, but I also wonder, do they publish the CFP on other web sites as well. e.g. DEV.to?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I don&#x27;t have a lot of time dealing with Perl these days, but I looked at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/recent&#x22;&#x3E;recent report of CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and I see there are still quite a few CPAN packages that do not link to their public Version Control System (VCS). If you have some spare time maybe you could check out the modules in the &#x3C;b&#x3E;VCS&#x3C;/b&#x3E; column and ask the author to add the appropriate fields so it will be easier for others to find the git repository.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the Holocaust memorial day in Israel. I assume most of the readers of the Perl Weekly know what it is about, but I am surprised how many people in the world have never heard the word or don&#x27;t know what it is about. I spend the day partially by watching interviews and lectures. I listed some of them on my site: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/holocaust-memorial-day-in-israel-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Holocaust memorial day in Israel in 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also wrote an article titled &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/humanitarian-aid-for-gaza&#x22;&#x3E;Rafah and the humanitarian aid for Gaza&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you&#x27;d like to read more about the topic from me, you can &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/subscribe&#x22;&#x3E;register to my newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Unfortunately I need to deal with this quite a lot instead of sending Pull-Requests.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html">
<title>#666 - LPW 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As we all know, German Perl/Raku Workshop 2024 happend few weeks ago, it turned out to be lucky for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. After GPW, we got the official announcement of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2024/04/announcing-the-london-perl-and-raku-workshop-2024-lpw.html&#x22;&#x3E;LPW 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is going to be one day event as per the tradition. The tentative date as of today is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;26th October 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and it is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Saturday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then don&#x27;t forget to plan your visit in advance. It is returning after a gap of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be a special event for one more reason as it would be the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th anniversay&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in terms of years. I am very happy to see the support we already got. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared the news that he has submitted &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 talks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; already. If you are planning to attend then please submit your talk as well. &#x3C;stron&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; always encourage first time speakers. If you can&#x27;t make it full length talk then you can even submit &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 minutes&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; lightning talk. To my surprise, as soon as the annoucement was public, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://geekuni.com/corporate-perl-training&#x22;&#x3E;Geekuni&#x3C;/a&#x3E; became the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Silver Sponsor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Ofcourse, we are looking for more sponsors. If your workplace codebase uses &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then I would suggest you please speak to the management if they are willing to sponsor the event. You can find more details about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024/sponsoring.html&#x22;&#x3E;different sponsor packages&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is another big event happening in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and it is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;24-28 June 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The event organisers made a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/tprc2024vol&#x22;&#x3E;Call for Volunteers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had plan to attend the event with family as it is happening in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Now the circumstance is such that even my own visit is not confirmed. It would be a big loss if I don&#x27;t make it to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; this time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you remember the last major release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? It was special because of the inclusion of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping, in the next release &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we get more features added to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. According to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/blob/5fdf6e90221900a85cd3091bd2755e41fc230d4d/Porting/release_schedule.pod?plain=1#L54&#x22;&#x3E;this document&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, the tentative release date is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th May 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The post series &#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN ...&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is my all time favourite. Recently it got fresh air and we had 4 in a row e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-november-2023&#x22;&#x3E;Nov 23&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-december-2023&#x22;&#x3E;Dec 23&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-january-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Jan 24&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-february-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Feb 24&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is nearly end of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Apr 24&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and we have not seen the post for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mar 24&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I just hope and wish, the tradition doesn&#x27;t die. I am keeping my fingers crossed.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, you please take a good care of yourself and your loved ones. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/665.html">
<title>#665 - How to get better at Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/665.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A new subscriber of the Perl Weekly wrote me:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x22;I&#x27;ve used Perl for a while but I would love to be fluent in it.  Please let me know if you have any advice.&#x22;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I think the best way is to work on projects and if you can find nice people who have time to comment on your work then ask them. Depending on your level you might want to try &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://exercism.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Exercism&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that has a Perl track for practice and a built-in system for asking for and getting feedback on the specific exercises. Even better, once you did the exercises you can become a mentor there helping others. That gives you another opportunity to look at these problems and help other people like yourself.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You can participate in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by Mohammad S. Anwar, the other editor of the Perl Weekly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Longer term I&#x27;d suggest to work on a real project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Either create a project for yourself or you can start contributing to open source projects (e.g. CPAN modules). I&#x27;d start trying to contribute to active projects - so ones that saw a release recently.  MetaCPAN has a page showing &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;recent CPAN releases&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the CPAN Digger provides some analytics and suggestions for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/recent&#x22;&#x3E;recent CPAN releases&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. You can also contributed to MetaCPAN itself. This is also a nice way to contribute back to the Perl community.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, Happy Passover celebrating the freedom of Jews from slavery. Let me wish to you the same we have been saying for hundreds of years at the end of the Passover dinner:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Next year in Jerusalem!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/664.html">
<title>#664 - German Perl Workshop</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/664.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 1&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/gpw2024/index.html&#x22;&#x3E;German Perl Workshop 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is going to be very busy week for those attending the annual event. As per the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/gpw2024/schedule?day=2024-04-15&#x22;&#x3E;schedule&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is giving talk on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/gpw2024/talk/7866&#x22;&#x3E;AI&#x2014;This Talk is Always Out of Date&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am pretty sure, it is going to be very popular among the attendees. Most of the talks are going to be in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as expected. English speaking attendees shouldn&#x27;t worry as there would be some talks in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;English&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; too. The team behind the GPW is so friendly and welcoming that you would never get bored throughout the day. It feels great to see how they have managed to organise the event every year. There was a time when &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; used to be so popular that attracted attendees from as far as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Japan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; just for one day event. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lee Johnson&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has been pushing hard to make it happen this year. Please show your interest in good numbers if you are LPW fans. Finding Sponsor is the biggest hurdle, if I am not mistaken. I just hope we don&#x27;t miss the opportunity this year.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently I got the shocking news about my friend, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Hodgkinson&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There was a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; post sharing the news that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; passed away last &#x3C;strong&#x3E;December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have had the honour to meet him at every LPW event. He would never miss the opportunity to catch up his friends. He was also regular to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; meetup. In the last few years when the event didn&#x27;t happen, he was actively engaging with friends on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I used to chat with him on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook messenger&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; regularly. I still have his message wishing me good luck when I joined &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Oleeo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. This news really shocked me. Last &#x3C;strong&#x3E;December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was so depressing time for me, as I lost my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mom&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on Boxing day. This is a small tribute to my buddy, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. May his soul rest in peace.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Please take extra care of your health and your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/663.html">
<title>#663 - No idea</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/663.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It seems I have less and less to write about in these editorials. This is of course not very surprising as I there are fewer and fewer articles published about Perl. The only thing that still keeps this afloat is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;the Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Mohammad. So maybe you can &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar/posts&#x22;&#x3E;sponsor it&#x3C;/a&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Sad news: Just a few days ago I heard that &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/rozallin/posts/pfbid0Smz8cifiBSm6GuPG5Dui1mssNv1TydpncD7sQX5bAGGmb83B9y4B4KWzVYQyghuyl&#x22;&#x3E;Dave Hodgkinson has passed away&#x3C;/a&#x3E; last December. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-hodgkinson/&#x22;&#x3E;LinkedIn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/davehodg&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, and his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.davehodgkinson.com/&#x22;&#x3E;web site&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he posted in November. May he rest in peace and his family find solace. He will be missed.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In a totally unrelated sadness: It has been &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/six-months&#x22;&#x3E;six months.&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish you a nicer week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/662.html">
<title>#662 - TPRC in Las Vegas</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/662.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How time flies, it is incredible. It feels like we just attended &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRC in Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Well the next edition is coming soon, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;June 24-28, 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, to be very precise. At the end of the conference in &#x3C;stron&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; last year, I was determined to attend the next one in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As we all know, you can&#x27;t plan everything and execute it too as per your wish. Honestly speaking, it is the only annual event where you get to meet and greet all the big guns. I would recommend everyone who can afford to attend, must &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2024.sched.com/tickets&#x22;&#x3E;book the ticket&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and enjoy the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Early Bird&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; offer.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html&#x22;&#x3E;last edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was discussed in details. There was even call for sponsors for the event as well. I know how hard it is to find a sponsor these days. I remember there was a time when you see sponsor desks all over at the entrance of event. Before, the name of event was enough to bring in sponsors but time has changed and you need to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/5-reasons-to-sponsor-the-perl-toolchain-summit&#x22;&#x3E;share reasons&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to find the sponsor. Thank you, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, for the dedidated blog post to gather the support and sponsors for the event. This year, it is happening in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lisbon, Portugal&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Not far from where I am based but it is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;invite-only&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; event. Having said, anyone interested to be part of the group, can start contributing to the Perl toolchain.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about sponsors, I made an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/644.html&#x22;&#x3E;appeal for sponsor&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, Nov&#x27;23, for my pet project, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge - Perl &#x26; Raku&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I did receive couple of offers but nothing materialised unfortunately. The exercise taught me a lesson, though. In order to find a corporate sponsor, one need to be a registered entity. Since I ran the project single handedly for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; now with zero experience of running and managing a registered entity, I find it involves lot of paper works and an accountant to look after finance matters. As you have guessed it correctly, this needs funding too. So I am going around the circle and not getting anywhere. I then decided to submit the project for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Outreachy 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; sponsored by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In the past, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Open Food Facts&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is the choosen one and is likely to be the case this time too. Time to start fresh again ...&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the last day of long &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Easter Holiday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in England. I had planned so much to do in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 days&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; break but could only managed to do few. I am happy the school is still on long break at least. I can enjoy &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Monday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for a change. How was your weekend?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter and look after yourself.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html">
<title>#661 - Perl Toolchain Summit 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/661.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/release/PEVANS/perl-5.39.9/view/pod/perldelta.pod&#x22;&#x3E;Perl 5.39.9 was released&#x3C;/a&#x3E; including the new ^^ operator. It is only a development release, but I&#x27;d like to encourage you to give it a try and give feedback to the developers.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was some nefarious activity on CPAN. Someone &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/1biniqg/perl5382_suspiciously_reposted_to_cpan/&#x22;&#x3E;re-uploaded perl-5-38.2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It was reported and the security team quickly eliminated the threat.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was wondering if I should write about the hate mails I received: one for myself as Jew (my ethnicity) triggered by what I wrote &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/659.html&#x22;&#x3E;two weeks ago&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and one on behalf of Mohammed as a Muslim (his religion) triggered by what he wrote &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html&#x22;&#x3E;last week&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I&#x27;ve removed these people from the distribution, but I think they need more accountability. I am still contemplating publishing the names of these people along with their messages so the Perl community and their employers will be aware of that. After all most of us don&#x27;t want to work with abusive people, do we?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl Toolchain Summit is coming again and they need your help sponsoring the even. Here is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2024/PTS2024-Sponsor-Prospectus.pdf&#x22;&#x3E;Sponsor prospectus for Perl Toolchain Summit 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Last year I ran an &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-2023-01-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;online course about Open Source development&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the proceedings went to the summit (though I transferred them late, so probably they could not use that in time). This year I don&#x27;t have the time for that, but I hope you will see the value in the summit and will sponsor it directly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html">
<title>#660 - What&#x27;s new ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/660.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to all the readers who fast during this holy month. May &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ALLAH s.w.t&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; accept your fasting, Ameen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently became active on official Slack for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; after a long gap. I noticed it is very much active and live. Lots of positive noise and useful information shared with each other. I am not a big fan of Slack but after spending just few days, I find it easy to move around. I would like to keep an eye for important news and announcement. Earlier my only source of information was the good old &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org&#x22;&#x3E;https://blogs.perl.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We used to have regular post by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; enthusiasts but that has stopped unfortunately. And I don&#x27;t blame them as I also stopped blogging completely. As and when I do blog, I use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; platform. Having said, the platform is still used by some, for example &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Steering Council&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for weekly updates. Every now and then, you do get some magical post by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans. One such post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/e_choroba/2024/03/changes-in-mooxroleparameterized.html&#x22;&#x3E;Changes in MooX::Role::Parameterized&#x3C;/a&#x3E; appeared last week by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;E. Choroba&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have been a big fan of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Moo - Minimalist Object Orientation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, so this post became even more important for me. Although, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has made it to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core, it is still a long way before it becomes a complete solution to all OO needs. I am looking forward to the next big release which would bring in some more features, hopefully.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was introduced to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by the post series &#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;David Farrell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It used to be regular every month with full of fun facts about new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; modules released. During those days, I used to be active on CPAN and released few &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I had the honour to find place in the post often. Recently &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; took the initiative to revive the activities on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Because of his hard work and with the help of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mathew Korica&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; we now have the post series back. You must check latest in the series, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-february-2024&#x22;&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN - February 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just realised that this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;150th&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; edition and in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 months&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; I will complete &#x3C;strong&#x3E;6 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as co-editor of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; newsletter. It has been a very fruitful learning experience for me and I enjoyed it thoroughly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Keep the spirit high and don&#x27;t let the bad influence pull you down. Please do take care your health and loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-03-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>