<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2021, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/535.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/534.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html">
<title>#536 - Auf Wiedersehen Hacktoberfest</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/536.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The headline of this week newsletter dedicated to all my German friends. However, the message is global &#x22;Good bye Hacktoberfest&#x22;. I don&#x27;t know the language, so I asked Google to help me. I am sure you all celebrated the month long festival with loads of contributions to many opensource codebase. I can completely understand the feeling at the end of month. Those who have participated and completed the challenge successfully i.e. submitted at least 4 eligible Pull Requests, should just relax and wait for the FREE gift. Please consider, November as break, since December would bring in another fun challenge i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://24pullrequests.com&#x22;&#x3E;24 Pull Requests&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anything else to look forward to?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, there is another fun bit is the &#x22;Advent Calendar&#x22;. There would be plenty of Advent Calendars available during the month. It is really hard to follow all. I came across something called, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.lenjaffe.com/AdventPlanet&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Planet&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, which collects almost all popular Advent Calendars for us. Please do checkout, if you want a early peek. I really miss those days when I used to have all the time just for such things. I have contributed to Perl/Raku advent calendars in the past. If you have spare time and interest then please do get in touch with the person behind the project now and book your slot. There is one &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2020&#x22;&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; dedicated to the members of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; only. I make sure the tradition continues every year. I hope everything goes as per the plan and we have another fun Advent Calendar by the dedicated members this year also.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Start your week with yet another informative newsletter. You take care of yourself and your family. Keep distace and stay safe,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-11-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/535.html">
<title>#535 - Exercism and Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/535.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A long, long time ago I contributed a few Perl-related exercises to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://exercism.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Exercism&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but then for another long time I only recommended it, but didn&#x27;t use it myself. Recently I returned to it with the hope to use it as a platform to allow my students to practice. I noticed that the Perl track has 62 exercises while many of the other tracks have more. Some of them twice as many.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have you tried doing the Perl track recently? Are you a mentor on the Perl track? Have you contributed an exercises?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wonder if it would be a good idea for Mohammad, to post his Weekly challenges as exercises on Exercism.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/534.html">
<title>#534 - Are you CPAN contributor?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/534.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How much have you contributed during the Hacktoberfest event yet?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;CPAN needs a helping hand, not just during Hacktoberfest. I am raising the subject as Dave Cross recently blogged about his experience with one of the distributions hosted on CPAN in this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/davorg/failing-to-get-product-information-from-amazon-with-perl-5a3g&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It also reminds me of my early days when I created Perl a library around some of Google&#x27;s public APIs. Two of them, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/WWW-Google-CustomSearch&#x22;&#x3E;WWW::Google::CustomSearch&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/WWW-Google-Places&#x22;&#x3E;WWW::Google::Places&#x3C;/a&#x3E; were used by many people, as I have had many queries related to them in the past. It is very common for an API provider to discontinue the service or move in a new direction any time without notice. It becomes an even bigger issue if the author of the CPAN distribution disappears from the scene. So the question is, how best to deal with such cases? Thanks to the PAUSE admins, there is a documented process to adopt a distribution and take it forward. You should get in touch with one of the PAUSE admins if you want to adopt a distribution and contribute.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For many years, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; has been my playground. I used to spend 2-4 hours every day looking for low-hanging issues in the recently uploaded distributions. I even wrote a two-part blog post talking about how to become a CPAN contributor. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/how-to-become-cpan-contributor&#x22;&#x3E;Part 1&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/how-to-become-cpan-contributor-part-2&#x22;&#x3E;Part 2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I also gave a talk at The Perl Conference in Glasgow 2018 on the same topic. You can watch the talk on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QYN1nijo9VY&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, if you fancy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember at one point, I was keen to contribute to MetaCPAN and be part of the Toolchain Gang. I couldn&#x27;t get the local dev setup of MetaCPAN and was looking for help. I was told that someone from the gang is working on dockerisation of MetaCPAN to make it easier for anyone to contribute. I missed the opportunity to meet the gang when it was held in Marlow, not far from where I live (London) in 2019. I don&#x27;t know if anyone is still working on that front.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I hardly contribute to CPAN these days but I still like to call myself CPAN contributor. However I do release a patch every now and then to some of my personal and adopted distributions. Being a member of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pullrequest.club/hello&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I do contribute to at least one distribution every month. I have never missed a month since I joined the club in Jan 2019.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If anyone is keen to become a CPAN contributor then please get in touch with me. We need fresh energy to make CPAN the central place to look for the best solutions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html">
<title>#533 - Consulting work</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just had a meeting with a company in the UK that were looking for some consulting in Perl. After our conversation I felt that what they are interested in is not really where my expertise is, so I referred them to two other people who have a lot more experience in those areas. However I realized I don&#x27;t know who is providing consulting or development service these days. So let me know. Who knows next time I might be able to refer the clients to you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the other hand I just found out that my client, where I do some refactoring on a web-application with some machine-learning backend (written in Python). is likely to move the project to their parent company. This probably means I&#x27;ll be free for other projects to introduce test automation, CI, and refactoring code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html">
<title>#532 - Hacktoberfest 2021</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have you joined the annual &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com&#x22;&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2021&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by Digital Ocean?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If not then please join without any further delay. Hacktoberfest encourages participation in the open source community. You can earn a limited edition T-shirt by completing the challenge.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Not sure if you noticed, but this time they have made an interesting change by allowing open source maintainers to also take part in the contest. Ever since I started &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I have hardly found time to dedicate to Hacktoberfest. Last year I could only submit 6 PRs, enough to win the contest, since you only need to submit 4 PRs. This year, I am only taking part as the maintainer of an open source project - &#x22;The Weekly Challenge&#x22;. The best year for me as contributor was 2019 when I submitted 160 PRs.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are looking for an open source project to contribute to then you can join &#x22;The Weekly Challenge&#x22; and win the competition by submitting 4 PRs in just one week.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, you could submit 2 Perl and 2 Raku solutions to the weekly task. Just submit one solution per PR. I know it is cheating but a fair one in my humble opinion. Again, please don&#x27;t limit yourself to just Perl and Raku. You are free to choose your favourite programming language. One more bit, please don&#x27;t tie yourself to the current weekly challenge. You are free pick any past week challenges. Plenty of choices available. If you have any questions with regard to submitting a PR then please follow the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/how-to-contribute&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that explains every detail. If you still have any questions then please get in touch with me. You can find my details on the page. I am also accepting PRs to another open source project - &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/theweeklychallenge&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; website which is also open source code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are a CPAN contributor then you could pick and choose your favourite distribution and contribute. However there is a catch, the distribution may or may not be part of the contest. Having said that, you can contribute to my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/MANWAR&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN distributions&#x3C;/a&#x3E; if you fancy. I promise, I will make the distribution to be part of the contest so that your PR will count towards the target. Just yesterday, I received a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/BankAccount-Validator-UK/pull/2&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on one of my CPAN distributions, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/BankAccount-Validator-UK&#x22;&#x3E;BankAccount::Validator::UK&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Hacking !!!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html">
<title>#531 - Legacy code</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I like working on legacy code whether it is Perl, Python or some other language, because it is code that is already very valuable to the organization that uses it. It is great to help the maintainers understand the code better and to give them confidence in making changes to the code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There are a number of language specific tools that can help you while dealing with legacy code. For example Perl Critic which is mentioned in at least two posts this edition. There are more generic things, like setting up a good CI system which is mentioned by Gugod.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The ideal situation is when both management and the engineers really want the change. They still probably need some external help from someone who has experience in similar situations and who has already seen systems where the engineers have no fear in making changes. It is a totally different world than what many people experience in organizations.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your fearless week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html">
<title>#530 - Outreachy 2021</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you remember, I mentioned the Outreachy program in the editorial of the weekly newsletter edition &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/522.html&#x22;&#x3E;#522&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has finally come to an end as Rosheen Naeem successfully completed the internship as reported by the TPF in a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/outreachy2021-complete&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Congratulations Rosheen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl Foundation is looking for mentors and project ideas for the next Outreachy rounds. If you have Perl or Raku project ideas, please get in touch with TPF.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Many years ago, I was approached for help by the Open Food Facts team as they found out about my distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/Food-ECodes&#x22;&#x3E;Food::ECodes&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Unfortunately it didn&#x27;t work out as I was too busy with my other pet projects. I hope one day I can contribute to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/openfoodfacts/openfoodfacts-server&#x22;&#x3E;Open Food Facts&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I remember I had trouble setting up a local development environment for my contributions. I haven&#x27;t had a chance to see if there has been any improvements in this area to help newcomers to contribute.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I request Perl fans to come forward and help the cool fun project Open Food Facts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html">
<title>#529 - K&#xF6;MaL for the math enthusiasts</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A long long time ago, when I was in high school, I participated in the annual competition of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.komal.hu/&#x22;&#x3E;K&#xF6;MaL, the Mathematical and Physical Journal for High Schools&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. (Look for the little UK flag for the English version). Back then we sent in the solution by snail-mail and we only had to write our name to be identified. However people with very common names were asked to include a 3-digit number between their names. There was no verification that two people with the exact same name did not pick the same number, but the chances were slim. Because my name is way too common in Hungary I picked the number 529 because it is 23^2. Funnily, if you squint it also resembles the initials of my name: SzG&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anyway, if you or your kids like math, informatics, or physics, I&#x27;d recommend it!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html">
<title>#528 - Legacy Code</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How old is the Perl code that you work on currently?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Curtis wrote an interesting &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/a-simple-way-to-fix-legacy-code.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about dealing with legacy code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a long time, I got the opportunity to work with good old CGI. It reminds me of my early learning days. Talking about CGI, I came across fun &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oasys.net/posts/migrating-a-perl-cgi-to-aws-lambda&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about Migrating a Perl CGI application to AWS Lambda.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Please do share anything interesting you are trying using Perl. I am currently working on Elastic Search using Perl. As always CPAN provides great support e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Search::Elasticsearch&#x22;&#x3E;Search::Elasticsearch&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What else changed in your routine?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, the school run is back. How about you?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter. Hopefully next week we will have more perl blog posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html">
<title>#527 - New school-year?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The number of posts has been really low in the last couple of weeks. I really hope that with the new school-year in the northern hemisphere, we&#x27;ll see an uptick in Perl-related content.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Other:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just saw a Tweet explaining why the person does not wear a mask. He writes because he is vaccinated he isn&#x27;t likely to be infected and &#x3C;b&#x3E;he accepts the risks&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. Well, I really try to avoid arguing with strangers on the Internet so I did not write to him, but basically he said that &#x3C;b&#x3E;he accepts the risk of endangering others&#x3C;/b&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In reality he spread two types of viruses. Potentially he spreads the Covid19 virus and for sure he spreads the idea that not caring for others is acceptable. For one, people who are unsure about the masks, seeing him without a mask will more likely stop wearing masks too.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Get vaccinated if you can and wear a mask when among people!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-30T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>