<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2024, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/675.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/674.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/673.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/672.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/671.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/670.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/675.html">
<title>#675 - Videos from TPRC 2024 - Las Vegas, Nevada</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/675.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;TPRC 2024 has ended and the videos are now available. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLA9_Hq3zhoFw6patag2gZcDjpugDLBStL&#x22;&#x3E;Enjoy!&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Oh and now that it is over, you can also register to the two virtual events I am running: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/events/301413566/&#x22;&#x3E;Continuous Integration (CI): GitHub Actions for Perl Projects&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/events/301871765/&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub Pages for Perl developers &#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-07-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/674.html">
<title>#674 - What&#x27;s new in Perl v5.40?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/674.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Around two weeks ago, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;9th June 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the much awaited &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/perl5400delta&#x22;&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was released. As always, the production release was packed with cool core enhancements. Thanks to the entire team of volunteers who worked day in day out to get the latest release smoothly. I would like to share my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Top #5&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core enhancements as below:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;ul&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v540/class.pl&#x22;&#x3E;New __CLASS__ keyword&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v540/class-reader.pl&#x22;&#x3E;:reader attribute for field variables&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v540/xor.pl&#x22;&#x3E;New ^^ logical xor operator&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v540/try-catch.pl&#x22;&#x3E;try/catch feature no longer experimental&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v540/for-list.pl&#x22;&#x3E;for iterating over multiple values at a time is no longer experimental&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/ul&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 1&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2024 in Las Vegas&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The entire day is dedicated for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hackathon&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The main attraction of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 2&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is going to be the keynote talk by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Who is your favourite &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2024.sched.com/directory/speakers?iframe=no&#x22;&#x3E;speakers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; at the event? I am looking forward to the talk by work colleague, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2024.sched.com/speaker/simbabque?iframe=no&#x22;&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There is another speaker I am looking forward to, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2024.sched.com/speaker/ingydotnet?iframe=no&#x22;&#x3E;Ingy d&#xF6;t Net&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, who is scheduled to talk about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;YAMLScript&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Clojure&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There is another talk, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2024.sched.com/event/1dGtK/build-a-better-readme&#x22;&#x3E;Build a better README&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, is one of my favourites by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Jason Crome&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. A recent post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://yamlscript.org/posts/jun-20-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Dr. StrangeYAML or How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the LLM&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ingy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is not to be missed. If you like playing with &#x3C;string&#x3E;LLM&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then this is your friend.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-06-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/673.html">
<title>#673 - One week till the Perl and Raku conference</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/673.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We had our first virtual event a couple of days ago. I was really happy to see that more than 25 people joined. We also have the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://youtu.be/mh9kx-Swx74&#x22;&#x3E;video recordings of Getting started with Docker for Perl developers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Please watch, click on the thumbs-up and follow the channel!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The next such event will be on 14 July about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/events/301413566/&#x22;&#x3E;Continuous Integration (CI): GitHub Actions for Perl Projects&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I&#x27;d like to encourage you to register to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens&#x22;&#x3E;Code-Mavens group&#x3C;/a&#x3E; an to the event itself. I would be also happy to get requests for topics to cover.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/events&#x22;&#x3E;events page of the Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E; you can now see all the Perl-related events we know about. It also features a calendar you can add to Google calendar or whatever other program you use to see the events along with your own events.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The closest of all those events is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that starts a week from today. It is still not too late to register and to use it as an excuse to go to Las Vegas... You could, of course also sponsor the conference...&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Another one of the big in-person events is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024/&#x22;&#x3E;London Perl and Raku Workshop&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that will take place in October. There you still have time to submit a talk proposal or to offer your sponsorship.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-06-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/672.html">
<title>#672 - It&#x27;s time ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/672.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E; ... to celebrate the release of Perl v5.40.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To be honest, I have been watching the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the updates almost every day for the last one week. The wait was over finally on Sunday late evening UK time. You can certainly take a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perldoc.perl.org/perl5400delta&#x22;&#x3E;closer look&#x3C;/a&#x3E; if you want. I am going to install the latest bundle in the next couple of days and play with it. Having said, I am a bit disappointed to find out that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;role&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is not yet implemented in the core OO. I understand the workload on the team, specially &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Evans&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I wish and hope he gets the support and helping hands in getting the outstanding features done quickly. Reason I am curious about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;role&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is that I am working on something that uses the new OO syntax and I need to implement &#x3C;strong&#x3E;role&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using it. Unfortunately it has to wait until another big release. Still I am very happy with all other new features. I would like to take this opportunity to thank the entire team for all the hard work in getting the release done in a timely fashion. You guys are doing a great job. The entire &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; community is proud of you all. With all the support around, we will get the glory back very soon.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am wondering when are we going to have the next edition of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping we would get it by end of this week.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-06-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/671.html">
<title>#671 - In-person and online events</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/671.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week I included an entry about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/events/301268306/&#x22;&#x3E;Getting started with Docker for Perl developers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; workshop I am going to run on June 13. This is part of a series of free virtual workshops I started to offer via the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/&#x22;&#x3E;Code Mavens&#x3C;/a&#x3E; Meetup group. If things go well I&#x27;ll run workshops for 3 languages: Perl, Python, and Rust and several related technologies. I&#x27;ve already schedule 3 events for Rust, 2 for Python, and 1 for Perl. Now, to plan ahead, I scheduled another Perl event:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/events/301413566/&#x22;&#x3E;Continuous Integration (CI): GitHub Actions for Perl Projects&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on July 14.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Even it these events are not relevant to you or they are not scheduled at a time when you can be available I&#x27;d like to invite you to register to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.meetup.com/code-mavens/&#x22;&#x3E;Code Mavens&#x3C;/a&#x3E; Meetup-group to get notified about other events. I am also going to send out (again) a survey to understand better what topics are more interesting to the members of that group, and at what time would it be most convenient for them. So by registering and voting for Perl you could get more Perl-related events.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last Week Mohammad mentioned both the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to take place in Las Vegas between June 24-28 and the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024/&#x22;&#x3E;London Perl and Raku Workshop&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that will take place, surprisingly, in London on October 26. Are there other in-person or virtual Perl conferences, workshops, or meeting planned? Let us know so we can include them in the Perl Weekly! At the bottom of each edition and on the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/events&#x22;&#x3E;events&#x3C;/a&#x3E; page.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The last thing I would like to highlight this week is a link Wendy shared a few days ago of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.flickr.com/groups/yapc/pool/&#x22;&#x3E;lots of pictures from YAPCs since 2003&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I even found several pictures of myself and became a bit nostalgic.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-06-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/670.html">
<title>#670 - Conference Season ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/670.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Are you regulars to Perl conference?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If yes then you have two upcoming conferences &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Las Vegas&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024&#x22;&#x3E;London Perl and Raku Workshop&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Depending on your availability and convenience, I would highly recommend you register your interest to your choice(s) of conference. And if you are attending then do take the plunge give your first talk if you have not done so before. It doesn&#x27;t have to be long talk, you can try quick 5 minutes lightning talk to begin with.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How about become a sponsor to the conference?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Believe it or not, it is vital that we provide financial support in the form of sponsor. So if you know someone who is in a position to support these events then please do share this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/this-is-your-opportunity-to-sponsor-the-perl-and-raku-conference-2024&#x22;&#x3E;TPRC 2024 Sponsors&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/announcing-the-london-perl-raku-workshop-2024-lpw&#x22;&#x3E;LPW 2024 Sponsors&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with them. It would be a big help to organise such events.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Keynote speakers for TPRC 2024...&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/blog/being-a-keynote-speaker.html&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where it is announced that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is going to be keynote speaker at the event. Well there is a bonus for all attending the event, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; would be giving a keynote remotely. I am sure, it is going to be a memorable moment to celebrate the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;25th anniversary&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Similarly, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; would be celebrating &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th anniversary&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; this year. I wanted to attend the TPRC 2024 in Las Vegas but for personal reason I am unable to attend. What a shame but at least I am definitely going to be part of LPW 2024 as it is local to me. No need to book travel ticket or reserve hotel room.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How many of you know about Pull Request Club?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pullrequest.club/hello&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Kivanc Yazan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It started in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Jan 2019&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I had the pleasure to be associated with it since the beginning. I never missed the assignment until the last I contributed in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;January 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Unfortunately I faced too much distraction and missed the fun ever since. I found this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://kyzn.org/pull-request-club-2021-2023-report&#x22;&#x3E;annual report&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by the creator himself. If you like contributing to opensource projects then you should join the club and have fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For all cricket fans in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, did you watch the final of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;IPL 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? I did and happy to see my favourite team, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Kolkatta Knight Riders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; lifting the trophy. Although, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;SRH&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the loosing team was my favourite too but it didn&#x27;t play to their capability. I am now looking forward to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;T20 World Cup&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; next. How about you?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bank Holiday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in England, so relax day for me. Enjoy rest of the newsletter. Last but not least, please do look after yourself and your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html">
<title>#669 - How Time Machine works</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/669.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week Mohammed wrote that he can&#x27;t wait to test out perl 5.40. In response Michiel Beijen wrote a blog post explaining how you can already try 5.39.10, using plenv. I love this!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As you might know a while ago I stopped using mailman for the Perl Weekly and now both the subscription and unsubscription process is done by sending me an email that I read and process manually. This gives an excellent opportunity to the new subscribers to introduce themselves and even to mention the subjects that are interested in.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As the Perl Weekly is a news aggregator I am going to share some of the items in his mail hoping that some of you will write blog posts covering some of the issues.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a long break from Perl, I&#x27;m looking for best current practice on building a website for a cycling club.  So I&#x27;m curious about the full stack (for collaborative dev, integration, and public deployment) the architecture (MVC (Dancer2 or Mojolicious) &#x26; DB), and frameworks for Plack/PSGI, JavaScript, unit and acceptance testing, and OO, for example.&#x3C;br&#x3E;Also, what collaborative tools to use for Scrum/Kanban collaboration, and source control, CI and CD.&#x3C;br&#x3E; To start with, I am hunting around for best practice on a dev Webserver and client, and, later, a public web hosting server.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This was my response: To respond to your questions: I personally was using Dancer a lot, but  Mojolicious seems to have slightly more development activity.&#x3C;br&#x3E;For CI I use either GitHub Actions or GitLab pipelines depending on which git hosting service the project uses.&#x3C;br&#x3E;I rent a server at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linode.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Linode&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but I have converted many of my sites to be static using some Static Site Generator and then I host them on GitHub pages.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I hope you&#x27;ll have more detailed answer.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Actually, in this edition we have a post by Dave Cross on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2024/05/deploying-dancer-apps/&#x22;&#x3E;Deploying Dancer Apps&#x3C;/a&#x3E; already responding to part of the questions. This is how time-machine works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a nice week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html">
<title>#668 - Perl v5.40</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/668.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The latest Perl Steering Council weekly updates about the good progress in preparation of release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I can&#x27;t wait to get my hand dirty with the new features.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;London Perl Workshop is making good progress thanks to the hard work of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lee Johnson&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As per the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024&#x22;&#x3E;official website&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, we now have a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Diamond Sponsor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping venue would be finalised soon. I would urge all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans to register your interest in the event so that the organiser can plan the event better.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The upconing event, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is in demand. I get to hear a lot of preparation is underway to make it memorable experience for all attendees. I am going to miss the fun, unfortunately. I hope to join you all online if it is available.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, you take extra care of yourself and your loved ones. Enjoy and celebrate Perl as always.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html">
<title>#667 - Call for papers and sponsors for LPW 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/667.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week Mohammed already mentioned the LPW, now they have a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2024/05/lpw-2024---call-for-papers-and-sponsors.html&#x22;&#x3E;Call For Papers and Sponsors&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am glad they write on bpo, but I also wonder, do they publish the CFP on other web sites as well. e.g. DEV.to?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I don&#x27;t have a lot of time dealing with Perl these days, but I looked at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/recent&#x22;&#x3E;recent report of CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and I see there are still quite a few CPAN packages that do not link to their public Version Control System (VCS). If you have some spare time maybe you could check out the modules in the &#x3C;b&#x3E;VCS&#x3C;/b&#x3E; column and ask the author to add the appropriate fields so it will be easier for others to find the git repository.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the Holocaust memorial day in Israel. I assume most of the readers of the Perl Weekly know what it is about, but I am surprised how many people in the world have never heard the word or don&#x27;t know what it is about. I spend the day partially by watching interviews and lectures. I listed some of them on my site: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/holocaust-memorial-day-in-israel-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Holocaust memorial day in Israel in 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also wrote an article titled &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/humanitarian-aid-for-gaza&#x22;&#x3E;Rafah and the humanitarian aid for Gaza&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you&#x27;d like to read more about the topic from me, you can &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://israel.szabgab.com/subscribe&#x22;&#x3E;register to my newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Unfortunately I need to deal with this quite a lot instead of sending Pull-Requests.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-05-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html">
<title>#666 - LPW 2024</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/666.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As we all know, German Perl/Raku Workshop 2024 happend few weeks ago, it turned out to be lucky for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. After GPW, we got the official announcement of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2024/04/announcing-the-london-perl-and-raku-workshop-2024-lpw.html&#x22;&#x3E;LPW 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is going to be one day event as per the tradition. The tentative date as of today is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;26th October 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and it is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Saturday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then don&#x27;t forget to plan your visit in advance. It is returning after a gap of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be a special event for one more reason as it would be the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th anniversay&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in terms of years. I am very happy to see the support we already got. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared the news that he has submitted &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 talks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; already. If you are planning to attend then please submit your talk as well. &#x3C;stron&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; always encourage first time speakers. If you can&#x27;t make it full length talk then you can even submit &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 minutes&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; lightning talk. To my surprise, as soon as the annoucement was public, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://geekuni.com/corporate-perl-training&#x22;&#x3E;Geekuni&#x3C;/a&#x3E; became the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Silver Sponsor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Ofcourse, we are looking for more sponsors. If your workplace codebase uses &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then I would suggest you please speak to the management if they are willing to sponsor the event. You can find more details about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2024/sponsoring.html&#x22;&#x3E;different sponsor packages&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is another big event happening in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and it is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;24-28 June 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The event organisers made a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/tprc2024vol&#x22;&#x3E;Call for Volunteers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had plan to attend the event with family as it is happening in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Now the circumstance is such that even my own visit is not confirmed. It would be a big loss if I don&#x27;t make it to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; this time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you remember the last major release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;? It was special because of the inclusion of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am hoping, in the next release &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.40&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we get more features added to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. According to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/blob/5fdf6e90221900a85cd3091bd2755e41fc230d4d/Porting/release_schedule.pod?plain=1#L54&#x22;&#x3E;this document&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, the tentative release date is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20th May 2024&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The post series &#x3C;strong&#x3E;What&#x27;s new on CPAN ...&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is my all time favourite. Recently it got fresh air and we had 4 in a row e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-november-2023&#x22;&#x3E;Nov 23&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-december-2023&#x22;&#x3E;Dec 23&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-january-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Jan 24&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/what-s-new-on-cpan-february-2024&#x22;&#x3E;Feb 24&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is nearly end of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Apr 24&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and we have not seen the post for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mar 24&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I just hope and wish, the tradition doesn&#x27;t die. I am keeping my fingers crossed.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, you please take a good care of yourself and your loved ones. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2024-04-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>