<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/565.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/564.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/563.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/565.html">
<title>#565 - Supporting the Perl Weekly</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/565.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I wrote about the issues we are facing with the Perl Weekly. I got a lot of responses and then yesterday I also noticed there were quite few comments on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/unb6yd/do_you_want_the_perl_weekly_to_continue/&#x22;&#x3E;Reddit&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as well. Let me thank all the responses now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Many people suggested that we could switch to sending out every 2 weeks or once a month, but I don&#x27;t think either of those would be a good idea. Some people suggested we (Mohammad and myself) should write more articles or interview people. Well, no. The Perl Weekly is specifically about collecting &#x3C;b&#x3E;your&#x3C;/b&#x3E; content and sharing it. So it is the wider Perl community that could solve the content-problem by writing more articles. Which brings me to one of our posts today. Dave Cross had another nice idea, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/davorg/cpan-module-tutorials-2be9&#x22;&#x3E;linking to tutorials of CPAN modules from MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. You don&#x27;t need to write some article on a topic that has never been mentioned. It would be enough to take one of the modules you use anyway. Put together an example on how to use it. Add some explanations and then post it on your blog. (Which could be very simple using GitHub pages.) Send us the link and also include it in the CSV file of Dave.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some people suggested to have a (better) web version and RSS feed. You are welcome to send a PR changing the web version to be better. The source of the Perl Weekly is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We also have two different RSS feeds: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/perlweekly.rss&#x22;&#x3E;latest edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/index.rss&#x22;&#x3E;10 most recent editions&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. However these get updated only once a week. If you really like RSS, you might want to use the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.theplanetarium.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Planetarium&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by who else, Dave Cross.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was some back-and-forth on Reddit whether the Perl-related Facebook groups are the best thing on earth or the worst thing on Earth. I think both sides are right. On one hand Facebook is a black hole that anything going there is invisible from the outside world - that&#x27;s why I don&#x27;t often link to it. On the other hand the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl programmers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; Facebook groups seem to be the most active locations for discussing anything about Perl. So let&#x27;s thank those Perl Mongers who spend time in these groups helping the newcomers. If I may suggest something, if you are not doing it yet: You could also try to direct them to the Perl Weekly and you could also work with them to set up a public blog (or use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/t/perl&#x22;&#x3E;dev.to&#x3C;/a&#x3E;) and write a post about something Perl related.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally some people suggested to ask for a grant from The Perl Foundation. Here is the thing. Money in itself is not an issue, but feeling that the work we do is appreciated goes a long way. The many responses I got show that there are at least a few people who value our work. Thank you!. However if the issue of money was already raised you could use some money to show your appreciation. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;Mohammad S Anwar&#x3C;/a&#x3E; has Patreon account with currently 23 supporters. Can we double this number?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also have a Patreon account, but for me a much better boost would be if you checked out the web-site of my son and became a user and a paying subscriber of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://torto.ai/welcome?utm_source=perlweekly&#x26;utm_medium=email&#x26;utm_campaign=perlweekly565&#x22;&#x3E;torto.ai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. That will make me a lot happier than any money you might send to my Patreon account.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So that&#x27;s about it for now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-05-23T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/564.html">
<title>#564 - Issues with OOP?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/564.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am a big fan OOP and can&#x27;t wait to see Modern Object in Perl, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, to be part of core Perl. Last update I had was in early January by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You can checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2022/01/msg262335.html&#x22;&#x3E;details here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then I would recommend you checkout &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki/Porting-from-Moose-or-Moo&#x22;&#x3E;this post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Those who don&#x27;t know, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is leading the team working on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about OOP, I came across another &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/common-problems-in-object-oriented-code.html&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by none other than &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; himself sharing the common issues with OO code. This should be taught to anyone starting OO in any language and not just Perl, in my humble opinion. Having read it few times already from start to end in one go, I keep going back to it to keep myself reminded about it all the time. You would definitely want to bookmark it for future reference.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few weeks ago, I shared post &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/why-is-object-oriented-programming-bad.html&#x22;&#x3E;Why is Object-Oriented Programming Bad?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Curtis. My favourite line in the post, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;I think there&#x2019;s a good case to be made that OOP is not nearly as useful as it&#x2019;s claimed.&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Mind you, this is coming from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enough of OO, lets talk about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Exceptions in Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would like to share the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/Ovid/5205534f7dcc52e4d931aaff301b39aa&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; (once again), where he points out the common issue in Perl. It reminded me about my recent &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets/blob/main/v534/try-catch.pl&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; sharing the new try/catch block in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.34&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, please find this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/Ovid/0ef90f9f48f04fdad5d2ee8204fab776&#x22;&#x3E;gem&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; talking about testing database operations with a fresh instance of SQLite everytime. I wonder, if this can be shared as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN module&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Just thinking out loud, I know.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-05-16T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/563.html">
<title>#563 - Shall we continue the newsletter?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/563.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I switched the email sending from an old mailman installation on my own server to Sendgrid. I was hoping to fix the delivery issues, but that did not happen. Some subscribers who have not received the newsletter earlier started to receive it, others stopped receiving it. The big difference is that now I see a report of who has not received it. For example I see many @cpan.org addresses in the bounce list. That&#x27;s just sad. I got some offers to use other services, free of charge, but frankly I am quite tired of fighting the SPAM filters.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In other news, we really hardly have any items to include in the newsletter. Well, except of the responsed to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, the job posts, and the posts of Flavio Poletti.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;These two issues together, and I really started to wonder if we should continue publishing the newsletter. What do you think?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-05-09T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html">
<title>#562 - Perl Conference</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/562.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish all the readers of the weekly newsletter, a very &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Idd&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. We are celebrating Idd today in England and luckily it is a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Bank Holiday&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as well.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have seen Facebook post about the upcoming &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlconference.us/tprc-2022-hou&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2022, Houston, TX&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. With this, I kept wondering why not have &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; too? Being member of the LPW organizing team, I discussed it with fellow member, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Good news is he seems positive about it as well. I don&#x27;t know whether we have enough time to kickstart the process. Just hoping we get the opportunity to organize the conference. It has been a long time since we last had the gatherings in London. We had German Perl Workshop organized successfully only recently. Although I didn&#x27;t see a single event report published by attending members unfortunately. I remember last time when I attended the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, there were plenty of post event reports published as per the tradition.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-05-02T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html">
<title>#561 - Switching to Sendgrid</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/561.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have just switched from using Mailman to Sendgrid to distribute the Perl Weekly. I hope this will improve the delivery rate. I was wondering what system should I use to maintain the list of registered people and got to the conclusion that, at least for the time being, I&#x27;ll use a flat file and I&#x27;ll manually maintain it. We&#x27;ll see how that works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In other news, my son started his own start-up company. He and his partner are building a tool for private investors so instead of chasing data sources they can spend more of their time on the decision making process. It would be nice of you if you checked out their site called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://torto.ai/welcome?utm_source=perlweekly&#x26;utm_medium=email&#x26;utm_campaign=perlweeklyintro&#x22;&#x3E;torto.ai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If would give a huge boost to them and would help them find investors if you also subscribed to their system. You could also use the code &#x3C;b&#x3E;perlweeklyApr20&#x3C;/b&#x3E; until 1st of May which gives 20% off.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html">
<title>#560 - Perl Rocks</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/560.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Here in England, two long weeks of school holidays are ending for us today. It is Monday bank holiday in England today. From tomorrow, we are back to the school run in the morning and afternoon, whilst fasting during the day as Ramadan is going on.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let&#x27;s enjoy the last day of the break and not worry about anything else.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the last one week or so, I have been sharing Perl sample code in posts on various social media platforms, like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Programmers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadanwar/&#x22;&#x3E;LinkedIn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has generated lots of buzz on the subject. Lots of new ideas, at least to me, came to the fore.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For those who missed it, let me share some of them here:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;ul&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1196449164496041&#x22;&#x3E;Stacked file test operators&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1197846361022988&#x22;&#x3E;Compare numbers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1195694301238194&#x22;&#x3E;Power of printf()&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1195152567959034&#x22;&#x3E;Size of hash&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1194997197974571&#x22;&#x3E;Handling of conflict markers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;li&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity/permalink/1193298991477725&#x22;&#x3E;Substitution operator&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/li&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;/ul&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have fun with Perl and share your experience with us. Take care of yourself and your loved ones!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html">
<title>#559 - Endangered and dying languages</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/559.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;While the population of the world is growing the language-diversity is shrinking. There are many languages that are used less and less. (Wikipedia has &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lists_of_endangered_languages&#x22;&#x3E;a list by location&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure as programmers there are plenty of thing we can also do to help. That&#x27;s why I have been investing time in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://librelingo.app/&#x22;&#x3E;LibreLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; project and specifically in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judaeo-Spanish&#x22;&#x3E;Judaeo-Spanish (aka. Ladino, or Judezmo)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Now I can also show you the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://diksionaryo.szabgab.com/&#x22;&#x3E;dictionary&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I have been working on. You can type in words in any of the languages listed there and it will try to find the Ladino word for it. The dictionary is still small. It contains only 3,500 words, but I hope I&#x27;ll be able to enlarge it to help people who would like to learn Ladino.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It was a very slow week and I hardly found any articles to include (besides the Weekly Challenge that Mohammad collects), but there were also new authors. Let me congratulate to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/simbabque/&#x22;&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/scotticles&#x22;&#x3E;Scotticles&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for their first posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html">
<title>#558 - Perl Magic</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/558.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I wish you all a very &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. May &#x3C;strong&#x3E;ALLAH s.w.t.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; bless us all in the holy month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have you seen any Perl code that surprised you recently?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have, only recently, found out that braces become optional when calling a subroutine, depending on when you call the subroutine. If a subroutine is defined before you call it in a script, braces are optional. If you call the subroutine in a script &#x3C;strong&#x3E;before&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; it is defined (which is perfectly acceptable too), then braces are a must.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How about this calling sub add() passing two scalar parameters? &#x3C;strong&#x3E;add my ($x, $y) = (2, 3);&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I also came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2022/03/30/making-dynamically-required-package-names-more-discoverable-in-perl&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where he shares a very interesting use of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x27;::&#x27;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in package names.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-04-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html">
<title>#557 - Human languages</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/557.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;First of all, let me congratulate &#x3C;b&#x3E;Mohammad S. Anwar&#x3C;/b&#x3E; for editing 100 issues of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you visit the main page of the website you will see a list of all editors, past and present, in the order they joined and with the number of issues they edited. Let me thank all of you!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Learning programming languages is not easy, but if you compare that to learning human languages you&#x27;ll notice that it has a lot more difficulties. Human languages have much bigger vocabulary and much bigger grammar with lots of exceptions. This already makes it much harder to learn on, but in addition it is hard to get fast and cheap feedback. Something you are given by the compiler/interpreter of your language. You can even add more by writing your own tests and setting up a CI system. That&#x27;s part of the value &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.duolingo.com/&#x22;&#x3E;DuoLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; provides. Fast and cheap feedback. However it is proprietary.  &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://librelingo.app/&#x22;&#x3E;LibreLingo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is an open source alternative to which I started to contribute. The most fun part for me is actually trying to write a course: building a dictionary and writing sample sentences.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html">
<title>#556 - Cucumber &#x26; Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/556.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How do you test a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Web API&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using Perl?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure you have most likely used TDD to test your Web API. How about trying something new for a change?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Something like BDD, Behaviour Driven Development. I came across BDD many years ago when my manager introduced the term to the team and gave us a short tutorial using Java. I was completely blown away by the idea itself. I never actually got the opportunity to use BDD in any of the Perl projects I worked in afterwards, unfortunately. Then few years later in 2018, I got the opportunity to attend the talk &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2018/talk/7547&#x22;&#x3E;Behaviour Driven Development and Cucumber&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Martin Berends&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; at the London Perl Workshop. After a quick search, I found a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6IsKr50wAE&#x22;&#x3E;video&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the same talk. If you missed the talk then it is your chance now to watch the talk. If the video is not enough and you are looking for more. I would highly recommend the book &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B084Z6GTKK&#x22;&#x3E;Cucumber &#x26; Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;John Davies&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was published by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlschool.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl School&#x3C;/a&#x3E; publishing house run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are interested in complete tutorial then you should check out this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.cognizantsoftvision.com/blog/how-to-test-web-apis-with-perl-and-cucumber&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Speaking of BDD, I came across the term &#x22;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming (XP)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x22;. TDD has been part of my day job most of the time without realising it being part of XP. I found this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.extremeperl.org/bk/home&#x22;&#x3E;website&#x3C;/a&#x3E; showing &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming using Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You can download the entire book in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.extremeperl.org/f/extremeperl.pdf&#x22;&#x3E;pdf format&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for FREE. If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Extreme Programming&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then take a look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.extremeprogramming.org&#x22;&#x3E;gentle introduction&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;THe last couple of years have been very tough for most of us in the IT sector. Although we all have been adjusted to the new normal of work-from-home culture, it has still left some scars behind. Mental health is one such issue being discussed more frequently during this period. I have found a way to keep my mind busy when needed; reading books (mostly non-technical). Recently I found the quote &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Lately my peace has been more important than proving my point.&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on web that express my current mental state. How do you deal with your WFH blues?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, I have finally reached the 3 digits figure i.e. my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. It took me nearly &#x3C;strong&#x3E;3 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to get this far. I would like to take this opportunity to thank each and every readers of the weekly newsletter for the kind words and appreciations. I would also like to thank, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for being my guide and mentor, all these years.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter, stay safe and pray for world peace.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-03-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>