<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/614.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/613.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/612.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html">
<title>#617 - The business risks of using CPAN</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/617.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You might know that I talk and write a lot about Open Source and I have a number of open source projects. Mostly web applications. One of them is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where I try to analyze CPAN packages and point to directions for relatively easy improvement. The most basic one would be a link to the public VCS (Version Control System) of the project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We have some historical data points with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/metacpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly reports&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Around 80% of the recently uploaded distributions have a link to their VCS. It is not bad, but is still 20% less than would be ideal. I am less happy about the fact that only 50% use any CI to check their code before it is released to CPAN.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;All this boils down to trying figure out the business risks of using Open Source 3rd party libraries in general and Perl modules in particular along with ways to alleviate them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;When you or your boss think about your Perl-based application, what are the things that make you worry? Do you bump into issues with modules that are not fixed? If you try to fix the issues, do you feel that it is hard to understand the code of the module?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What would make your life as a programmer using Perl easier? What would make your manager happier? Write a blog post. Comment on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/perlweekly/issues/506&#x22;&#x3E;this issue&#x3C;/a&#x3E; or reply to me in private!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html">
<title>#616 - Camel in India</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/616.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;When I say &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I mean &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Indian Subcontinent&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; i.e. Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan and Srilanka. Having said, my prime concern is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; right now. You must have realised the context of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Camel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by now. Today I would like to talk about the popularity of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I remember when I left &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2000&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, it was on the rise and that is how I got into &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Programming&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. After moving to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;England&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I noticed how frequent the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans meetup and share ideas. I got the opportunity to attend some and realised how it can boost the popularity of the language and spread the positive word among newbies. Regular &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; meet also keep the subject live and active.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ever since the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COVID&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; happened, all these in-person events stopped initially. But the good news is that we are getting back on track with the events like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.to/tprc-2023-tor&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha Conference in Helsinki&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have decided to attend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Canada&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have submitted talk proposal too, little late though. I am still waiting for the acceptance. The other conference is clashing with my planned visit to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; unfortunately.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Going back to the main topic, I am wondering if we ever had any &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Conference in India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am aware of active &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but never heard of their activities. In the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Will Braswell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; reached out to me with a proposal to do &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Conference in India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Because of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;COVID&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we put it on hold then. At the time, we decided to do month long tour to cover major cities spending 2-3 days in each city. I suggested the best time would be &#x3C;strong&#x3E;August&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as I will have long summer break. We would definitely need sponsors, ideally if we do under the banner of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Foundation&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then the reach would be even greater, in my humble opinion. The local &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group can be handy in organising the event. I would be eager to know if any &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Mongers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group interested in these events. I would expect the groups down south would be more active as they are highly aware of technologies in general.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just realised this is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;130th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. I also completed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;5 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as co-editor of the weekly newsletter in this month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter. Please do share your ideas and suggestions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html">
<title>#615 - PTS - Perl Toolchain Summit</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/615.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perltoolchainsummit.org/pts2023/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was held last week in Lyon, France. The website itself does not have a lot of information on it, but luckily the participants have blogged about it. There is plenty for you to read now if you&#x27;d like to keep up with the development in Perl, how to package Perl modules; how to install them, how CPAN and MetaCPAN work etc.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The PTS is a small even for people who are very deeply involved in the Perl ecosystem. It is a brain-storming session and a Hackathon. I wish there were similar session held more frequently around the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are looking for some Perl related event to participate in, there are two that I know of listed at the bottom of the newsletter and on our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/events.html&#x22;&#x3E;events page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. One is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com/&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in July in Toronto, Canada&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and the other one is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in August in Helsinki, Finland.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you have the time and the budget make sure you attend at least one of them!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the meantime, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/614.html">
<title>#614 - Why not Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/614.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few days ago, I found this article, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://two-wrongs.com/why-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Why Perl?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; shared on Facebook. To be honest, there was nothing new in the article, same old bits discussed. Depending on who you ask the question, the chance you might get crispy answer. Well here we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.polettix.it/ETOOBUSY/2023/04/29/why-perl&#x22;&#x3E;one&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Flavio Poletti&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In my career of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;over 25&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; years, I have been part of team building robust application using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the nearly every domain under the sun. At my current work place, I got the opportunity to work on a really huge system mostly built using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Having said, I do agree that not many people talk about the power of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. We should all take the collective responsibility and make sure we don&#x27;t miss a single opportunity to promote &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Did you know that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Toolchain Summit 2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is back?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Altough I am not as active on social platforms as before, I hardly seen any news about it. I just happen to see some activities on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by a friend of mine and realised the big event is back after a gap of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. One of the participant, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Johnson&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; already shared the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/paul_johnson/2023/04/the-perl-toolchain-summit-2023.html&#x22;&#x3E;event report&#x3C;/a&#x3E; if you are interested. I am hoping few more in coming days by other participants.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is rarely discussed in the field of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, right?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Now we have a project, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;PerlGPT&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; supported by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/perlgpt&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Foundation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We should all promote the project and help in any possible ways.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Similarly there was another big news about latest release of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/1344vs5/pdl_2083_released_and_updates_from_a_year_of&#x22;&#x3E;PDL 2.083&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, in few weeks time we are going to have a much awaiting release of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/blob/275f4e511457b9578602fc7a19a23cde36fe66bb/Porting/release_schedule.pod?plain=1#L54&#x22;&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am confident it would silence the negative voices. Till then enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-05-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/613.html">
<title>#613 - CPAN Dashboard</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/613.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; one of the links I display is the link to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpandashboard.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Dashboard&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of each author. Assuming they have configured it. Every time I look at the CPAN Digger I feel surprised that so few of the CPAN authors have set up the Dashboard. Even among the active ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are a CPAN author, tell me, is it because you don&#x27;t know about the dashboard, you don&#x27;t know how to set it up, or that it does not provide you enough value? The first we solved now. For the second, there is a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpandashboard.com/add/&#x22;&#x3E;page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; explaining it. In case you don&#x27;t feel its value, let me know what would be interesting to you in such a dashboard?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On Wednesday we are celebrating the 75th &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independence_Day_(Israel)&#x22;&#x3E;Independence Day of Israel&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which is preceded by two memorial days. As someone eloquently put it: Jews have two memorial days &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yom_HaZikaron&#x22;&#x3E;Yom HaZikaron&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (Memorial Day for the Fallen Soldiers of the Wars of Israel and Victims of Actions of Terrorism) to remind us of the cost of having Israel and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yom_HaShoah&#x22;&#x3E;Yom HaShhoah&#x3C;/a&#x3E; (Holocaust Memorial Day) to remind us the cost of not. The memorial days are hard, but the Independence day is a huge event celebrating having our own country again after 2000 years of not having it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your Week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/612.html">
<title>#612 - Coming Soon!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/612.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;So what&#x27;s coming soon!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well it&#x27;s the subject of the talk to be presented by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com/event/1Lhr0/coming-soon&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023, TORONTO, Canada.&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I have been waiting for the event to come to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Canada&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as going to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;America&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was never on card. Post &#x3C;strong&#x3E;9/11&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, travelling to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;America&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; having &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Mohammad&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as first name isn&#x27;t good idea. Having seen the list of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com/directory/speakers&#x22;&#x3E;speakers&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I am sure it&#x27;s going to be lots of fun. I really wanted to attend the event and meet the top guns. So what&#x27;s stopping me? I haven&#x27;t been keeping well in the recent months. I know my current employer, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oleeo.com&#x22;&#x3E;Oleeo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; has been regular sponsor of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and have sponsored selected few to attend various events in the past. Having said, I have to be mentally prepared before I take the plunge but I really don&#x27;t want to miss the opportunity. I still remember the first time, I attended the talk by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German Perl Workshop 2018&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and it was about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4c8ixLgpxwo&#x22;&#x3E;Rescuing Legacy Code&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. After that I met him again at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Conference 2019, Riga&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I think that was the last time I ever attended any conference in person. I am not sure if I still have time to reserve a place or even submit a short talk proposal at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about conference, I would also like to mention another big event in Europe, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Koha Conference in Helsinki&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. They have extended time to accept talks. So if you are planning to attend then please do submit your proposal now. I am planning to visit India in the month of August otherwise I would have given a push.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am a big fan of writing skills of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and many more. It&#x27;s not just about blog post but also about their books. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; recently published &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://actions.davecross.co.uk/&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub Actions Essentials&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I haven&#x27;t read it yet but I am confident it is going to be worth spending time and money.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and please do take extra care of your health.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html">
<title>#611 - Test coverage on CPAN Digger</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/611.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Easter and Happy Passover!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In Hungary Easter Monday is the time to go out and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://medium.com/globetrotters/the-curious-tradition-of-sprinkling-women-so-they-can-grow-5b3e69e0d30d&#x22;&#x3E;sprinkle women with water&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Back when I grew up I was not aware that it is in order so they can grow, but whatever. Nor did I know that it was a pre-Christian (aka. Pagan) tradition.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Celebrating Passover, among other things, requires cleaning your house, your car, your office. This is what turned into the big spring cleaning tradition in many parts of the world. I cleaned my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/notifications&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub notifications&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had some 600 entries there. Luckily most of them were just updates and did not require any action from me.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;During the last week I spent way too much time on sending pull-requests to CPAN modules, but I also got around to improve the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN::Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It does not store the generated html files in the git repository any more and it now includes the test coverage numbers from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cpancover.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPANCover&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It makes it easy to find a CPAN package that needs contributors to increase the test coverage. I also believe that in most cases the author of a package that was recently released (and thus appear on the CPAN Digger) will more likely be active on the package and thus more likely to accept your contribution.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently saw a post asking &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/bekahhw/why-arent-you-contributing-to-open-source-3nk8&#x22;&#x3E;Why aren&#x2019;t you contributing to open source?&#x3C;/a&#x3E; There were a number of interesting answers, but the top most one was focusing way more on &#x27;releasing your own open source&#x27;, while I think there is a huge open field &#x3C;b&#x3E;contributing to an existing open source project&#x3C;/b&#x3E; without the burden of maintaining it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Another comment talked about the difficulty with the agreements one needs to sign on the big, corporation-created projects, such as React. Actually only a very small fraction of open source projects are from corporations and only a very small fraction requires any signed agreements. Avoid those. Pick one that does not require any such agreement. Pick one that is not a huge, well known project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html">
<title>#610 - Perl and TPF</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/610.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Belated &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Ramadan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to those who celebrate the holy month.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To me and most of us, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, is the parent body who supports the language. With the emergence of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, it is now referred as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPRF (The Perl and Raku Foundation)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There have been many positive changes brought by the parent body. One of them is the creation of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Steering Council&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and we even get the weekly update too. You can checkout the latest update from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/psc/2023/03/this-week-in-psc-102.html&#x22;&#x3E;PSC&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The change in name reminds me when I had to change the name &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to accommodate &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and many other languages. Even today, I use the term &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as I find it hard to move on. The best part is the team shares ideas from other languages. A fellow &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; member, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Cheok-Yin Fung&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started series where she talks about popular and usefull &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; module. Latest in the series is about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/c_y_fung/2023/03/graph---weekly-travelling-in-cpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;Graph&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you like the idea then do share your comments and encourge her. I am so proud of her. I would also like to mention about the work recently done by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2023/03/improvements-to-planet-perl-and-perlanet&#x22;&#x3E;Improvements to Planet Perl and Perlanet&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am looking forward to the next big stable release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; which would bring the new shiny OO concept, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; among many other features. Ideally I would want to have &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v7&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as it was suggested many years ago. I have no clue if anything is happening on that front.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you look at the positive noises on so many social platforms, I am confident we are going to bounce back soon. We have best of the best talent, we just need guidance. I am sure, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TPF&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; can help us on that front too. So all you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Hackers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, please don&#x27;t loose hope. We would bring back the glory we once had. For now enjoy all the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; goodies in the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-04-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html">
<title>#609 - Open Source and your workplace</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/609.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You probably already heard about the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I started to teach. The core assumption there is that helping more people contribute to Open Source will make the world a better place.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have been teach two versions of this course as open registration where anyone could register and I already started to teach one at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.jce.ac.il/en/&#x22;&#x3E;Azrieli College of Engineering&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in Jerusalem, Israel. I hope soon I&#x27;ll be able to teach this (via Zoom) at other institutions as well around the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As part of that course I started to collect information on Open Source projects by governments, corporations, higher education institutions, and non profits. The results so far can be seen &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/open-source-by-organizations/&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However I have another direction with this I&#x27;d like to understand how your workplaces relate to open source. Do they have any formal guidelines on how you can contribute to open source? Informal ones? What happens if you encounter a bug in an open source project you use? Are you allowed to contribute the fix back? On company time? Do they have a budget to support open source contributors who are not employees of the company? e.g. random Jane who works on some open source project? Please get in touch with me if you can share anything.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html">
<title>#608 - Love You Perl!!!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/608.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My 6 years old twins reminded me on Sunday morning about Mother&#x27;s Day. Although I didn&#x27;t even know such day existed when I was in India but this country exposed me to all kind of celebrations. I miss my mom a lot. Let me share with you one of my childhood memory. During my school days, everytime somebody complain to my mom about my fight she wouldn&#x27;t listen to my side of story. In fact she would start beating me up infront of the complainant. All my so-called friends knew this and they would blackmail me all the time. My mom would never defend me and believe what others have to say about me. I hated it to the bottom of my heart. This affected my personality and made me an introvert. I have been fighting with my nature all my life, even today.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I see the similar treatment to my beloved programming language &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It pains me when I see some &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Gurus&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; never defend the language same like my mom. I expect them to show the bright side of the language to the rest of the world instead, being the language guru. Even a single negative statement about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; would take us one step back and create a bad image. I am fully aware of all the shortcomings but I am not going to go out and tell everyone about it. I would rather find the solutions, if I can. There is nothing wrong to try other programming languages from the job prospective. In fact, I have recently played with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Python&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, thanks to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; but &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; remains my first choice of programming language.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know I don&#x27;t blog regularly any more but I have done it in the past every time I have done something nice using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You can find some of them &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar&#x22;&#x3E;bpo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I know there are many &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans out there doing their bits to dust off the negative image. Honestly speaking, we need more people to come forward. For example, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; has been running dedicated website, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where he showcase the cool features of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have seen some of the brightest brain creating magic using &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; every week when it comes to solving the weekly challenge. The best part is that they even share the code with others on various platforms like &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Mother&#x27;s Day&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to all the moms out there, including mine who is in India right now. I love you mom. I would like to apologise to all the readers of the newsletter about the last week incident when I couldn&#x27;t get my contributions to the newsletter available on time. I will try to be more organised in future, promise.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-03-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>