<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/601.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/600.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html">
<title>#603 - Generating prejudice</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/603.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure most of you reading this newsletter have heard that &#x22;perl is unreadable&#x22; or &#x22;perl is a write only language&#x22;, or maybe that &#x22;perl is dead&#x22;. In many cases this comes from people who have never actually saw perl. You might have not named this phenomenon, but this is called prejudice.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prejudice&#x22;&#x3E;Prejudice&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is having (usually negative) opinion about an individual, a group of people, or a thing, with partial or no real knowledge about the subject. It&#x27;s name is quite clear. It is having a judgement before (pre) having knowledge.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One can see prejudice as a phenomenon that happens naturally, but it can also be manufactured and used for personal, economic, or political gains. We saw that happening in the last 25 years with Perl. I saw a number of very interesting, though painful cases.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Prejudice against Perl clearly has way less personal consequences than other forms of prejudice, but maybe because of that it is easier to discuss it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In one case, a few years ago, someone explained to me that he writes both in Perl and in Python. When he writes in Perl he does not care about indentation or good programming practices as Perl works that way as well. Then he continued explaining that Perl is unreadable. He did not seem to realize the absurdity that the cause and effect relationship might not be of language-&#x26;gt;readability, but rather effort-to-write-clean-code-&#x26;gt;readability.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I often hear people writing in Perl talking about the code being unmaintainable. It is a type of internalized prejudice when you could know otherwise, but because of the social pressure of viewing the negative aspects one will adopts, repeats, and thus strengthens the prejudice. &#x22;If even Perl developers say so then it must be true.&#x22;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Once, more than 10 years ago, when &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/fosdem-2011-and-perl.html&#x22;&#x3E;I was at FOSDEM&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I talked to someone at the pre-conference beer drinking party. She explained that at their company they would not consider hiring anyone who had ever written in Perl. - Clearly a very stupid idea as there are some brilliant Perl programmers. However, this is where prejudice leads to. It does not only hurt the Perl developers, it also hurts the people having the prejudice.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;How is prejudice manufactured?&#x3C;/b&#x3E; One key aspect of creating and then increasing this prejudice against Perl and even against people who wrote in Perl was the repetition of lies that are now accepted as &#x22;facts&#x22;. Another aspect was that saying bad things about Perl seemed like a requirement to be accepted in the Python community. It certainly helped some people who moved from Perl to Python to &#x22;be forgiven&#x22;. I remember when I first started to write in Python and go to Python events, there was a some pressure to distance myself from my &#x22;sinful past&#x22; writing Perl. So far I managed no to cave in and so I still receive such demands once in a while.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;How to fight prejudice?&#x3C;/b&#x3E; There are many articles about this topic, I am sure it will be interesting to read some of them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;hr&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;That&#x27;s it for this weeks rant.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the meantime I continue running two instances of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. One in Hebrew for a mix of biologists and programmers. Some of whom are students and some with work experience. The other one is in English with extra focus on Perl. I hope that the participants in this course will soon start opening issues and sending Pull-Requests to various CPAN modules.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html">
<title>#602 - RIP Ben Davies</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/602.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I got the sad news about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Ben Davies&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; through the git notifications, being member Raku github repositories. Although I didn&#x27;t know him personally but I felt a personal loss. He was so young and actively involved in development of Raku language. I found &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.tributearchive.com/obituaries/27062822/benjamin-nelson-davies&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; sharing the details, if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It reminded of loss another very dear friend of mine, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rakudoweekly.blog/2020/03/16/2020-11-farewell-good-friend&#x22;&#x3E;Jeff Goff (aka DrForr)&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I had the honour to meet him at various Perl/Raku conferences. Life is so unpredictable, it is unbelievable. I have reached a point in my life where every little things create havoc as far as health is concerned.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about heartbroken news, I would like to bring the subject raised by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the last edition of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/601.html&#x22;&#x3E;weekly newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. At times, I wonder how can one be so disrespectful to others. I was really sad to hear what &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; had to go through. Honestly speaking, I only came to know about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.holocaustremembrance.com/resources/working-definitions-charters/working-definition-antisemitism&#x22;&#x3E;Antisemitism&#x3C;/a&#x3E; when I moved to England in 2000. During my college days, I never had interest in subject outside of domain of India. Although I was aware of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;love/hate&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; relationship between Muslims and Jews, I never bothered looking into the history behind it. Muslim community in general in India is more sympathetic towards fellow muslims. Some may find, my relationship with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; strange. Again, I must confess that I wasn&#x27;t aware about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; background when I first met him when he took my interview in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2016&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I only found out later about him being a Jewish when I had further interactions with him with regard to CPAN works. He has been my mentor ever since I first met him and has helped me every time I was in trouble. For me, religion is very personal thing and I like to keep it private. Having said, I don&#x27;t hide the fact that I am a practicing Muslim.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I urge everyone, please be kind to each other and spread love. Life is too short, so enjoy every moment of it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-02-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/601.html">
<title>#601 - The bad apple</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/601.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Welcome to the Perl Weekly!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am ambivalent about writing this and including in the Perl Weekly, but I feel if I don&#x27;t speak up then how can expect others to do so.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For another perspective on the subject I&#x27;d recommend you read &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/mohashim/status/1619037124711559169&#x22;&#x3E;this thread&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Mohammed Hashim on trust and perspective.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A couple of weeks ago I received an email full of good old antisemitism. It was clearly indicating that it is from one of the readers of the Perl Weekly. It was a tirade of expressions common to white Christian antisemites. Usually also referred to as white supremacists. It is clear that the sender knew what he was doing was reprehensible as he tried to hide behind an anonymous address. However, I am not sure what he wanted to achieve with this message. I guess he was upset that he cannot physically harm me. This person is also a bit slow. He found out that I am a Jew only now and I definitely did not hide this fact. I wonder what will happen when he understands that the other editor is a Muslim. These white supremacists usually hate them too.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This past week was the International Holocaust Remembrance day. Both of my parents went through the Holocaust, but at the end they were among the few lucky ones who survived. My father was born in 1917 so he was well aware of the pre-Holocaust rhetoric. I am quite sure he would be shocked by the level of Jew-hatred that goes on the social networks and in the public sphere in general. More or less with impunity. Both from the right and from the left.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After WWII many Germans said they did not know what was happening. Now we can see what&#x27;s going on. Unfortunately most people try not to look and don&#x27;t speak up. They might be afraid to speak up. If they do speak up they usually point to the other side of the political aisle and it gets tagged as partisan politics. The growing anti-Jewish public expressions bother me a lot, but what bothers me even more is that the majority is silent.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;hr&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;OK, now that I got this off my chest, let me mention the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;Open source development course&#x3C;/b&#x3E;&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I started to teach last week. We had our first session, but if you hurry you can still join us and catch up using the videos. If you are interested &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-2023-01-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;here is the site&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that is being generated from the information of the participants. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-2023-01-public/&#x22;&#x3E;Here is another site&#x3C;/a&#x3E; where you can see the participants of a similar course I started 4 weeks ago.&#xA0;If you are interested look at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/c/osdc-2023-01-perl&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for the details on how to sign up.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Participants in the course are already blogging about it and soon they will start contributing to Perl-based projects. Most likely CPAN distributions. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/c/osdc-2023-01-perl&#x22;&#x3E;&#x3C;b&#x3E;Join us!&#x3C;/b&#x3E;&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-30T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/600.html">
<title>#600 - 600th edition and still going ...</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/600.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; celebrated the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/perl-weekly-challenge-200&#x22;&#x3E;200th week&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and today we are presenting &#x3C;strong&#x3E;600th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Kudos to all the editors, current and past for the care and affections. It feels nice to be associated with such a popular events.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would also like to thank all the die hard fans of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly Newsletter&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for their support and constructive suggestions from time to time. It really helps me to focus on things important to the readers. I know it is not easy to do this every week but the love and affection we get works like a magic.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember there was time when blogging was the only source of information but now a days we have plenty of platforms where you get usefull informations. You know what I mean and where you can catch us. I love having 2-ways dicussion on any topics related to Perl. It is something I always encourage if you have spare time. I have seen how young blood getting involved in so many exciting things about Perl, for example on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Telegram&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although I don&#x27;t get time to take part in the discussion but I do watch how the discussion follow through. I have senior member of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; helping young blood with their experiences. It would be unfair to name few here. You know who I am talking about. I salute to all those who keep &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; alive.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you have any ideas/suggestions then please do share with us. I would to hear your point of views. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter till then.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-23T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html">
<title>#599 - Open Source Development Course for Perl developers</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/599.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently I started to offer a course called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The idea is to let participants learn and practice(!) git/github/pull-request/testing/code-coverage/linters/ci/etc. That way they improve their development practices and can also contribute to Open Source projects.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is a course designed to run for 12-13 weeks with about 5 hours per week workload. It can be either part of a university program or people can take it while they have a full-time job. Every week there is a 1-2 hours long presentation and the rest is hands-on work with my async help.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;d like to offer a version of this course especially for people who are interested in contributing to Perl-based Open Source projects. The participants will learn Perl-specific tools and processes. All proceedings will go to sponsor the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blogs.perl.org/users/book/2023/01/the-perl-toolchain-summit-is-back-in-2023.html&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Toolchain Summit&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Check out &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-public-2023-01-perl&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for further details and let me know ASAP if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-16T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html">
<title>#598 - TIOBE and Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/598.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy New Year everyone !!!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Year 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; saw the biggest release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was released with big bang. There were lots of positive vibes around it. I had never seen such noise before. If you missed the fun then you can checkout my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not a big fan of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TIOBE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but came across &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.tiobe.com/tiobe-index&#x22;&#x3E;TIOBE Index for January 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; going up slightly in the index recently. It is refreshing to see the progress. Who knows one day, it would reach the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;TOP 5&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; brackets.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking back the participation in &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, it looks promising. Nearly &#x3C;strong&#x3E;10K&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contributions in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by the members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the last &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;What is new happening in Perl?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, personally, I am looking forward to the modern OO &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in core &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; wrote an interesting &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/converting-object-oriented-code-to-corinna.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; recently where he shared his real life experience with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-09T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html">
<title>#597 - Happy New Year!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/597.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I hope you had a successful 2022 and you are ready for the next year. I certainly have lots of plans. As always. They are also changing a lot all the time. One of them is a new course I am working on called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;OSDC - Open Source Development Course&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is a hands-on course that covers git/GitHub/GitLab/Testing/CI using real-world open source projects. It is also not only a plan, I am starting the first session next Sunday. It will be given in Hebrew.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For the course I started to collect &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/open-source-by-corporations&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source projects developed by corporations&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There are a few where the product is open source such as &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://redis.io/&#x22;&#x3E;Redis&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.elastic.co/&#x22;&#x3E;Elastic&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There are others where the company shares some of its code as open source such as Netflix, Facebook, or Booking.com.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I&#x27;d like to ask for your help. Look around at your company and maybe other companies and let me know which one shares projects using an Open Source license. It would help me and the participants of this courses a lot. For the purpose of the course and for my collection the programming languages don&#x27;t matter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, if you can also point out Perl-based projects, that would be even better. Then I could feature these projects in the newsletter. Let&#x27;s start now with one I already found:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/bookingcom/pakket&#x22;&#x3E;pakket&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.booking.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Booking.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is an Unopinionated Meta-Packaging System that allows you to manage dependencies. It works by trying to avoid work.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your year!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-01-02T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html">
<title>#596 - New Year Resolution</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/596.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;With the end of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; celebration, another celebration kicks in i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Christmas/Boxing Day&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Although I don&#x27;t celebrate, being a Muslim, but I do enjoy the break from the routine work.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This edition of the weekly newsletter is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;120th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope you enjoy reading the newsletter as much as I do getting ready for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you have any new year resolutions?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I used to but then last year I stopped it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Why?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well couple of projects closed to my heart didn&#x27;t get started and that made me very pessimistic. I feel so bad that I don&#x27;t even talk about it. I hope new year will bring positive change.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Still, I don&#x27;t feel like setting new year resolutions. Could it be, I am getting old to keep up with fast pace dev life? Having said, the dev inside me still alive but just needs some push. Fortunately I have so many people around me that always gives me much needed positive energy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let&#x27;s talk about some positivity now. Well for me, it was the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and team. I wanted to be part of it but then missed the train unfortunately. Never mind, there is always next time. Having said, I did manage to get &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/app-timer&#x22;&#x3E;the post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; up but was too late to make it. Fortunately my contribution to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; did work out nicely like &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://raku-advent.blog/2022/12/21/day-21-raku-and-i-journey-begin&#x22;&#x3E;Raku and I&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the holidays and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html">
<title>#595 - Happy Hanukkah - Merry Christmas</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/595.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Yesterday was the 35th birthday of Perl. Congratulation to Larry Wall!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is the 1st day of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanukkah&#x22;&#x3E;Hanukkah&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, commemorating the Maccabean revolt agains the Seleucid (Greek) Empire when the Jews recovered Jerusalem roughly 2200 years ago. When I go for my daily stroll, I often pass by some archeological digging from that era. We lit the first candle yesterday night.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In a few days the Christian world will celebrate Christmas, the birth of Yeshua (commonly known as Jesus) roughtly 164 years later. Both events are celebrated by lights and way too much food.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two weeks ago I wrote extensively about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/&#x22;&#x3E;DEV&#x3C;/a&#x3E; inviting you to post there and even if you don&#x27;t feel like writing, at least to support the few of us who post about Perl. A few people followed my call. It is still mostly only Yuki Kimoto posting there, but there were a few posts by others, there were some comments and a few &#x22;likes&#x22;. As for me, I publish about a lot of things, not only Perl and I put most of them in series. I have a steady number or readers and the number of followers is also growing nicely. There are more than 400 already. If you too are interested about the subjects I write about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/szabgab/&#x22;&#x3E;follow me on DEV&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html">
<title>#594 - Advent Calendar</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/594.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; celebration begins with the start of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;December&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. For all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans, we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to the hard work of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his team. I am sure you have checked out the amazing daily source of fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As of today, we have got through &#x3C;strong&#x3E;12 days&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you have any favourite so far?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well I do have mine. To me the best part is the festive flavour in every article. I find it amusing and fun to read the story. I have contributed in the past but never got around to add the spice. I would blame the lack of background knowledge. This year&#x27;s calendar started with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toby Inkster&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; creation &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-01.html&#x22;&#x3E;Silent Mite&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. What a cool way to start the calendar. If you look at closely all the contributions so far, you would notice a fresh air with lots of positive energy. One name stands out very prominently this year is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault DUPONCHELLE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. His first contribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-03.html&#x22;&#x3E;Santa is on GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E; was a nice way to begin the journey. Then found a gem from a very dear friend of mine, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; talking about good old friend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CGI&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In fact, I have seen him presenting the subject &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-04.html&#x22;&#x3E;northpole.cgi&#x3C;/a&#x3E; at the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Conference&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found another piece of work by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault DUPONCHELLE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MongoDB&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 5&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contribution &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-05.html&#x22;&#x3E;Catching dreams&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is worth checking, if you want to explore &#x3C;strong&#x3E;MongoDB&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If I am not mistaken then few years ago, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared his creation &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/SVG::ChristmasTree&#x22;&#x3E;SVG::ChristmasTree&#x3C;/a&#x3E; in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I was happy to see it part of this year calendar too, not directly though. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 8&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-08.html&#x22;&#x3E;A Perlmas Tree&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Maximilian Lika&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I found &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Day 11&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contribution very technical dealing with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;signal ALRM&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Not an easy subject to discuss in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in my humble opinion. Thanks &#x3C;strong&#x3E;OODLER&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the fine contribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022/2022-12-11.html&#x22;&#x3E;Wake up! Time to open presents!&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are still looking for more &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; theme fun then I would highly recommend, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/advent-calendar-2022&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge Advent Calendar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Like in the past, this year also, it has contributions from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; hand picked by me. I am sure you would find it interesting.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am working on something that I would love to be part of this year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Hopefully it would be ready soon. Well I am also working on something similar for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be an achievement if I can get both done on time. Please wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-12-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>