<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2021, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/523.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/522.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/521.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/520.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html">
<title>#526 - Politics in Programming?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I came across a blog post by Curtis titled &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/blog/politics-in-programming.html&#x22;&#x3E;Politics in Programming&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. As is always the case, it touched on sensitive topics. You may or may not agree with his point of view but it is worth a read, IMHO.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let me confess, ever since Cor was renamed to Corinna, I always double check whether there is a double &#x22;r&#x22; or a double &#x22;n&#x22; in the name. I get it wrong all the time. Joking apart, I am very happy that Corinna is being discussed on so many different public platforms, a BIG thanks to Curtis and his team.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was another topic discussed on Facebook, &#x22;Data structures in Perl&#x22;. It brought back some good old memories of when I was first introduced to Perl. I came from a C background, so you would assume the transition would have been smooth. That wasn&#x27;t the case for me. I had a hard time getting my head around &#x22;references&#x22; in Perl. Once I passed that hurdle, the next disaster was waiting for me, i.e. &#x22;regex&#x22;. I had no clue about it before. It took me a while to get hold of it. Even after 22 years of working with Perl, I still find regex magic that I have never seen before, thanks to Abigail contributions to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perlweeklychallenge-club&#x22;&#x3E;the weekly challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The next big thing I dealt with after regex was &#x22;network programming&#x22;. The best book to understand the subject is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/network-programming-with/0201615711/&#x22;&#x3E;Network Programming with Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Lincoln D. Stein, imho.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Did you notice, I didn&#x27;t mention OO in Perl yet?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is only because I got the opportunity to actually use OO programming very late in my career. The first book that I read on the subject was &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.manning.com/books/object-oriented-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Object Oriented Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Damian Conway. It was the first book by Damian that I read and I completely fell in love with it. Of course, how can I miss the next one by Damian, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/perl-best-practices/0596001738/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Best Practices&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am happy to see Damian giving a thumbs up to the Corinna project headed by Curtis in his recent blog post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/damian_conway/2021/08/a-dream-realized.html&#x22;&#x3E;A dream realized&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. About the future of OO in core Perl, I am not too worried as it is in safe hands now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A fellow member of Team PWC, Adam Russell, started a Discord server for the purposes of discussing more academic Computer Science type topics, as they relate to Perl. If you are keen to join then please follow the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://discord.gg/Ng9nrdDg&#x22;&#x3E;invitation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;School holidays are coming to an end soon, at least in the UK, so enjoy it while it lasts. Don&#x27;t forget to keep a safe distance and use a mask in public places. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-23T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html">
<title>#525 - Vacation time?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;it seems it is vacation time for many of the authors as the number of posts is smaller than usual.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your vacation and remember if you can get vaccinated and in any case, even if you are already vaccinated and even if your country/state/city does not require you to put on a mask, put it on when among people! It is just a small piece of fabric and it might save the life of some other person.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Sure, you might not be contagious, but by having a mask on you also encourage others to put on their mask.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your time here!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-16T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html">
<title>#524 - Object::Pad</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is no longer a secret that I am the biggest fan of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki&#x22;&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/a&#x3E; project, headed by Curtis Poe. The motto of the project tells you everything you need to know about it, &#x22;Good enough&#x22; is not good enough. Having said that we still have to wait for the final push by the team behind the project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What shall we do in the meantime?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, we are encouraged to give &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Object::Pad&#x22;&#x3E;Object::Pad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; a try. Paul Evans is the man behind this distribution. A fellow member of Team PWC, Cheok-Yin Fung, wrote a blog post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/c_y_fung/2020/09/oo-linked-lists-in-perl.html&#x22;&#x3E;OO linked lists in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, last year (25th Sep 2020 to be precise). She updated this blog post recently and added another implementation using Object::Pad. This is what I call serious hacking. I have one more similar story to share with you as shared in a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://phoenixtrap.com/2021/08/03/whats-next-oo-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Mark Gardner. In this post, Mark shared his experience dealing with Object::Pad. With so much going on about Object::Pad, I gave myself a week to get things in place. But the week went past without any results unfortunately. Don&#x27;t get me wrong, I am not giving up yet. I will get my hands dirty and share my experience with everyone. In fact, Dave Cross, suggested I should include Object::Pad in the book I am currently working on. Currently the book has solutions implemented in traditional OO and Moo only. I will definitely add Object::Pad in the second revision soon after, promise.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you have any stories to share with regard to Object::Pad? If yes then please do share them with us. Or if you haven&#x27;t tried it then why not give it a go and make-over your existing project to use Object::Pad.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, did you attend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://conf.raku.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E;? If not then you can still watch the recordings of the three-day event. I also gave a short talk (30 minutes) on day three about &#x22;Making of Raku Developer&#x22;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the school holiday period with your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-09T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/523.html">
<title>#523 - How to improve your Perl?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/523.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There were not many posts this week, but some of them were really interesting.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally I got a bit overwhelmed with work. It is very interesting that there are organizations where people don&#x27;t know how to use git properly, where they hardly have any tests and no CI is running, but they already have Kubernetes set up because some consultant thought that would be cool to use it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On one hand it makes me angry that people don&#x27;t introduce testing, CI, and CD early in the development process. It would be a lot cheaper, smoother and faster for them, but on the other hand I also like trying to figure out how things happen to work. Sometimes, it seems, by total chance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-02T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/522.html">
<title>#522 - Promote Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/522.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure many of you are aware of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.outreachy.org&#x22;&#x3E;Outreachy&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It all started with GNOME&#x27;s Women&#x27;s Summer Outreach Program (WSOP) in 2006. The idea was to encourage women&#x27;s participation in Open Source projects. In 2009, the GNOME community revived the program to encourage more women to contribute to GNOME and renamed it to GNOME Outreach Program for Women. It became a very popular program in no time and successfully brought in more women into the fold. The program was further expanded with more organisations joining in e.g. Fedora, Mozilla, JBoss, OpenStack, Subversion etc. With the additions, in 2013, the program was renamed to the Free and Open Source Software Outreach Program. At one point, there were 16 organizations involved in this program. In 2015, the program was again renamed to Outreachy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Did I mention Perl in the above discussion?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, in 2014, TPF sponsored an internship for Pattawan Kaewduangdee to work on MetaCPAN under the mentorship of Olaf Alders as a part of the Outreach Program for Women. There is another name that caught my eye, Upasana Shukla. I came across &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://upasana.me/2013/05/18/meta-cpan-debian-wikimedia-twisted-dancer-moose/&#x22;&#x3E;a blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Upasana where she mentioned how GNOME&#x27;s Outreach Program for Women helped her get into the Perl fold. If you look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.outreachy.org/alums/2021-05/&#x22;&#x3E;list of interns&#x3C;/a&#x3E; from the Indian subcontinent (India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Nepal, Sri Lanka) it is amazing. In recent years, TPF has sponsored &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://world.openfoodfacts.org&#x22;&#x3E;Open Food Facts&#x3C;/a&#x3E; projects for Outreachy. In 2020, Areesha Tariq, from Pakistan successfully got the internship to work on the Open Food Facts project. Please check out this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://medium.com/@areeshatariq02/get-a-remote-and-paid-internship-my-outreachy-experience-482a6cfc0564&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Areesha sharing her experience. It didn&#x27;t stop there, a few weeks ago, TPF announced another intern, Rosheen Naeem, again from Pakistan, to work on the Open Food Facts project. You should check out her recent &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://roshnaeem.medium.com/everybody-struggles-f6dbe33293b4&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about her journey. It is very inspiring.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would like to thank TPF for supporting the Perl projects and Outreachy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I can tell you from my own experience, we have great talent in the Indian Subcontinent. I wish more and more organisations would come forward and sponsor interns from these regions. When I started &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge - Perl &#x26; Raku&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, (a.k.a Perl Weekly Challenge), I was hoping to tap into the talent pool from this region, specially young college students. As the tagline says &#x22;You do not have to be an expert&#x22; to take part in the weekly challenge. Although we do have handful of students from Russia in the team. I am glad that, at least, we have built a platform where geeks from around the world come and share their experiences every week. Maybe one day we will have sponsors to help us reach out to young talent and bring new energy into the Perl community. Sometimes I wonder why we have never had a Perl Conference on the Indian subcontinent just like we have here in Europe and America. It shouldn&#x27;t be too hard to hold one as these days everything is online. We could invite guest speakers from across the globe to address the talent in the region. Is there anyone out there willing to help us orgranise Perl Conference?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A humble request to all fellow citizens of the United Kingdom, please don&#x27;t listen to Boris Johnson (Prime Minister of the UK) and keep wearing masks in public and maintain social distancing.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter until then.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-07-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/521.html">
<title>#521 - Floods in Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/521.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This week we saw the tremendous and devastating power of nature in Europe as well. The Guardian even mentioned the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/16/western-germany-floods-angela-merkel-horror-catastrophe-deaths-missing-search-flooding-belgium&#x22;&#x3E;Moselle River at Perl in Germany&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The place where Liz and Wendy attempted to re-unite the Perl 5 and Perl 6 communities as well. That was not very successful.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was wondering what can we do?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know a few members of the Perl community who are also volunteer firefighters. Some of them might have taken part in the rescue efforts maybe even risking their own lives. That a very generous way of helping others and helping the world when disaster strikes.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know a few other members of the Perl community who make an effort to reduce their own carbon footprint by traveling by bike and train only. That can help postpone the disasters and if enough people do them might even prevent the disasters.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What do you do? What examples could we follow to help when disaster strikes? What could ew do to try to avoid the disasters in the first place? Write about it in a blog post and send the link to me!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-07-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/520.html">
<title>#520 - CPAN Bus Factor</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/520.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If, like me, you are a fan of MetaCPAN then you must have noticed the latest changes to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; site. It is the introduction of new metric, &#x22;CPAN Bus Factor&#x22;. Don&#x27;t know what I am talking about? Well then you should read the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2021/06/30/cpan-bus-factor/&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, which is a collaborative work by Neil Bowers and Olaf Alders.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It reminds me an incident from the past when I received an email from Neil Bowers about one of my CPAN distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/IP::Info&#x22;&#x3E;IP::Info&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as he was reviewing CPAN modules for locating an IP address. Later he published his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://neilb.org/reviews/ip-location.html&#x22;&#x3E;report&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on 8th Aug 2012. You can take a look collection of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://neilb.org/reviews/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN module reviews&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by him. If my memory serves, Neil also ran &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cpan-weekly.org/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Weekly&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, for a while. I did join the mailing list and the received CPAN Weekly newsletter talking about a CPAN module and its usage every week. Unfortunately it is no longer active.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A long time ago, I used to be an active CPAN contributor. Unfortunately, because of time constraints, I&#x27;m no longer as active as I used to be. I even wrote a two-part blog post on the subject - &#x22;How to become a CPAN contributor?&#x22; - for perl.com in 2018. You can check out the posts, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/how-to-become-cpan-contributor/&#x22;&#x3E;Part 1&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/how-to-become-cpan-contributor-part-2/&#x22;&#x3E;Part 2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Why am I talking about CPAN contributions?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A friend of mine and fellow contributor to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, Cheok-Yin Fung, wrote a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/c_y_fung/2021/07/how-i-uploaded-a-cpan-module.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about her experience of uploading her first distribution to CPAN. It reminds me of my early days of struggle with CPAN. These days there is a lot of help available on various public platforms. I wish her all the best and welcome to the club of CPAN contributors.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I came across a very interesting &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://medium.com/codex/how-to-create-awesome-pull-requests-b634e7f00e47z&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by JJ Merelo talking about Pull Request do&#x27;s and don&#x27;ts. Very helpful advice for anyone looking to contribute to open source projects in general.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-07-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html">
<title>#519 - Crystal conference and course</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/519.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am going to give a presentation at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://crystal-lang.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Crystal&#x3C;/a&#x3E; 1.0 &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://crystal-lang.org/conference/&#x22;&#x3E;conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; alongside Yukihiro &#x27;Matz&#x27; Matsumoto and Bruce Perens (just to throw in two names you might be familiar with and to have some honor by association). It is taking place this Thursday. It is my first presentation at an international conference for a long time. Wish me luck!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you cannot make it to the conference, but you are interested in learning Crystal, I am going to start an experimental programming Crystal course via Zoom. You can &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/crystal-course&#x22;&#x3E;get more information and register here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As for Perl, it was a rather quiet week without a lot of posts, but still there is some nice stuff in here&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-07-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html">
<title>#518 - Becoming book author?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/518.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I recently came across a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://davecross.substack.com/p/the-story-of-ebooks-and-me&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Dave Cross where he shared the story of how he got into publishing ebooks. I highly recommend you read his blog post, I find it inspirational, personally. I always wanted to write a technical book on a subject related to Perl. I have high regard for those who are professional authors e.g. Curtis Poe, brian d foy, Gabor Szabo, Dave Cross and many more. Ever since I started the weekly challenge, I became more involved in writing technical blogs. Soon I realised it is not the same as writing a technical book. But the urge inside me to become an author didn&#x27;t die forever. With Dave&#x27;s recent blog post fanning the idea once again, I became charged one more time but this time I am seriously thinking about it. I have a topic that I wanted to explore for some time. I discussed it with Gabor and Dave and got very positive responses. So it is official I am now working on my first book, soon to be published by Dave Cross. Fingers crossed. Life is so beautiful when you have friends like Gabor and Dave who always encourage and guide you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There is another story that I would like to share. Andrew Shitov reached out to me few days ago to ask if I was interested in sharing my Raku story at the upcoming &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://conf.raku.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I have accepted his offer and am working on my presentation. I haven&#x27;t submitted my talk yet but will do so soon. Do you have a Raku story to share? If yes, then please do submit your talk before the deadline.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One last story for the week and then I will go away. Many of you know that I have been running the Perl Weekly Challenge for more than 2 years now. It started as a weekly challenge aimed for Perl and Raku community but soon it spread out to other languages. As of today, we now have received contributions in over 50 different languages. Latest addition is the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/crystal-binary-palindrom&#x22;&#x3E;Crystal programming language&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by none other than Gabor Szabo himself. A long time ago, someone (I don&#x27;t remember who), suggested that I should register a generic domain instead of perlweeklychallenge.org. I didn&#x27;t waste any time and registered the new domain theweeklychallenge.org. Having registered the new domain, I didn&#x27;t have the courage and expertise to switch over the actively used live site to another domain. I asked about this on Facebook and guess what? Dave Cross came up with step-by-step guide explaining how to do the domain switch. I was still very nervous to take the risk. Then came the final blow with Gabor asking the same question: why don&#x27;t I move domain to a generic domain. To cut a long story short, Gabor and I spent an hour or so yesterday (Sunday afternoon) and got the domain switched over. So we now have new domain the weekly challenge: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;theweeklychallenge.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Thank you Gabor and Dave for all the support and guidance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html">
<title>#517 - Commitment and habit</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/517.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Flavio Poletti has just completed one year of blogging. Mohammad S. Anwar has been editing the Perl Weekly for more than three years and running the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for more than two years.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not sure what the secret is, but something about creating a commitment, even if it is an artificial commitment that then you need to stick to. I am sure both of them had times when they thought of sleeping in and not doing the work that day or that week. After all, this is not their paid job, but the commitment kept them going. With time it became easier to do the task and the whole thing became a habit. I wish more people found the strength to do something like this.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-06-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>