<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/589.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/588.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/587.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/586.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html">
<title>#590 - Perl &#x26; Corinna</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/590.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Congratulation to all England cricket team fans for the T20I world cup trophy. You played like a champion in the final. Although you beat us (India) in the semi final, still I am very happy for you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Did you hear any update about Corinna recently?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We used to get regular update earlier and I really enjoyed the discussion about the Corinna. Last week &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/OvidPerl/status/1590247361384792065&#x22;&#x3E;tweet&#x3C;a&#x3E; where he mentioned that code example has been added to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/blob/master/README.md&#x22;&#x3E;README.md&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am sure you are going to love it. Thank you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and the entire team of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for all the hard work. We are waiting for it patiently.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was one more &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/OvidPerl/status/1591119906510077963&#x22;&#x3E;tweet&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; that made my day about the proposed feature of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; where you no longer need to end module with true value. In my career of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;23 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I have come across many creative ways to return true values in the module. I welcome this change and thanks the entire team.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am keeping the editorial short this week as I am running short of time. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-11-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/589.html">
<title>#589 - GitHub Actions for Perl modules</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/589.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Winter has arrived to us as well. After many months, yesterday was the first day I had to put on long trousers and socks. Tomorrow we might even get some rain. Anyway...&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is still a bit surprising to me that only about 50% of the distributions recently uploaded to CPAN have any CI configured. Look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/metacpan.html&#x22;&#x3E;stats&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;detailed report&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Clearly we, in the Perl community, have been spoiled by the excellent work of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cpantesters.org/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Testers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and thus people feel less need to enable GitHub Actions. On the other hand by enabling GitHub Actions they could reduce the load from the (very few) CPAN testers. They could get feedback much faster. In some ways they could do even do more diverse testing.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just saw the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/FGasper/perl-github-action-tips&#x22;&#x3E;Tips for testing Perl modules via GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of Felipe Gaspar. There are some excellent suggestions on how to test your module on some special versions of perl and on other platforms such as Cygwin, FreeBSD, OpenBSD. Just to name a few. I&#x27;d like to also reiterate my offer. If you&#x27;d like to get help adding GitHub Actions to your project, open an issue on your GitHub project and tag me (@szabgab) so I&#x27;ll be notified. I&#x27;ll be happy to help and maybe even create a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/os&#x22;&#x3E;blog post and record a video&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about your module. I keep a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/ci-for-cpan-modules&#x22;&#x3E;journal&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the recent PRs I sent with some comments and links.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl community embraced automated tests. Every Perl module comes with lots of tests. Let&#x27;s now embrace Continuous Integration that runs on every push and executes these test to get very quick feedback!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-11-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/588.html">
<title>#588 - TRPF, what&#x2019;s in a name?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/588.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few days ago, I came across the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/announcements&#x22;&#x3E;official announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with regard to the name change. I saw mixed reaction on Facebook groups for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;So what is my (personal) view on the topic?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I understand name change is not an easy decision, it must have been going on for days if not months. My view is to keep &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; separate. Having said, I like the name change at least it is better than what it was before. Since we are talking about name change, my suggestion is why not change it back to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;Yet Another Society (YAS)&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as it was before if I am not mistaken. Then have two separate board under its wings i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;The Perl Foundation (TPF)&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;The Raku Foundation (TRF)&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Also allow the individual board to decide the path they want to follow. This way we don&#x27;t cross each others path and stay friendly. It sounds simple, isn&#x27;t it? Not sure if it is easy to implement.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This name change brought back memories when I decided to change the name &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As you all know, right from day one, we decided to have both &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as the main contributing languages. A few months later after the launch, I found the name not reflecting what actual happens on the ground. But I already had the domain &#x3C;strong&#x3E;perlweeklychallenge.org&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; registered and all the actions were happening under the same domain. After discussing with some of my close friends, I decided to change it to a new domain, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;theweeklychallenge.org&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To me, it makes more sense as we gradually opened up to many more languages, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;92&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to be precise as of today. It wasn&#x27;t an easy decision for me to change the name and move everything to new domain. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; helped me with the domain switch and patch the old domain to divert trafic to the new domain. Everthing seems to be stable now but I still refer the team as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as it is very close to my heart.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How was your experience with Hacktoberfest 2022?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My contributions this time didn&#x27;t meet the minimum requirement of the event. Although I submitted &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and all of them were accepted and merged by the author but only &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 PR&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; were counted as the other two PR were part of non-participating repositories. Having said, I am happy many of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; members got more than &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; this time. Congratulations &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you want to have fun and share your knowledge every week with others then please do join us here on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Also please don&#x27;t forget to checkout the experience of our &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/champions&#x22;&#x3E;champions&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-31T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/587.html">
<title>#587 - Continuous Integration for Perl modules</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/587.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For years Perl was a long way ahead of the other languages in terms of testing the modules. The volunteers of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cpantesters.org/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Testers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; provide an excellent service. Every time a new module or a new version of an older module is uploaded to CPAN (via &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pause.perl.org/&#x22;&#x3E;PAUSE&#x3C;/a&#x3E;) within days and sometimes even within hours the CPAN Testers would download the new release, test it on their machines, and send a report to the author. Sometimes they would even open issues/tickets manually to report the problem and help the author(s) fix them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;These days, however, Open Source developers can use a number of free Continuous Integration systems that would give them feedback much sooner: On every push to GitHub or GitLab. They can run the author or release tests on these systems. They can configure to test other modules that use their module (reverse dependencies) to make sure the new changes don&#x27;t have a negative impact on these users. They can can even re-run all the tests every day making sure that changes in the dependencies of the module don&#x27;t break it. (CPAN Testers usually run the tests of a module only if you release a new version or if your module is a dependency of something that was released.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;By catching certain issues before they release a new version they provide a better experience to every user of CPAN and they also take some of the manual work off the shoulders of the CPAN Testers who are few.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For many years Travis-CI was the de-facto standard to set up CI for GitHub-based project. These days it is primarily GitHub Actions.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So, I have been on a quest to configure GitHub Actions to all the Perl projects where the author is interested. I have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/os&#x22;&#x3E;documented some of these&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and I have written on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/ci&#x22;&#x3E;Why and how to CI&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I use the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to locate candidates, but if you&#x27;d like to get help with setting up CI, open an issue on your project and tag &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/&#x22;&#x3E;me&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you like my quest, feel free to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/support.html&#x22;&#x3E;sponsor me&#x3C;/a&#x3E; so I&#x27;ll be able to allocate more time to this. Oh, and if your company needs help with CI and test automation, I offer that as a service.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/586.html">
<title>#586 - Perl and Camel</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/586.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This is my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;115th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of the weekly newsletter. I know it is nothing as compared to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;323 editions&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by the chief editor &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am very happy to have come this far, thanks to all the readers of the weekly newsletter for the support and encouragements. It took me &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 years and 5 months&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to achieve this milestone.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Please excuse me for the long-winded editorial this week to celebrate the occasion.&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As we all know &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Camel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; are  insperabale for years now. I still remember when I was first introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the late ninetees, we use to refer &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Camel&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books. The association of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with the big publishing house like, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oreilly.com&#x22;&#x3E;O&#x27;Reilly&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is mostly responsible for the trend. Having said, there were few others too in the market but &#x3C;strong&#x3E;O&#x27;Reilly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; stood out among them. But we can&#x27;t ignore the ground reality at the same time, for reasons known to most of all, the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books started disappearing from the book shelves in recent years. Talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books, we can&#x27;t forget the service of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Randall L. Schwartz&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and many more. Of all those, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; still holding the ground as far as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is concerned in my humble opinion.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you remember the announcement of Perl 7?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I still remember, I watched the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlconference.us/tpc-2020-cloud&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Sawyer X&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and was very excited about it. But as you all know, it didn&#x27;t turn out as planned. Let&#x27;s not go there. Immediately after the announcement, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; came up with the book, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/preparing_for_perl7&#x22;&#x3E;Preparing for Perl 7&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, published by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlschool.com/about&#x22;&#x3E;{Perl School}&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I was lucky to get the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; copy of the book by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I thoroughly enjoyed it as his many other &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; books. While collecting informations for this editorial, I noticed the book is now declared &#x3C;strong&#x3E;retired&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, unfortunately.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Fast forward, in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we got another book, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/perl_new_features&#x22;&#x3E;Perl new features v5.10 to v5.34&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Once again, I was offered the book for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by the author. I would highly recommend this book to anyone who is new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or even if you have used &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for years. I found many new features that I wasn&#x27;t aware of earlier. The best part is the explanation of each features with great examples. It makes it so easy to understand the topic. I read the book from start to end and came up with my own examples of some of the features mentioned in the book. Those who follow me on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/mohammad.s.anwar&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadanwar&#x22;&#x3E;LinkedIn&#x3C;/a&#x3E; knows that I ran daily feature series where I shared one feature with examples everyday. It is now documented for future reference in the form of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as suggested by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How many of you have read the book &#x22;Learning Perl&#x22;?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have during my early days of learning &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was the main source of information for me. Keeping the tradition on, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brain d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; alongwith &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Randall L. Schwartz&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Tom Phoenix&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; came up with the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1492094951&#x22;&#x3E;8th Edition&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. This time, I was offered not &#x3C;strong&#x3E;one (1)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but &#x3C;strong&#x3E;four (4)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; copies of the physical book with free delivery by the generous &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I picked four members of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;(&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;) and hand it over the book, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Learning Perl 8th edition&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. A very big thank you to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; from the entire &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; members.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Do you think it stopped there?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, the short answer is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;No&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Recently &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; contacted me and offered me &#x3C;strong&#x3E;50 coupons&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of his new creation &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/learning_perl_exercises&#x22;&#x3E;Learning Perl Exercises&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Honestly speaking, I didn&#x27;t know about the book earlier. I have been giving &#x3C;strong&#x3E;one coupon&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; every week to one lucky member of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. So far, I have already given &#x3C;strong&#x3E;10 coupons&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fan or new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then why don&#x27;t you &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/how-to-contribute&#x22;&#x3E;join us&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and learn from each other something new every week. Trust me, you will enjoy the journey.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How well do I know brian d foy?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Honestly speaking I haven&#x27;t met him yet but would love to one day. My first interaction with him was in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2010&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; when I published my first distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Test::Excel&#x22;&#x3E;Test::Excel&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. During those days, one need to get the namespace registered with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;PAUSE admins&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. He is one of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;PAUSE admins&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; that I happen to interact with. I still remember during the email conversation he mentioned that he liked my distribution and one day he would use it. Ever since, I have had many email conversation with on different occasions. I proudly remember one such occasion when &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; offered me to do interview series for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I happily accepted his offer without even blinking once. I did three interviews namely with &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-gabor-szabo&#x22;&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-curtis-poe&#x22;&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-damian-conway&#x22;&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Unfortunately after that I got distracted and busy with other personal projects.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you tried GitHub Workflow yet?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Two names i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;  immediately come to my mind when talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub Workflow&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In fact, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; seems to be on a mission to help &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; modules to have workflow configured. Recently I published a new release of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Test::CSS&#x22;&#x3E;Test::CSS&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, the very next morning I noticed &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/install-developer-dependencies-first-test-css&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by him. I would highly recommend you to take a look at his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/os&#x22;&#x3E;other similar works&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub Workflow&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, my colleague at work and friend, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, wrote a detailed and thorough &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://simbabque.github.io/posts/github-workflow-guide-for-modules&#x22;&#x3E;guide&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on the topic, you really don&#x27;t want to skip it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;How many of you have completed the challenge of Hacktoberfest 2022?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One thing I noticed this year, the pull request has to be accepted and merged for it to qualify. Now even after the pull request is accepted and merged, you still have to wait for another seven days review period. This year, I was lucky to receive the distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/HTML::Form&#x22;&#x3E;HTML::Form&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as my assignment for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;October&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as member of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pullrequest.club/hello&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. To my surprise, I noticed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;HTML::Form&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is participating in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As of today, I have submitted &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. That means, I am done as far as my monthly assignment for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. With regard to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, both the pull requests have been accepted and merged, thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. One of them is passed the review period and other is still waiting. Although I submitted &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 more pull requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but unfortunately they are not participating in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2022&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, although both have been accepted and merged. To qualify for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; specially designed T-shirt, I still have to find a distribution and submit &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 more&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; pull requests. Wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you nominated your Perl Hero?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If not then you still have chance to nominate your &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Hero&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Quick and easy to nominate is just commenting on this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/nominate-2022-white-camel&#x22;&#x3E;official announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and giving the name with reasons. Easy, right?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html">
<title>#585 - Handle your Pull-Requests, please!</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/585.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I know you are busy with tons of stuff and I know that as an Open Source developer you are most likely just a volunteer, but so are the people who send you Pull-Requests. It is very unpleasant to do the work, even if it small, send the pull-request and then never hear from the author any more.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Looking at my GitHub profile, apparently I created 600 Pull-requests, 530 of them are closed but 70 are still open. Some of them are open since 2011, that is 11 years ago. Some are as small as changing http to https in a URL, accepting (or rejecting) them should not take more than a few second. Finding them might be harder as GitHub does not seem to have a button for that, but you can easily search for them as you can see in my post &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/github-pull-requests-waiting-for-me&#x22;&#x3E;Listing Pull-request waiting for a user&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So I&#x27;d like to ask you to check if there are any &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/github-pull-requests-waiting-for-me&#x22;&#x3E;Pull-Requests waiting for you&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and try to clean up the queue.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hacktoberfest: If you receive a Pull-request during October, if you like it, accept it and consider marking it according to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.com/participation/#maintainers&#x22;&#x3E;instructions for maintainers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; so the PR will be accepted. (Hacktoberfest recognized 11 PRs I sent since registering, none of the repos are marked as participating. I am not sending the PRs for Hacktoberfest, but it would be encouraging to get the recognition.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html">
<title>#584 - Hacktoberfest &#x26; Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/584.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Happy Hacktoberfest 2022 everyone !!!&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure, most of you, already started hacking open source code. If not then you haven&#x27;t missed the train yet. You still have plenty of time to submit at least &#x3C;strong&#x3E;4 Pull Requests&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to qualified repositories in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; or &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitLab&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then I suggest you please take a look at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.com/participation&#x22;&#x3E;this page&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The rule of the game has changed since I first participated in the year &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2015&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have received the specially designed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;T-shirt&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; every year after completing the challenge ever since. As far as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is concerned, there are plenty of choices we have. However you have to make sure the open source project is taking part in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hacktoberfest&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; event. As mentioned in the official note, you have to be quick as only the first &#x3C;strong&#x3E;40,000&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; participants who complete the challenge are eligible to receive the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;FREE T-shirt&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Almost all my opensource contributions are hosted on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, you are FREE to pick any from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitLab&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; too. If you are like me, then you can pick and choose the participating repository from the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/topics/hacktoberfest?l=perl&#x22;&#x3E;list here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Having said, if you are still not sure then I would recommend two fun open source projects, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://pullrequest.club/hello&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request Club&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Kivanc Yizan&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you miss &#x3C;strong&#x3E;London Perl Workshop&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There has been discussion started few days ago among the team members behind the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. We have an official &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/lpw/2022/09/london-perl-workshop-status-update-2023.html&#x22;&#x3E;announcement&#x3C;/a&#x3E; requesting your opinions about the proposed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;LPW 2023&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I sincerely request you all who participated in the past and would like to attend the event next year. Please do share with your friends too. I have already seen emails with suggestions, being one of the organiser. Thank you for your inputs, much appreciated.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-10-03T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html">
<title>#583 - Sponsoring Perl and other Open Source work</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/583.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy New Year - Shana Tova - to all the Jews around the world!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A couple of days ago Ed Freyfogle wrote us pointig to their post on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blog.opencagedata.com/post/sponsoring-metacpan&#x22;&#x3E;sponsoring MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I love this on so many levels. First of all, of course the fact that they sponsor some Perl-related activity. They also blog about it. They also send us a heads up to be included here in the Perl Weekly. I hope many more small and large companies, and also individuals will follow them.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Dean Hamstead also sent us an email linking to the new &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://the-perl-store.creator-spring.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Store&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, that was also announced on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/tpf-merch-store&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Foundation blog&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Buying a T-shirt or some other swag will both help you with clothing and help TPF financially. Nice initiative!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally, I managed to set up my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/sponsors/szabgab/&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub sponsors profile&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. So now, if you&#x27;d like to support my Perl and in more general Open Source work (articles, code, and videos) you can do so via GitHub as well. It would be awesome to get a few of you start supporting me via GitHub in the next couple of days. That will help things get rolling there and I would be able to see how the system really works.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-26T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html">
<title>#582 - Grandfather&#x2019;s Perl</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/582.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Few months ago, there was a blog post &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.blog/2022/07/06/why-perl-is-still-relevant-in-2022&#x22;&#x3E;Why Perl is still relevant in 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E; created a lot of noise among the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; community. The author clearly missed the point. If you check the comments section, you can see how, White Camel Awardee, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and few others responed to the post.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I was pleasantly surprised when I found out that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; came up with perfect response to the other blog post with this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://stackoverflow.blog/2022/09/08/this-is-not-your-grandfathers-perl&#x22;&#x3E;This is not your grandfather&#x2019;s Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has already created positive noise. If you want to take a closer look at the recent changes to the latest release of &#x3C;/strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; then please do checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E; sharing the changes with example. By the way, it is not just limited to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You will find plenty more to keep you busy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we got another gem from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; sharing the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/current-corinna-status.html&#x22;&#x3E;Current Corinna Status&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you can&#x27;t wait for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I would suggest you take a look at &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; module &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Object::Pad&#x22;&#x3E;Object::Pad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Paul Evans&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, today, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Monday 19 September&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the date of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II&#x27;s State Funeral&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; declared as National Bank Holiday. Please checkout the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-19T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html">
<title>#581 - What to write about?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/581.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;People often tell me that they don&#x27;t know what to write about or that they are too new to Perl to blog about anything. Let&#x27;s see.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week I posted this article about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/ansi-command-line-colors-with-perl&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI command line colors with Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It hardly has anything to do with Perl, but I needed it and it can be a useful to others as well. Actually it originated from a discussion I had with my son who is using Python. So first I wrote the article &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://code-maven.com/ansi-command-line-colors-with-python&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI colors using Python&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and only after that I converted it to Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It did not require any deep knowledge, definitely not that of Python or Perl.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So if you would like to try writing articles, there are plenty of such small subjects one can cover.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After including the link in the previous edition of the Perl Weekly, Thomas K&#xF6;hler contacted me saying that he would do it differently and then he posted a short article showing how would he use &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://gott-gehabt.de/800_wer_wir_sind/thomas/Homepage/Computer/perl/ansi-colors.html&#x22;&#x3E;ANSI colors in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; including a link back to the original article.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This is excellent.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So here is a suggestion: If you don&#x27;t have an idea for an article, pick one of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Maven&#x3C;/a&#x3E; posts and write a different solution or extend the subject and send a link to us, the editors of the Perl Weekly.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-12T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>