<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2021, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html">
<title>#533 - Consulting work</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/533.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just had a meeting with a company in the UK that were looking for some consulting in Perl. After our conversation I felt that what they are interested in is not really where my expertise is, so I referred them to two other people who have a lot more experience in those areas. However I realized I don&#x27;t know who is providing consulting or development service these days. So let me know. Who knows next time I might be able to refer the clients to you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the other hand I just found out that my client, where I do some refactoring on a web-application with some machine-learning backend (written in Python). is likely to move the project to their parent company. This probably means I&#x27;ll be free for other projects to introduce test automation, CI, and refactoring code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html">
<title>#532 - Hacktoberfest 2021</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/532.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have you joined the annual &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com&#x22;&#x3E;Hacktoberfest 2021&#x3C;/a&#x3E; run by Digital Ocean?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If not then please join without any further delay. Hacktoberfest encourages participation in the open source community. You can earn a limited edition T-shirt by completing the challenge.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Not sure if you noticed, but this time they have made an interesting change by allowing open source maintainers to also take part in the contest. Ever since I started &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I have hardly found time to dedicate to Hacktoberfest. Last year I could only submit 6 PRs, enough to win the contest, since you only need to submit 4 PRs. This year, I am only taking part as the maintainer of an open source project - &#x22;The Weekly Challenge&#x22;. The best year for me as contributor was 2019 when I submitted 160 PRs.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are looking for an open source project to contribute to then you can join &#x22;The Weekly Challenge&#x22; and win the competition by submitting 4 PRs in just one week.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, you could submit 2 Perl and 2 Raku solutions to the weekly task. Just submit one solution per PR. I know it is cheating but a fair one in my humble opinion. Again, please don&#x27;t limit yourself to just Perl and Raku. You are free to choose your favourite programming language. One more bit, please don&#x27;t tie yourself to the current weekly challenge. You are free pick any past week challenges. Plenty of choices available. If you have any questions with regard to submitting a PR then please follow the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/how-to-contribute&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that explains every detail. If you still have any questions then please get in touch with me. You can find my details on the page. I am also accepting PRs to another open source project - &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/theweeklychallenge&#x22;&#x3E;The Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; website which is also open source code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are a CPAN contributor then you could pick and choose your favourite distribution and contribute. However there is a catch, the distribution may or may not be part of the contest. Having said that, you can contribute to my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/author/MANWAR&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN distributions&#x3C;/a&#x3E; if you fancy. I promise, I will make the distribution to be part of the contest so that your PR will count towards the target. Just yesterday, I received a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/BankAccount-Validator-UK/pull/2&#x22;&#x3E;Pull Request&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on one of my CPAN distributions, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/BankAccount-Validator-UK&#x22;&#x3E;BankAccount::Validator::UK&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Happy Hacking !!!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-10-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html">
<title>#531 - Legacy code</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/531.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I like working on legacy code whether it is Perl, Python or some other language, because it is code that is already very valuable to the organization that uses it. It is great to help the maintainers understand the code better and to give them confidence in making changes to the code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There are a number of language specific tools that can help you while dealing with legacy code. For example Perl Critic which is mentioned in at least two posts this edition. There are more generic things, like setting up a good CI system which is mentioned by Gugod.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The ideal situation is when both management and the engineers really want the change. They still probably need some external help from someone who has experience in similar situations and who has already seen systems where the engineers have no fear in making changes. It is a totally different world than what many people experience in organizations.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your fearless week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-27T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html">
<title>#530 - Outreachy 2021</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/530.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you remember, I mentioned the Outreachy program in the editorial of the weekly newsletter edition &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/522.html&#x22;&#x3E;#522&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has finally come to an end as Rosheen Naeem successfully completed the internship as reported by the TPF in a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://news.perlfoundation.org/post/outreachy2021-complete&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Congratulations Rosheen.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The Perl Foundation is looking for mentors and project ideas for the next Outreachy rounds. If you have Perl or Raku project ideas, please get in touch with TPF.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Many years ago, I was approached for help by the Open Food Facts team as they found out about my distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/Food-ECodes&#x22;&#x3E;Food::ECodes&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Unfortunately it didn&#x27;t work out as I was too busy with my other pet projects. I hope one day I can contribute to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/openfoodfacts/openfoodfacts-server&#x22;&#x3E;Open Food Facts&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I remember I had trouble setting up a local development environment for my contributions. I haven&#x27;t had a chance to see if there has been any improvements in this area to help newcomers to contribute.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I request Perl fans to come forward and help the cool fun project Open Food Facts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-20T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html">
<title>#529 - K&#xF6;MaL for the math enthusiasts</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/529.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A long long time ago, when I was in high school, I participated in the annual competition of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.komal.hu/&#x22;&#x3E;K&#xF6;MaL, the Mathematical and Physical Journal for High Schools&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. (Look for the little UK flag for the English version). Back then we sent in the solution by snail-mail and we only had to write our name to be identified. However people with very common names were asked to include a 3-digit number between their names. There was no verification that two people with the exact same name did not pick the same number, but the chances were slim. Because my name is way too common in Hungary I picked the number 529 because it is 23^2. Funnily, if you squint it also resembles the initials of my name: SzG&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anyway, if you or your kids like math, informatics, or physics, I&#x27;d recommend it!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-13T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html">
<title>#528 - Legacy Code</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/528.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;How old is the Perl code that you work on currently?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Curtis wrote an interesting &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/a-simple-way-to-fix-legacy-code.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about dealing with legacy code.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;After a long time, I got the opportunity to work with good old CGI. It reminds me of my early learning days. Talking about CGI, I came across fun &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oasys.net/posts/migrating-a-perl-cgi-to-aws-lambda&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; talking about Migrating a Perl CGI application to AWS Lambda.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Please do share anything interesting you are trying using Perl. I am currently working on Elastic Search using Perl. As always CPAN provides great support e.g. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Search::Elasticsearch&#x22;&#x3E;Search::Elasticsearch&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What else changed in your routine?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For me, the school run is back. How about you?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter. Hopefully next week we will have more perl blog posts.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-09-06T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html">
<title>#527 - New school-year?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/527.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The number of posts has been really low in the last couple of weeks. I really hope that with the new school-year in the northern hemisphere, we&#x27;ll see an uptick in Perl-related content.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Other:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I just saw a Tweet explaining why the person does not wear a mask. He writes because he is vaccinated he isn&#x27;t likely to be infected and &#x3C;b&#x3E;he accepts the risks&#x3C;/b&#x3E;. Well, I really try to avoid arguing with strangers on the Internet so I did not write to him, but basically he said that &#x3C;b&#x3E;he accepts the risk of endangering others&#x3C;/b&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In reality he spread two types of viruses. Potentially he spreads the Covid19 virus and for sure he spreads the idea that not caring for others is acceptable. For one, people who are unsure about the masks, seeing him without a mask will more likely stop wearing masks too.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Get vaccinated if you can and wear a mask when among people!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-30T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html">
<title>#526 - Politics in Programming?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/526.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I came across a blog post by Curtis titled &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/blog/politics-in-programming.html&#x22;&#x3E;Politics in Programming&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. As is always the case, it touched on sensitive topics. You may or may not agree with his point of view but it is worth a read, IMHO.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let me confess, ever since Cor was renamed to Corinna, I always double check whether there is a double &#x22;r&#x22; or a double &#x22;n&#x22; in the name. I get it wrong all the time. Joking apart, I am very happy that Corinna is being discussed on so many different public platforms, a BIG thanks to Curtis and his team.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;There was another topic discussed on Facebook, &#x22;Data structures in Perl&#x22;. It brought back some good old memories of when I was first introduced to Perl. I came from a C background, so you would assume the transition would have been smooth. That wasn&#x27;t the case for me. I had a hard time getting my head around &#x22;references&#x22; in Perl. Once I passed that hurdle, the next disaster was waiting for me, i.e. &#x22;regex&#x22;. I had no clue about it before. It took me a while to get hold of it. Even after 22 years of working with Perl, I still find regex magic that I have never seen before, thanks to Abigail contributions to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perlweeklychallenge-club&#x22;&#x3E;the weekly challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. The next big thing I dealt with after regex was &#x22;network programming&#x22;. The best book to understand the subject is &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/network-programming-with/0201615711/&#x22;&#x3E;Network Programming with Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Lincoln D. Stein, imho.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Did you notice, I didn&#x27;t mention OO in Perl yet?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is only because I got the opportunity to actually use OO programming very late in my career. The first book that I read on the subject was &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.manning.com/books/object-oriented-perl&#x22;&#x3E;Object Oriented Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Damian Conway. It was the first book by Damian that I read and I completely fell in love with it. Of course, how can I miss the next one by Damian, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/perl-best-practices/0596001738/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Best Practices&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I am happy to see Damian giving a thumbs up to the Corinna project headed by Curtis in his recent blog post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/damian_conway/2021/08/a-dream-realized.html&#x22;&#x3E;A dream realized&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. About the future of OO in core Perl, I am not too worried as it is in safe hands now.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A fellow member of Team PWC, Adam Russell, started a Discord server for the purposes of discussing more academic Computer Science type topics, as they relate to Perl. If you are keen to join then please follow the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://discord.gg/Ng9nrdDg&#x22;&#x3E;invitation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;School holidays are coming to an end soon, at least in the UK, so enjoy it while it lasts. Don&#x27;t forget to keep a safe distance and use a mask in public places. Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-23T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html">
<title>#525 - Vacation time?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/525.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;it seems it is vacation time for many of the authors as the number of posts is smaller than usual.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your vacation and remember if you can get vaccinated and in any case, even if you are already vaccinated and even if your country/state/city does not require you to put on a mask, put it on when among people! It is just a small piece of fabric and it might save the life of some other person.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Sure, you might not be contagious, but by having a mask on you also encourage others to put on their mask.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your time here!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-16T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html">
<title>#524 - Object::Pad</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/524.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It is no longer a secret that I am the biggest fan of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki&#x22;&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/a&#x3E; project, headed by Curtis Poe. The motto of the project tells you everything you need to know about it, &#x22;Good enough&#x22; is not good enough. Having said that we still have to wait for the final push by the team behind the project.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What shall we do in the meantime?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well, we are encouraged to give &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Object::Pad&#x22;&#x3E;Object::Pad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; a try. Paul Evans is the man behind this distribution. A fellow member of Team PWC, Cheok-Yin Fung, wrote a blog post, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/c_y_fung/2020/09/oo-linked-lists-in-perl.html&#x22;&#x3E;OO linked lists in Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, last year (25th Sep 2020 to be precise). She updated this blog post recently and added another implementation using Object::Pad. This is what I call serious hacking. I have one more similar story to share with you as shared in a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://phoenixtrap.com/2021/08/03/whats-next-oo-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Mark Gardner. In this post, Mark shared his experience dealing with Object::Pad. With so much going on about Object::Pad, I gave myself a week to get things in place. But the week went past without any results unfortunately. Don&#x27;t get me wrong, I am not giving up yet. I will get my hands dirty and share my experience with everyone. In fact, Dave Cross, suggested I should include Object::Pad in the book I am currently working on. Currently the book has solutions implemented in traditional OO and Moo only. I will definitely add Object::Pad in the second revision soon after, promise.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you have any stories to share with regard to Object::Pad? If yes then please do share them with us. Or if you haven&#x27;t tried it then why not give it a go and make-over your existing project to use Object::Pad.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not least, did you attend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://conf.raku.org/&#x22;&#x3E;The Raku Conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E;? If not then you can still watch the recordings of the three-day event. I also gave a short talk (30 minutes) on day three about &#x22;Making of Raku Developer&#x22;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the school holiday period with your loved ones.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2021-08-09T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>list of tags?</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>