<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2022, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/575.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/574.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/573.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/572.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/571.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html">
<title>#580 - Perl Mentor</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/580.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Good luck to all parents with school going kids in England, as today is the day one after a long summer vacation. I am one of them, fortunately or unfortunately. Be strong and you will get through this phase of life too.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Parents are the best mentor for their kids, in my humble opinion. During my early days, I didn&#x27;t know the importance of mentor. Having met some great mentor in real life in the recent times, I can say it is great service. In 2018, I gave a short talk on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://act.yapc.eu/lpw2018/talk/7543&#x22;&#x3E;The power of mentoring&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, at London Perl Workshop. A work colleague who does &#x3C;strong&#x3E;mentoring&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as part of his role, is by far the best mentor, I have met so far. I learn something new every day from him by just joining him on daily standup. Although my contribution to the standup is nothing but it feels nice to see young blood with so much energy. I wish I had mentor like him when I started.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I remember there was an initiative started on private &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook group&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to encourage and help newbie. Unfortunately nothing happened although we had loads of mentor in the group.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Is it easy to be a mentor?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You would think so but I can tell you it is not. You have to have patience first thing first. I have seen how difficult it is to be a mentor. I would like to share a sweet moment with you. A month ago, a young blood interested to learn &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; reached out to me on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. At times, I wonder how did he find out about me. His question was, how do I execute &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hello World&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; script, he has already created. He was using VSCode editor. I am not a big fan of VSCode editor but in the current role, I got the opportunity to use it. Having said, I still use &#x3C;strong&#x3E;vim&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for everything else. Back to the story, we started talking on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; messenger. I find it hard to convey message on messenger. So I requested him to join on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team video call&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It took &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 minutes&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; call to resolve the issue. While there, I showed him few other things beyond, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;hello world&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, he would carry on exploring the language further.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Is it mostly about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In my personal experience, no. I was once contacted by a member of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team PWC&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with regard to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;git related issues&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as he couldn&#x27;t submit his contribution to the weekly challenge. So there again, we jumped on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Team video call&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and in no time, he was good to go. Just to be explicit here, he was not a newbie but an experienced techie with way more than experience than me. It feels great to help. It is not one-way traffic as when I get stuck, I know who to contact. Luckily I get instant help too, so far. Few months ago, when I used to do &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/mohammadsajidanwar&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube video&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I had trouble with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;OBS Studio&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I asked for help on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. You wouldn&#x27;t believe, I had more help than I expected from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Lance Wicks&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I now have working environment back, although I am not doing live video any more because of lack of time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For those, need help can reach out to me on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/mohammad.s.anwar&#x22;&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I must make this clear, I will not do your course work. I am available for anyone anytime as I literally spend &#x3C;strong&#x3E;12-14 hours&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in front of machine every day.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a great week and enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-09-05T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html">
<title>#579 - Looking for that motivation</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/579.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html&#x22;&#x3E;Last time&#x3C;/a&#x3E; I mentioned the numbers I collect with the number of visitors to CPAN and I was wondering about the increased activity starting in August 2011. I got a few comments in email and some on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/wosxyi/perl_weekly_issue_577_optimism_and_numbers/&#x22;&#x3E;Reddit&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Probably the best explanation is what I received from Neil Bowers:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a look at the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://neilb.org/2022/02/07/cpan-report-2022.html&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN report I did in February&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. If you look at the new user signups, you&#x27;ll see a jump in 2012, and also looking at that chart you&#x27;ll see that 2012, 2013, and 2014 seem to buck a trend.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In 2012 Intermediate Perl was released, which told the reader to sign up for a PAUSE account and release a test module. If I remember right, brian d foy ran a tutorial at YAPC::NA the previous year, where he also got people to sign up (not sure if the tutorial was 2011 or 2012). We had the first CPAN Day in 2014, which also resulted in a big bump in CPAN releases. That may have helped 2014 stay up above the trend.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The question now, what could be a new motivation to increase activity and if there could be one that is sustainable?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-29T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html">
<title>#578 - Corinna MVP</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/578.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Belated Happy Independence Day to all fellow Indians. We celebrated 75th Anniversary of Independence on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;15th August&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, a proud moment for all of us.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ever since the release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, everyone is looking forward to the next big thing in the pipeline, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, you don&#x27;t need an introduction but if you do then you can take a look at this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor&#x22;&#x3E;official documentation&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; recently shared the latest update about the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna (MVP)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; as accepted by The Perl Steering Committee as detailed in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/blob/master/rfc/mvp.md&#x22;&#x3E;document&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Do you follow the latest release to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I noticed one particular distribution, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/WWW-Mechanize&#x22;&#x3E;WWW::Mechanize&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, currently maintained by a friend of mine and colleague at work, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. He is on the mission to clear pending issues. He shared the news recently that pull request queue is empty in this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/simbabque/status/1559267485764816896&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter thread&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I noticed the distribution has &#x3C;strong&#x3E;92.50% coverage&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you have spare time and would like to contribute then please do help get &#x3C;strong&#x3E;100% coverage&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Perl jobs in London seems getting back on track. Couple of days ago, I received an email about &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.careers/jobs/perl_programmer_business_owner_uk_eu_remote&#x22;&#x3E;Perl role in London&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by Perl Careers. The title of the post caught my eye, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Developer and Business Owner?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, I would like to recommend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://leanpub.com/learning_perl_exercises&#x22;&#x3E;Learning Perl Exercises&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;brian d foy&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am sure, you will find it handy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-22T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html">
<title>#577 - Optimism and numbers</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/577.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;last week Mohammad expressed his optimism about Perl rising again. It&#x27;s nice to have a gut feeling about that, but I would also like to see the numbers. So I looked at the stats I&#x27;ve been collecting for a while: The number of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/cpan-number-of-visits.html&#x22;&#x3E;visits to CPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. More specifically these are the number of &#x22;entrances&#x22; to MetaCPAN (and in earlier times to SCO as well.) as measured by Google Analytics.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My assumption is that we can measure well the level of Perl usage by the number of visits to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The number for July 2022 does not indicate any (positive) changes, but it is probably too early to see any effects anyway.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;However, looking at the numbers I noticed that there was a nice increase in the activity in 2012. Actually starting in August 2011. This increased activity lasted about a year then the decline continued and by 2014 the activity was below that of the 2011 level.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I could find 2 Perl-related events preceding the increased activity. In May 2011 the release of perl 5.14 and in July the opening of MetaCPAN. Neither seem to explain the change. So I am turning to you:&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What other things happened in or out of the Perl community that might explain that sudden increase of visitors to CPAN?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-15T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html">
<title>#576 - Perl is on the Rise?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/576.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally I have noticed the fresh energy among all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans ever since the release of latest &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I am telling this based on the amount of positive noise I heard on various public platform. There are still few in the pipeline that would give further push e.g. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. If you are interested to know more then please do checkout this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Ovid/Cor/wiki&#x22;&#x3E;page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; maintained by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/recent&#x22;&#x3E;MetaCPAN&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is another place where you can see all the latest cool &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; projects. I know plenty of volunteers helping to improve the code base. If you use a distribution and you like it then why not share your experience with the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and submit your proposal to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://cfp.perladvent.org&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;? Or if you have created one then why not share with rest of the world.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you are new to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and needs help then please do give us a shout. There are plenty of help available on various public platforms.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-08T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/575.html">
<title>#575 - Backward compatibility</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/575.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One of the ongoing discussions in the Perl community is the question of backward compatibility. One group of people say it is (one of) the most important traits of Perl that you can run very old code on a very new version of Perl. The other side mostly say that there are very few cases when this is actually needed and the change in the version of Perl is just one aspect of upgrades people need to handle.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Then comes the case, like the introduction of th $00 variable in Perl 5.32 that breaks the code of people who used that variable for their own purposes. This is not the first case where a change in perl (or for that matter in a CPAN module) breaks some working code. Neither will be the last.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So the question isn&#x27;t IF there can be changes breaking backward compatibility, but how we deal with them? Do the authors give proper warning? Are there tools to find pieces of code that will be impacted? (e.g. a Perl Critic rule). Are there instructions how to fix the code that will be broken?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On the other side of the coin, how can a user - a user of Perl or a CPAN module - ensure that changes in any of the dependencies won&#x27;t impact their product or service? How can they notice any impact before it reaches the production system? Possibly even before it reaches the development machines forcing the whole team to stop working.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hint: write and run automated tests!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-08-01T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/574.html">
<title>#574 - Perl Community</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/574.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The community spirit among Perl fans is always the highlight of any event. I am sure you have experience it too. Little while ago, there was discussion to give new life to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Many volunteers came forward to help the project, like, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Adam Russell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. As we are getting close to the next edition, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; came together and kickstarted the project with a big push. I noticed in the recent weeks, lots of activities on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/perladvent/Perl-Advent&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to all the volunteers. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; made an official call for papers in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.olafalders.com/2022/07/21/the-perl-advent-calendar-2022-call-for-papers-is-now-open&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I request all &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans to submit proposal. If you need any help submitting an article, then please do &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/perladvent/Perl-Advent/blob/main/FAQ-submit.mkdn&#x22;&#x3E;checkout the page&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for guidance. I would encourage first timer to come forward and share their experience with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; distributions. I am sure, everyone has few favourite distributions or their own creations that they want to talk about and share with the community. There are plenty of help available, if you need, so just give us a shout.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Talking about revival, recently I spoke about &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN Weekly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, creation of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Neil Bowers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I shared my intention of getting it back up. In no time, I got plenty of offer. One of them was &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Cheok-Yin Fung&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. She even shared the initial draft that I am currently reviewing. Thank you, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Cheok-Yin&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the help. The plan is to launch it on the birthday of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; i.e. 18th Dec. I will share more about it soon. Wish me luck.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Maintaining &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; distribution is a big responsibility. I have seen regular release of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/dist/WWW-Mechanize&#x22;&#x3E;WWW::Mechanize&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, thanks to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Julien Fiegehenn&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for all the care and love. You can find the details in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/simbabque/status/1549670503719153664&#x22;&#x3E;Twitter thread&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I know it takes a lot of efforts to keep the distribution live and active as I too have the responsibilities of handful of distributions. Having said, credit must be given to all the contributors who provide patches.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-07-25T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/573.html">
<title>#573 - Pocket money or serious support?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/573.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last week Mohammad raised the idea of a GitHub-pages-based central blogging platform for Perl to which Dave Cross added his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.reddit.com/r/perl/comments/vwb2j1/perl_weekly_issue_572_perl_blogger/&#x22;&#x3E;comment&#x3C;/a&#x3E; pointing out a misunderstanding. At first I liked the idea of Mohammad as way of making it easier for people who don&#x27;t know how to setup a blog, but on a second thought. Setting up a site for blogging on GitHub pages is less than 5 minutes. On GitLab and Codeberg it might take a bit more, but still way less than the whole writing part. If you need help ask Flavio, David, Mohammad, or myself.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;A few years ago the Perl community got really enthusiastic by the idea of supporting each other via one of the monthly-support platforms. The problem, as I understood, was, that most people received only some small pocket money that did not make any real impact. So most people thought: Instead of taking home 20-40 USD a month I will use this money to support others. We ended up with a circular support in which no one received any substantial support. If you go over the amounts the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/supporting-perl-creators&#x22;&#x3E;Perl related people&#x3C;/a&#x3E; receive you&#x27;ll see that most of them only receive a few 10s of USD. For most people living in the economically advanced world that&#x27;s just pocket money. Manwar is the person closest to some substantial amount, but he still needs more.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;This is our challenge now. Can we, as a community, increase his support to reach 500 UK pound? We are already half-way there. If you already support him, please consider increasing the amount so we reach USD 10/supporter! (we are at about USD 5.5). If you are not supporting him yet, do it now:  &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar/&#x22;&#x3E;Manwar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-07-18T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/572.html">
<title>#572 - Perl Blogger?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/572.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Are you a &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; blogger?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The state of Perl blogging is not hidden from anyone. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; wrote an extensive &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlhacks.com/2020/09/blogging-for-perl&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; explaining not just the issues but also suggestions to get around it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I proposed an idea on my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://twitter.com/cpan_author&#x22;&#x3E;personal twitter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; handle and asked for public opinion. As of today, it got &#x3C;strong&#x3E;22 likes&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I know, it isn&#x27;t big number.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;By the way, what was the proposal?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The proposal was to setup dedicated domain (https) powered by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;GitHub Pages&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The static site would be generated by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Hugo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It would be open to public to submit blog post as &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Markdown&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; formatted page as pull request. After a quick review, the post would be live.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Sounds simple, isn&#x27;t it?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The proposal should be familiar to those who have ever wrote an article for &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com&#x22;&#x3E;Perl.com&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It has the same the process as I mentioned above, I was reminded the same in response to my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Twitter post&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by a friend of mine. It makes me sad to see that the last post on the site was published on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;25th May 2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I came to know about the site for the first time when I found out about the monthly post &#x3C;strong&#x3E;&#x22;What&#x27;s new on CPAN&#x22;&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;David Farrell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. In the early days of my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;CPAN&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; association, every time I upload a new distribution, I would wait for the article to see if my distribution made it or not. Some of my distributions did appear in the article, just for record. I even did interview series, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl Ambassador&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the site in the year 2020. I had the honour to interview, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-gabor-szabo&#x22;&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-curtis-poe&#x22;&#x3E;Curtis &#x27;Ovid&#x27; Poe&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.perl.com/article/the-perl-ambassador-damian-conway&#x22;&#x3E;Damian Conway&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. What a shame, I couldn&#x27;t continue even though I had the list of high profile &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Ambassadors&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to interview.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I have mostly blogged on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://blogs.perl.org/users/mohammad_s_anwar&#x22;&#x3E;blogs.perl.org&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I don&#x27;t consider myself an active blogger, although I used to blog frequently before. I don&#x27;t feel comfortable now a days blogging on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;bpo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, so I decided to blog on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and cross linked on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;bpo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It is (cross linking) something not approved by many as I understand. I am likely to setup my personal blog site instead, just for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I will share the details when it is live. You are all welcome to contribute.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am up for new ideas and suggestions too. Please do share if you have one.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-07-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/571.html">
<title>#571 - Sponsoring TPF or individuals</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/571.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;What if you had a steady income of a few thousand USDs just for doing awesome things for Perl so you can afford to do whatever you want? I bet there would be tons of things you could do. Improving CPAN modules, patching Perl, writing articles, recording videos, encouraging others to write more. etc.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So what if we could support a few people to do just that? How could you be part of it? You could &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlfoundation.org/donate&#x22;&#x3E;donate to TPF&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, but for you, as an individual it might be better to support an individual directly. Without the organizational overhead. For this a while ago I put together the list of &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlmaven.com/supporting-perl-creators&#x22;&#x3E;all the Perl-related people&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I knew about at that time, who are accepting donations. They are mostly looking for monthly support instead of a one-time support. In my opinion it is much better to support someone with $10/month than $200 one-time donation. Partially because having a steady income is much better than having the need to raise more funds every few weeks or even every few months. With that said both at Patreon and GitHub Sponsors you can subscribe to a regular donation and then, after the payment you can cancel it. Effectively providing a one-time donation.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I went over the list now. There are 11 people listed on that page with a total of 139 sponsors. (There is probably some overlap the same person sponsoring more than one &#x27;creator&#x27;.)&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Personally I&#x27;d recommend you &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.patreon.com/manwar&#x22;&#x3E;sponsor the work of Mohammad&#x3C;/a&#x3E; as he both creates code and generates a lot of publicity for Perl, but if you decide to support someone else from the list that&#x27;s awesome too. If you find donate to someone who is not in this list yet, and if they agree, feel free to send a PR to add them to the list.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2022-07-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>