<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
>

<channel rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/">
<title>Perl Weekly newsletter</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/</link>
<description>A free, once a week e-mail round-up of hand-picked news and articles about Perl.</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright 2011-2023, Gabor Szabo</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>szabgab@gmail.com</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2011-08-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>weekly</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/633.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/632.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/631.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/630.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/629.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/628.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/627.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/626.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/625.html" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/633.html">
<title>#633 - Remember 9/11?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/633.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Finally I am back editing the weekly newsletter. As you all know I share the responsibilities with the chief editor, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I usually do the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;even&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; numbered weeks and he does the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;odd&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; ones. Having said, I was off the job for sometime because of health issues, I decided to take &#x3C;strong&#x3E;odd&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; numbered week i.e. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;633&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to make a comeback. From next week onwards, I will be back to the routine. I would like to take this opportunity to thank &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for all the help and support.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Today is &#x3C;strong&#x3E;9/11&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, people all around the world remember this day with different emotions. I still remember the event, I was sitting with my team in a small office in central London. Around lunch time local time, we got the news. The team was made up with Iraqi, Indian, Pakistani and English. So you can imagine the mixed reactions? For me, it is a very special day as I got married on this day &#x3C;strong&#x3E;20 years&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; ago. I choose this day so that I would never miss the most important day of my life.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Coming back to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I have been out of touch with it for the longest period. Thanks to &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org&#x22;&#x3E;The [Perl|Weekly] Challenge&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I was holding the ground and stay in touch with the magical power of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. There was a time, I used to be active and available to help anyone with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; related queries. With passing time, I find it hard to cope with the work load. I recently saw this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/olafalders_im-looking-to-pick-up-some-extra-weekend-activity-7105556888615858176-1BAB&#x22;&#x3E;post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It feels nice to see so much help available.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Post release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I saw jump in activities among the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; fans but there is still some not so positive vibes going around which makes me very sad. There is clearly two groups, one is very vocal in sharing personal opinions and the other is not so vocal but allow free speech. I happen to see both sides on daily basis and wish we had one platform where we can share our experience with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. This would have help sending one strong voice to the young generations and welcome to the community.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently concluded, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference in Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was a great event where I met so many young and enthusiastic members of the community. We should provide a common platform to these young bloods to come forward and share their experiences. They have so much knowledge, it is unreal. One evening, I spent with a twins brother having abundance of knowledge. Just talking to them gave me so much positive energy. On a funny note, it makes me realise I am getting old very quickly. Deep down, I would like to give back to the community that has been so welcoming. Having said, I have to be selective where I put my energy in. I keep getting invitations to be part of so many exciting things but I hardly find time for it. One thing, I would definitely do before I die is finish the book I started long time ago. It is primarily &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; focussed and I have a publisher, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, ready to help.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and please do share your stories with us.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-09-11T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/632.html">
<title>#632 - New school-year</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/632.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;My kids are not in school any more, but for those who have kids in school or who are themselves kids in school: good luck!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On a side note: yesterday &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B8BeC922reo&#x22;&#x3E;I was interviewed&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on the weekly Ladino meeting called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://esefarad.com/tag/enkontros-de-alhad/&#x22;&#x3E;Enkontros de Alhad&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It is in Ladino (Judeo Espanyol) and has nothing to do with Perl, but who knows, maybe you will find some parallel.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-09-04T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/631.html">
<title>#631 - The Koha conference ended</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/631.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Sorry for the late issue. As far as I know Mohammad is on his way back from vacation and I enjoyed a fun day at the dentist and now all I can eat is ice-cream. As Mohammad seems to take vacation seriously, even the Weekly Challenge report is missing this time. Anyway.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;The 24 episode long blog series of Liz came to an end, and with that she said &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/lizmat/winding-down-mof&#x22;&#x3E;Goodbye to Perl&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I remember meeting her first time some 20 years ago at a Perl conference. She was always very nice. Good luck with your work on Raku!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am also glad Thomas Klausner went to the Koha-conf as we now have a nice, green and yellow &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://domm.plix.at/perl/2023_08_things_i_learned_at_perlkohacon.html&#x22;&#x3E;report&#x3C;/a&#x3E; about it.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-08-28T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/630.html">
<title>#630 - Vacation time</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/630.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hello there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It&#x27;s me, Gabor again as Mohammad is on vacation in India. Actually I am also on a semi-vacation in Hungary. I work some, but most of the time I spend with friends. So you are stuck with me again. This is not that bad as I can further explain what I meant last week.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Apparently I did not explain myself properly in the previous edition. I don&#x27;t intend to include rather random articles about other languages in the Perl weekly, but I will not totally refrain from them either. I will mention my non-Perl training courses if I think they might be relevant to some of you.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some people suggested that I pass on the whole Perl Weekly to &#x27;the community&#x27;. I don&#x27;t think there is anyone (maybe except of Mohammad) who would want to take over the whole newsletter. I guess if anyone was interested, s/he would have already offered to be part of the editorial staff. Let&#x27;s make this also an invitation: if you think you&#x27;d like to edit the newsletter once in a while then let me know.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;On another note, if you are using Facebook, I&#x27;d like to remind you that the recommended Perl group is the one called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In any case, enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-08-21T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/629.html">
<title>#629 - Are we afraid of other languages?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/629.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Once in a while when I share something that is not Perl related I get some negative comments. Occasionally even some hate-speech or abusive messages. It&#x27;s not pleasant, but I hear from others who publish stuff, that they get such messages too. In some cases a lot more than I do. So I guess it is part of the deal. I might have some more impact on the life of people by having this platform and some people hate me for that. The question, what shall I do with my &#x27;platform&#x27;?&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Some people think the Perl Weekly and even me as an individual should only care about Perl. They say: If people see that the chief editor of the Perl Weekly talks about other programming languages then that&#x27;s going to ruin Perl. It&#x27;s pretty laughable as most of the other weekly newsletters are owned by a single person who runs them as a business.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Anyway, I recall in the early 2000s we had a very active Perl Mongers group in Israel called &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perl.org.il/&#x22;&#x3E;Israel.pm&#x3C;/a&#x3E; that I lead. At one point we started to have a &#x27;foreign languages&#x27; track in which we showed each other various other programming languages. I recall once I gave a presentation about Dart. We also had presentations about Tcl, Ruby, and Python. We were not bothered by that. At one point I even started to joke that in Perl There&#x27;s More Than One Way To Do It, one of them is Python.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Unfortunately I did not pick up Python early enough and did not start to offer Python training early enough. As most of my clients started to switch to Python they found other trainers who offered Python courses. By the time I realized I need to diversify it was too late. Most of my clients were gone and getting back them is rather difficult as they already have a trainer they are satisfied with.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Which brings me to a question I ask myself: Should the Perl Weekly be exclusively about Perl serving the interest of the language, or should it serve the interest of the people on the newsletter? I think we need to strike a balance. Mostly providing Perl-related content, but also provide some pointers for people who understand that they too might need to look elsewhere in order to find a source of income. I don&#x27;t want to give the message that is an either-or. IMHO for everyone it is totally fine to work in other programming languages and keep Perl as a hobby if that&#x27;s what life brings.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;To me it seem that the use of Rust will grow and thus it is a good time to learn about it and to start to offer training courses in it. So let me remind you that starting in September I am going to run a Zoom-based Rust course. If you are interested, let me know in an email!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-08-14T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/628.html">
<title>#628 - Have you tried Perl v5.38?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/628.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Ever since the release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I have been thinking of playing with it but never got anything interesting to work on. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Chris Prather&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is taking the lead to my knowledge, sorry if I missed anyone else. You can checkout the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-0.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 0&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-1.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 1&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-2.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 2&#x3C;/a&#x3E;,,&#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-3.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 3&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-4.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 4&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-5.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 5&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://chris.prather.org/perl-roguelike-part-6.html&#x22;&#x3E;Part 6&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. We should all be gratefull that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Chris&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is making an effort to showcase the power of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I would also like to mention another name, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Renee Baker&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, who shared his encounter with the latest release in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blog.perl-academy.de/2023-08-01-ein-groaer-klassenunterschied-class&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, originally written in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;German&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; but I used browser translate feature to read in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;English&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Kudos to their efforts for sharing the knowledge with us. I applaud their dedications and love for &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;One of core team member, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Steven Little&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; started project, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/stevan/Stella&#x22;&#x3E;Stella&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, using the latest release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It also reminded me a &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/blog/politics-in-programming.html&#x22;&#x3E;blog post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; shared &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2 years ago&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I still find it very usefull and handy.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Have you done anything with Perl v5.38?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If yes then please do share with us so that we can make it public here with the community. In &#x3C;strong&#x3E;2021&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I shared the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Design Pattern&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; implementation using &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://metacpan.org/pod/Moo&#x22;&#x3E;Moo&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and family in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/Design-Patterns&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. With so much happenings with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, I tried to re-implement &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/Design-Patterns/tree/master/00-class-feature/01-singleton&#x22;&#x3E;Singleton&#x3C;/a&#x3E; just for fun using the new experimental feature &#x3C;strong&#x3E;class&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I will see what else I can do next with the limited features we have in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook and Perl ...&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As most of you know, we have two very active &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook groups&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; primarily dedicated to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; language i.e. &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlcommunity&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl Community&#x3C;/a&#x3E; managed by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.facebook.com/groups/perlprogrammers&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Programmers&#x3C;/a&#x3E; managed by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Will Braswell&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Fortunately, I am one of the moderators for both &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; groups in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Facebook&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Of the two groups, one is private and the other is public. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor Szabo&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, the chief editor of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl weekly&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; newsletter, joined the Facebook group with much fanfare. Everyone welcomed him with open hands. I was happy to see him sharing his valuable ideas with the group members. Last week &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/627.html&#x22;&#x3E;newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; editorial created so much noise that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; decided to leave the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Programmers&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; group. Only recently we &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1H9yKf8BI0&#x22;&#x3E;heard&#x3C;/a&#x3E; from &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Sawyer X&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; about the abuse he received and how he decided to stay away from any future &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl meetups/conferences&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. What a loss to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in general. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Dave Cross&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; also left the group in the similar fashion but luckily he is still active. If we start loosing stalwarts like this then very soon we will not have anyone to lookup for advice/guidance.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am writing this editorial midweek (Thursday night) as I am flying to India on Friday morning. By the time you get this newsletter, I would be in India. I will checkout the response on social media platform. Let us all try to create friendly space where everyone is welcome.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter and stay safe.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-08-07T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/627.html">
<title>#627 - Rust is fun</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/627.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You might know that for many years I provided Perl training to corporations, both here in Israel and overseas. Unfortunately there are hardly any Perl courses these days. Three years ago I had a client from Switzerland that wanted to have a mix of training and consulting on testing their perl-based code. Another client from Germany wanted me to analyze their code-base and give them recommendations on how to modernize their code-base. There were a few others who reached out to me, but none of them were testing-related and none talked about training. I recommended them to contact some of the other people who do Perl consulting.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am not the only one who mostly lost their perl-related income. Some still stick around the Perl community maybe writing some Perl for fun, but they had to find other sources of income. Some people moved away from hi-tech altogether others moved to non-programming positions, and others learned other languages. For some time Ruby was a big winner of ex Perl developers, but it has been declining for years. Python had an appeal too, but they created so much animosity towards Perl, that switching over had an emotional toll. In a way Go (Golang) was an easier choice as it is so different from Perl. Then came Rust.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So what shall I do now? I asked myself a couple of years ago when I noticed that my Perl-related income has almost totally vanished. I still ask it now as I have not really found a &#x27;home&#x27;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;It took me quite a while to pick up Python, but eventually I started to write a lot of code and started teach it too. It is going quite well. However, despite even helping with the organization of several Python conferences, I never felt part of the Python community.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Recently I picked up Rust and I went all in. I started to work on the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rust-digger.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Rust Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which is similar to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cpan-digger.perlmaven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;CPAN Digger&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I already uploaded my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://rustatic.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;first crate&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, and I even started to run my first experimental Rust course (in Hebrew). I was quite happy to see the presentation of Dave Rolsy: &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vBsEF-anSLY&#x22;&#x3E;Why Do Programmers Love Rust?&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. That gave me further motivation.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;So now I am thinking to offer another, still experimental Rust course. This time in English. Probably starting in September. It will be Zoom-based; 2-3 hours a meeting in the morning hours of USA, late afternoon in Europe; running for a few weeks. It will cost a few hundred USD/EUR. The exact details will be determined later. For now I&#x27;d like to see if there is an interest attending it. So if you feel you&#x27;d like to participate let me know. Without any obligation to actually participate.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Have a good your week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-31T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/626.html">
<title>#626 - What is Oshun?</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/626.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I am sure you have followed &#x3C;strong&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023 in Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; whether as attendee or &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/@YAPCNA/videos&#x22;&#x3E;watching the videos&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I was fortunate to attend the conference and meet the who&#x27;s who of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl Community&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. The highlight of the conference for me was the keynote, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uT0S-jfO1mE&#x22;&#x3E;Coming soon ...&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, presented by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. It was during the keynote, we were introduced to a new project, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/Perl-Oshun/oshun&#x22;&#x3E;Oshun&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. Since the release of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, we have all been introduced to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, a modern OO to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core. &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Oshun&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is the next big thing after &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To be honest, it is really cool idea and I can&#x27;t wait it to be included in the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; core. I know it is in early stage right now but I am glad it is in safe hand.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;I would also like to mention about another talk &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1H9yKf8BI0&#x22;&#x3E;No one is immune to abuse&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Sawyer X&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I was lucky enough to be in the audience. In general, we are proud of the friendly and encouraging nature of the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; community but it is also fact that you do come across few who are not too friendly. I could relate to what was shared in the talk as I have experienced the abuse myself during the early days of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;[The/Perl] Weekly Challenge&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I must confess it took me months to recover from it. Those who are part of the weekly challenge must have noticed it too. I stopped participating in the weekly challenge for sometime and kept myself limited to managing the challenge as opposed to contributing to the weekly challenge in &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, writing &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blogs&#x22;&#x3E;blog posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and making &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://www.youtube.com/c/mohammadsajidanwar&#x22;&#x3E;YouTube videos&#x3C;/a&#x3E; for the same. I did come back few months later and participated again but it didn&#x27;t last long.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;If you missed the conference this year then you have plenty of time to book your place at &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc.us/tprc-2024-las&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2024&#x3C;/a&#x3E; which is going to be held in sunny &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Las Vegas, Nevada&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;We also had surprise announcement by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Olaf Alders&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; with regard to the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://cfp.perladvent.org&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2023 CFP&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I missed the deadline last year and couldn&#x27;t find a place in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perladvent.org/2022&#x22;&#x3E;Perl Advent Calendar 2022&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I will make sure this time, I submit my proposal well before the deadline. If you have something to share with the rest of the community then I would request you to come forward and submit your proposals.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Last but not the least, the next big event, &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is happening next month. You can find the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi/Schedule.html&#x22;&#x3E;schedule&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of the event. I am going to miss the event as it is clashing with my home visit to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;India&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I hope and wish you all have great time.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Thank you &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; for the space in the editorial of last week &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/625.html&#x22;&#x3E;newsletter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. It means a world to me. Enjoy rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-24T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/625.html">
<title>#625 - Mohammad Sajid Anwar the new White Camel</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/625.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Let me start by congratulating Mohammad Sajid Anwar, my fellow editor of the newsletters, for receiving the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://whitecamel.org/&#x22;&#x3E;White Camel Award&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Mohammad, you certainly deserved it!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As it turns out the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://whitecamel.org/&#x22;&#x3E;White Camel web site&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is still served from my GitHub Account. I updated it now adding the most recent recipients. I also updated the README in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/szabgab/whitecamel.org&#x22;&#x3E;repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. There are several TODO items. It would be really awesome if you could help me with the site. If you don&#x27;t know how, then join me in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.zulipchat.com/&#x22;&#x3E;OSDC chat&#x3C;/a&#x3E; and we can discuss it there.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;You might remember I used to teach a lot of Perl courses, but then unfortunately that market dried up. I did run a remote training course in 2020 about testing in Perl, but not much else. The pandemic also did not help much with training. Oh yeah, at the beginning of the year I ran an instance of the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/&#x22;&#x3E;Open Source Development course&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with focus on Perl. The video recordings are &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://osdc.code-maven.com/osdc-2023-01-perl/&#x22;&#x3E;here&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. However, I am starting to offer my &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://szabgab.com/&#x22;&#x3E;corporate training courses&#x3C;/a&#x3E; again. It would be great to teach Perl again, but even if it is &#x27;only&#x27;, Git or GitHub it will be still fun.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Lastly for today: The &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlkohacon.fi/&#x22;&#x3E;Perl and Koha conference&#x3C;/a&#x3E; is going to place August 14-18, 2023, Helsinki, Finland. You still have a month to get there!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the week!&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-17T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
<item rdf:about="https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html">
<title>#624 - TPRC 2023</title>
<link>https://perlweekly.com/archive/624.html</link>
<description>&#x3C;p&#x3E;Hi there,&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;By the time you read this newsletter, I would be on the flight to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Toronto&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; to attend &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://tprc2023.sched.com&#x22;&#x3E;The Perl and Raku Conference 2023&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I hope and wish to meet many experts and learn from their experience.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;In the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/622.html&#x22;&#x3E;issue 622&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, I mentioned that &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; is coming soon. Then a week later, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Gabor&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; announced the arrival of latest release in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://perlweekly.com/archive/623.html&#x22;&#x3E;issue 623&#x3C;/a&#x3E;. I was pleasantly surprised by the early release. I would like to take this opportunity and thank all involved in the release. Special mention to &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; and his team for the work on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Corinna&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. To me it is one of the most anticipated feature. To me, it is not just another release but a very special one. Therefore I was expecting it to be the talk of the town. Unfortunately I didn&#x27;t come across any such noise. In fact, the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; was more discussed on various social platform. I even collected my experiment with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.36&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://github.com/manwar/perl-cool-snippets&#x22;&#x3E;GitHub repository&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;As of today, the latest release is one week old and I finally managed to install it on my &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Windows WSL (Ubuntu 20.04)&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Plan is to extend the above mentioned repository and record my experiment with &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I have recorded the installation steps in the &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://gist.github.com/manwar/868aeb07ef4b445b55f726b02a79544d&#x22;&#x3E;gist&#x3C;/a&#x3E;, if you are interested.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;For all the German speaking readers, we have &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://blog.perl-academy.de&#x22;&#x3E;blog posts&#x3C;/a&#x3E; with the regard to the &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Renee Baecker&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. Talking about blog post, we have another &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://ovid.github.io/articles/corinna-in-the-perl-core.html&#x22;&#x3E;detailed post&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by the lead designer of Corinna, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Curtis Poe&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;. I would also like to mention another name here, &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Andrew Shitov&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, mostly known for his work on &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Raku&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;, sharing his &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://andrewshitov.com/2023/07/06/built-in-classes-in-perl-5-38&#x22;&#x3E;solution&#x3C;/a&#x3E; to the task &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://theweeklychallenge.org/blog/perl-weekly-challenge-224/#TASK1&#x22;&#x3E;Special Notes&#x3C;/a&#x3E; of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Week #224&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; using the new &#x3C;strong&#x3E;class feature&#x3C;/strong&#x3E; of &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Perl v5.38&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;&#x3C;strong&#x3E;Who owns the Camel logo?&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Well it is long outstanding issue, so much talked about it but unfortunately nothing happened so far. I just hope and wish it gets resolved soon. I came across this &#x3C;a href=&#x22;https://dev.to/thibaultduponchelle/open-letter-to-tim-oreilly-to-free-the-perl-camel-k3i&#x22;&#x3E;Open Letter&#x3C;/a&#x3E; by &#x3C;strong&#x3E;Thibault Duponchelle&#x3C;/strong&#x3E;.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Enjoy the rest of the newsletter.&#x3C;/p&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>2023-07-10T10:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:subject>editorial</dc:subject>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>